<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<string_table>

	<string id="aem_start_421">
		<text>So, what are you going to do now? No more fighting in the Arena, close your small business and search for a better life in distant lands, or what?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_4211">
		<text>Don't be too quick with making decisions, Marked One. That was just one tournament out of many.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_42111">
		<text>It may sound strange, but I suspected that from the very start. Come on, lay your cards on the table.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_421111">
		<text>So, this time you have won and became the Champion of the Arena, but that's just a challenge title - nobody can be sure you aren't going to kick the bucket next time. The tournaments are held more or less regularly - once or twice a day, from 22:00 to 06:00. You will know about the Arena to be opened from the messages I gonna post in the public network. As long as you are the Champion, you are welcome to choose any of the announced fights. It means, it is up to you to decide who and what to fight with and when. But there are certain limitations about weapons and ammo: it is prohibited to use any kind of explosives, whether grenades or ammo, and heavy weaponry: RG-6, RPG-7 and Gauss-rifle. That's it in a nutshell. Now the Arena is to be cleaned a bit, so you are free to go to the Bar and get totally drunk. But don't be late for the opening! See you!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_4211111">
		<text>Sounds good. Bye.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_31">
		<text>Hi, Champ!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_311">
		<text>Hello. What's up?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_3111">
		<text>Wow... Such enthusiasm... You'll have to wait - very few competitors yet. Come back later.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_31111">
		<text>Ok. Agreed.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_611">
		<text>Bingo! My congratulations!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_621">
		<text>No luck... Maybe some other time.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_631">
		<text>Take the earnings.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_641">
		<text>Wonderful fight! You've won the bounty and the bonus.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_651">
		<text>The victory is not reckoned.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_661">
		<text>Penalty for violating the rules.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_711">
		<text>Hi, Champ! You've decided to pay a visit to the Arena? As long as no worthy challenger has turned up to take your title, I'd advise you not to relax and keep acting. How about eliminating a couple of mutants? Some fresh ones have been delivered recently.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_721">
		<text>Look, Marked One, there's a small trouble about you. Hostile factions decided to unite for a while to fight their common enemy.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_7211">
		<text>And what's the problem for me?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_72111">
		<text>For you?.. Well, their "common enemy" is you. Try to remember, how many guys you have seen off to heavens? So those still alive refuse to fight with you... one at a time.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_731">
		<text>Hello, Marked One. Look, we've got so many mutants delivered recently, that there's no room to keep them. And as ill luck would have it - no one agrees to fight with them. Maybe you go for it?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_7311">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_73111">
		<text>Think it over, it would be a good deal. Earn a bit and help us at the same time.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_741">
		<text>Hi, Marked One. The Arena is open again. C'mon, choose the fight quickly. We have a tight schedule today.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_81">
		<text>Greetings, stalker!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_start_91">
		<text>Hello, Marked One.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_extra_0">
		<text>I have a request for you.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_1">
		<text>What's it about?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_2">
		<text>Include me in your notification list.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_21">
		<text>As you wish.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_3">
		<text>Can you stop sending me your messages?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_31">
		<text>Sure, I'll delete your PDA from the notification list.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_4">
		<text>Can you turn on some more lights on the Arena?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_41">
		<text>I'll see what I can do.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_5">
		<text>Switch the lights back to normal.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_51">
		<text>Turn on... Switch off... Make a decision, man!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_6">
		<text>DELETE MOD</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_61">
		<text>Are you sure?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_611">
		<text>Yes.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_612">
		<text>No.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_extra_9">
		<text>Forget it.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_job_quest">
		<text>So, what fights are there today?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_closed">
		<text>None at the moment. Wait until opening.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_done">
		<text>That's all for today - no more competitors.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_select">
		<text>Choose...</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_reject">
		<text>Maybe next time.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_group_reject">
		<text>I changed my mind.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_quest">
		<text>If you are absolutely sure about your abilities, I can suggest you time limited fights. These fights are usually very fast and require some real skills. But they offer the advantage to get a bonus or even double the prize if you manage within the given time. But remember one strict rule: it is prohibited to kill your opponents after the timer has elapsed! The penalty for not following this rule is equal to the prize. I assure you, it's better to get no prize and remain with the money you have rather than pay the penalty. And those alive will be at hand for other fights. So, what's your word: should I set the timer?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_5">
		<text>5 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_10">
		<text>10 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_15">
		<text>15 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_20">
		<text>20 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_30">
		<text>30 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_40">
		<text>40 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_50">
		<text>50 seconds.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_60">
		<text>1 minute.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_unlimited">
		<text>No, no way.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_time_reject">
		<text>I changed my mind.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_quest">
		<text>Who do you stake on?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_vs">
		<text>against</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_reject">
		<text>Nobody, I changed my mind.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money">
		<text>How much?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money_tm">
		<text>rub.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money_empty">
		<text>Some other time maybe - my wallet is empty.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_money_reject">
		<text>To hell with it.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_ready">
		<text>Bets have been made - all bets are off.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_stake_go">
		<text>Let's go!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_extra">
		<text>Totalizator.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_extra_info">
		<text>Wanna make some money without risking your health? You have come to the right place! You are welcome to bet in two ways: Mutant Fighting and Factions' Tournament. It's simple: you tell me who you want to bet on, pay the cash and tramp to the stand to watch the fight. If you win - you get your money and bonus, if you lose... Well, at least you have had the pleasure from watching the fight. What's your choice?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_job_extra_reject">
		<text>I changed my mind.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_team_military">
		<text>The Military.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_military1">
		<text>The Military</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_military2">
		<text>the Military.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_killer">
		<text>The Mercs.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_killer1">
		<text>The Mercs</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_killer2">
		<text>the Mercs.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_freedom">
		<text>The Freedom.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_freedom1">
		<text>The Freedom</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_freedom2">
		<text>the Freedom.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_dolg">
		<text>The Duty.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_dolg1">
		<text>The Duty</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_dolg2">
		<text>the Duty.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_neutral">
		<text>The neutrals.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_neutral1">
		<text>The neutrals</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_neutral2">
		<text>the neutrals.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bandit">
		<text>The bandits.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bandit1">
		<text>The bandits</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bandit2">
		<text>the bandits.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_pseudodog">
		<text>The dogs.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_pseudodog1">
		<text>The dogs</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_pseudodog2">
		<text>the dogs.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_boar">
		<text>The boars.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_boar1">
		<text>The boars</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_boar2">
		<text>the boars.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_snork">
		<text>The snorks.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_snork1">
		<text>The snorks</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_snork2">
		<text>the snorks.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bloodsucker">
		<text>The bloodsuckers.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bloodsucker1">
		<text>The bloodsuckers</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_bloodsucker2">
		<text>the bloodsuckers.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_zombie">
		<text>The zombies.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_zombie1">
		<text>The zombies</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_zombie2">
		<text>the zombies.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_chimera">
		<text>The chimera.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_chimera1">
		<text>The chimera</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_chimera2">
		<text>the chimera.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_burer">
		<text>The burer.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_burer1">
		<text>The burer</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_burer2">
		<text>the burer.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_gigant">
		<text>The pseudogiant.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_gigant1">
		<text>The pseudogiant</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_team_gigant2">
		<text>the pseudogiant.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_mutants">
		<text>Slaughter.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_info">
		<text>Finally, the Duty resumed capturing mutants for the Arena, sometimes really rare species can be encountered. So, what will be your next victim?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_military">
		<text>Fight with the Military.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_military_info">
		<text>One can wonder, what they are doing in the Bar... But due to having a coat-tail among the Military headquarters, the Duty can afford it. No one doubts the Military are professionals: all of them had smelled the powder even before the Zone appeared. And in the Zone they have been constantly polishing their skills during regular raids deep in the Zone. They are armed with the best of native weapons.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_killer">
		<text>Fight with the Mercs.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_killer_info">
		<text>The Mercs are well organized militarized faction with perfect foreign weapons. They say, the Mercs perform orders for foreign governments. Many natives dislike them, and they are a burr under the Military's saddle indeed, but the power of this faction makes everybody take into consideration their influence in the Zone and sometimes even "draw bridges".</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_freedom">
		<text>Fight with the Freedom.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_freedom_info">
		<text>Guys from the Freedom are irreconcilable enemies with the Duty, but during the tournaments they are inviolable in the Bar. There are many deserters from the Duty among them, who once gave up the ideology of "the last hope for the mankind", that's why the relationship between the factions are, to put it mildly, rather strained. Though the Duty consider these guys lame-brained, the latter are not inferior to them, and their weapons and equipment are also at high level.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_dolg">
		<text>Fight with the Duty.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_dolg_info">
		<text>The Duty faction... They are our self-proclaimed cops. It is due to them that the fights at the Arena became possible. Members of the faction always take part in the fights, polishing their combat skills for raids into the Zone. They are equipped like state specops, with products of native military-industrial establishment.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_neutral">
		<text>Fight with the neutrals.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_neutral_info">
		<text>Ordinary acting alone stalkers, not belonging to any of the factions in the Zone. Quite possible that you will meet someone who has stolen a march from you before - it's a good chance to get even then. The armament is different - native and imported barrels, but don't expect any weak ones.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_bandit">
		<text>Fight with the bandits.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_bandit_info">
		<text>Another portion of condemned men from the Dark Valley. They have been given ordinary Arena weapons, so don't hope for them to shoot at you with some rusty World War I rifles.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_special">
		<text>Fight with the Zone's combined team.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_special_info">
		<text>There are representatives of all the factions of the Zone in the team. Overall quantity slightly exceeds the usual. And all of them are eager to get even with you for your killing their "fellow tribesmen".</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_special_1">
		<text>Roger that.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_special_warning">
		<text>You have poor chance to get back alive. Are you sure you want to dare them? Better you use your brains now rather than splash them on the Arena.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_special_continue">
		<text>Even worse used to happen. Announce the fight.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_stakes">
		<text>Fight with the mutants.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_stakes_info">
		<text>Stalkers from various factions trash the life out of mutants... Or vice-versa... What fight do you choose?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_turnament">
		<text>Factions tournament.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_turnament_info">
		<text>A tournament of prestige between the factions, each tries to demonstrate its supremacy. Sometimes they settle quarrels with minimal losses as well. The rules are very simple: a number of teams keep killing each other until only one remains - the strongest. Will we get it started?</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_mutants_dog">
		<text>The dogs.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_boar">
		<text>The boars.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_tushkano">
		<text>The rodents.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_snork">
		<text>The snorks.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_bloodsucker">
		<text>The bloodsuckers.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_zombie">
		<text>Controller and the zombies.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_chimera">
		<text>The chimera.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_burer">
		<text>The burer.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_mutants_gigant">
		<text>The pseudogiant.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on1">
		<text>Single combat.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on2">
		<text>Versus two.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on3">
		<text>Against three opponents.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_fight_1on6">
		<text>Bloodbath.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_msg_done">
		<text>The Arena is being closed for maintenance. No more fights for today.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_close">
		<text>Time has elapsed, the Arena is being closed for maintenance. Opportunity only knocks once.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_open">
		<text>Attention! The Arena is open again! Who wants to be the first volunteer donor to part with a litre of his blood?</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_3h">
		<text>All those eager to take part in the Arena combats are welcome to the Bar. The first fight will commence in 3 hours.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_6h">
		<text>6 hours until the Arena opening.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_12h">
		<text>12 hours until the Arena opening.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_24h">
		<text>A reminder for everybody: Arena combats will resume in 24 hours sharp.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_48h">
		<text>The Arena will be opened in 48 hours; check-in of the participants has started.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_msg_72h">
		<text>Opening of the Arena is planned in 3 days.</text>
		</string>

	<string id="aem_barman">
		<text>The Barkeep</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_admin">
		<text>Arena's Admin</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_arny_dead">
		<text>People, who the fuck wasted Arnie? If anyone finds the bitch - shoot his head off on-site. Reward guaranteed. As for now the Arena opening is shelved, keep an eye for the news.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_restore">
		<text>New admin for the Arena has been hired. The combats will resume soon.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_1">
		<text>What the hell! Some motherfucker wasted the Arena Admin again! Somebody slay the rabid stinker!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_2">
		<text>Hey, you bastard... If I find out your name... It's better for you to commit a suicide, because when my men get you, they will take their time to torture you!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_3">
		<text>Attention all stalkers in the Bar! The Arena Admin has been killed again. Go and find the assasin, it's time to stop this shit from happening once and forever!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_barm_4">
		<text>Guys, they have bumped off the Arena Administrator again. The assasin is somewhere nearby. Find him, but don't kill him: just bust his bones and roast in the fireplace. Afterwards the Duty will hang the remains on some tree by the Bar entrance.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_arny_spread_out">
		<text>Well, guys, shit happened... Arnie got drunk and smacked into an anomaly... Got torn into pieces, not a single intact bone left. Therefore there will be no more fights on the Arena as you may guess. As soon as a new administrator shows up, the news will be transmitted via the general channel.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_admin_spread_out">
		<text>Damn it, the new Arena Admin got lost somewhere. If anybody comes across this drunkard, take him to the Bar immediately. As for me there's a great likelihood the alky vanished in an anomaly or some other shit has happened... Whatever, the Arena will be closed until a new administrator has been found. Thanks to all! Dismissed.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_1">
		<text>Dropped in at the Bar to toss off a glass. Do not turn over until Arena opening.</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_2">
		<text>Went to the Bar to squander your money on drinks. Losers!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_3">
		<text>If anybody needs to talk to me - I gonna be at the Bar. But no talk will be smooth without first serving me a drink!</text>
		</string>
	<string id="aem_drunk_4">
		<text>What the... Everyday is same... Vodka here, vodka there and vodka again... In short: I'm at the Bar.</text>
		</string>
</string_table>