<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="item_cheburashka_name">
		<text>Cheburashka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_cheburashka_desc">
		<text>An old toy of a soviet cartoon character. Looks like it stayed in an anomaly for a while. It's warm and smells fur. Toy's been darned on its back.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_guitar_sidr_name">
		<text>Sidor's guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_guitar_sidr_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich's favourite musical instrument.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_yashik_weapon_name">
		<text>Box with armaments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_yashik_weapon_desc">
		<text>Heavy box with assault rifles. Is equipped with a code lock. Locked and sealed.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="af-night-star_teterev">
		<text>"Black Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star_teterev">
		<text>"Black Star" is a rare type of the "Night Star" artifact. Origin is unknown, but the artifact increases the fire resistance of its host, unlike the "Night Star".</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="item_bp_mily_otschet_name">
		<text>New path report</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_bp_mily_otschet_desc">
		<text>Military report about recovering of an old blocked path between Agroprom and Cordon. According to report's data, the path was stable before the Second Big Surge in the times of "faction wars". After the Second Big Surge Zone's anomalous energy sealed the path. Now there's a possibility to use the old path again.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_af_esc_anomaly_name">
		<text>Unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_esc_anomaly_desc">
		<text>Strange unknown artifact. Highly radioactive with no other remarkable properties.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_antena_name">
		<text>Microphone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_antena_desc">
		<text>Directional microphone with high sensitivity. Clearly distinguishes even between low sounds at a distance of over 200 meters.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_pda_friend_barman_name">
		<text>Schvid's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_friend_barman_desc">
		<text>Schvid's PDA. Still in working condition. Copied undamaged records:\nRecord ¹1:\nYesterday saw three bandits capture a Dutier. Assholes!\nRecord ¹2:\nBandits have become impudent! They have, according to our data, several Dutiers as prisoners.\nRecord ¹3:\nToday was a lucky day - I found three "Mincer Meat" artifacts.\nRecord ¹4:\nWe've had a hassle with some "Freedom" soldiers, but we managed to fight back.\nRecord ¹5:\nOur group was captured by "Freedom", they stripped us of our weapons. They want to take us to a small tower next to the wagon and force us to get the artifacts from it. They don't want to climb themselves - there is strong radiation there. We tri...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_af_for_night_stalker_name">
		<text>"Black Soul"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_for_night_stalker_desc">
		<text>"Black Soul" artifact. It has got only negative properties and, when touched, causes dizziness and nausea. Exhibits strong local gravitational field - it is difficult to tear hands off the artifact. Prolonged contact with it would have serious implications for the organism.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_af_of_doch_starik_name">
		<text>Doll</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_of_doch_starik_desc">
		<text>Old man daughter's doll. It looks quite unusual and has a strange effect on the person holding it, causing a slight dizziness and noise hallucinations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kid_zapisi_name">
		<text>Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kid_zapisi_desc">
		<text>An ordinary school notebook. Gnarled children's handwriting with errors and "sunshines" on the sidelines. The notepad has almost rotted completely, with only the last few pages remaining readable.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_wpn_of_qest_on_elevator_name">
		<text>Sniper rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_wpn_of_qest_on_elevator_desc">
		<text>Sniper rifle's receiver has been torn up by a cartridge explosion. There is a strange symbol carved on the buttstock.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_kolba_dummy_name">
		<text>Empty flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_dummy_desc">
		<text>Empty lab flask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_name">
		<text>Flask with water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_desc">
		<text>Lab flask filled with water from the swamp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_zombie_name">
		<text>Serum</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_zombie_desc">
		<text>Serum. The ugly sight and disgusting smell are in tune with the medicine's purpose. It causes a temporary condition, close to zombieness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_treasure_of_figa_name">
		<text>Note from Figa's stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_treasure_of_figa_desc">
		<text>Note from Figa's stash. Contents:\n"I have been studying anomalous phenomena in the Yantar territory for a long time. Most recently I observed a strange glow at the plant near the compressor building. The glow is reminiscent of glimpses of an artifact, but is much stronger. It occurs only at certain hours. It was about ten o'clock that night, I was close, but I was afraid to go further. Besides, I had a headache - apparently the bipsizon effect was running out ... I had to leave. Recently Sakharov ran out of this miraculous drug (at the most inappropriate time!), but I will try to get there again anyway. If I hesitate, the glow may be noticed by someone else! There's a risk that I get zombifed, so I'll stash a "Fish" here - Sakharov promised to cure me. I hope everything goes OK and I won't need this message.\nFiga\n\nP.S. If you are reading this note, I'm most likely dead. For such very case, I have secured some most important documents related to the laboratory at Yantar lake that I had found. They are in the bus at the road leading to the factory gate. Be careful, there's very serious stuff going on... I think I detected something about the origins of the Zone itself!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dnevnik_tomsona_name">
		<text>Professor Thompson's diary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dnevnik_tomsona_desc">
		<text>Professor Thompson's diary.\n
		2006, March 21.\nI, Joseph Carl Thompson, the deputy of professor Mengelin - our science head. We're deeply involved in quite dangerous experiments and I have started this diary as an extra log in case of emergency. A week ago we received a group of criminals convicted to death. Looks like the government decided that these guys are the most appropriate "test subjects". That's a switch! We've had enough problems here even without this criminal constituent. On the other hand, their intellect is low so we can observe changes more clearly. We've spend a lot of time on the project which, according to our theories, would boost human intellectual abilities a lot. We haven't tested it yet because of lack of proper test subjects but now, with a full barn of them, we're expecting first real results.\n\n
		2006, March 23.\nToday we conducted the first major experiment with working equipment. First it went on smoothly, all devices showed stable boost of cortex performance and throughput of subcortex synapses. But suddenly the performance started to change unpredictably and one of the subjects began to shout loudly. Interesting, he clearly said "Zone", "April 12th", "Consciousness" among other unarticulate shouts. Then he fell in psychosis and convulsions... We had to stop the experiment and give him sedatives. Nonetheless, when the subject woke up, he began to demand everybody to kill him and other subjects. Wild shouts disturbed other subjects, so we transfered that particular one to X-18 lab to the Second science team which is conducting experiments on human body to gain its abilities. They don't need intellectual subjects so this one will work nicely for them.\n\n
		2006, March 26.\nLooks like our experiments are coming to an end. We've got first amazing results! Phenomenal data, enormous brain activity. Patients started to think way faster and their abstract thinking has developed vastly (the subjects used to be just dumb criminals).  Their IQ reached 200! But there is some bad news as well - the situation is turning dangerous. It looks like all subjects began to show some kind of hypnosis ability. The personnel started to fear the subjects and we've had to equip all the assistants with weapons and develop new instructions about working in pairs.\n\n
		2006, March 27.\nStrange things happened in the lab: professor Mengelin, our head, seems to be out of his mind today! Looks like he is either obsessed with some brilliant idea or he's falling ill of psychosis... Without any reason he ordered to eliminate all our test subjects. Exactly when our experiments started to give positive results! My collegues said that he had spent the whole night alone with one of the lab units without letting anyone else in. Looks like he discovered something. I'm not sure what it is all about, but his order must not be questioned anyway. Security team took the subjects out of the lab but never came back. Security chief is nervous keeps constantly calling somewhere.\n\n
		2006, March 28.\nThe security team finally returned. They look slightly inhibited, don't remember some things. But they all claim that the order was carried out and bodies were buried. They are not capable to explain where they were the previous day and why some of them lost their weapons... All the group was transfered to our medical unit. Mengelin spent all day to explain his new idea - a new project developed from the old one, aimed to discover the ability to unite multiple human consciousnesses to better solve any problem. The "O-Consciousness" project, he developed it, while he stayed alone locked in the lab. Impressive project, but looks quite unrealizable to me. In case of success we're expecting a giant leap for humanity, not just some ordinary breakthrough! We're working passionly, updating the equipment for new purposes. All of us are excited and enthusiastic.\n\n
		2006, April 2.\nThere're strange things happening - we were able to create some object that professor Mengelin believes can give endless knowledge to a human when directly contacted. I think, he's going crazy due to side effects of the lab unit fields. But I have to admit that the strange object does influence consciousness when one gets close to it. Also the object can be physically explored, touched and even seen only during certain time periods. I have no idea so far as to why and how it's possible.\n\n
		2006, April 3.\n\nTonight Mengelin shot himself in his office. There's a mess in the lab, some government agents have arrived and seized all research documents. They're disassembling our equipment and moving it away without explaining anything. Also, a group of well armed militants has arrived with them. Strange camo and black berets. I can't recognize their insignia. They're acting quietly, looking unkindly, and our own security team has disappeared. All proceedings were stopped, we were not able to test the strange object. Looks like we won't be able to do this any more - the government obviously decided to stop our experiments. I was appointed the head of our science team and got the order to destroy all evidences. But that object is priceless! It's a single specimen of our experiments! I couldn't destroy it. When we shipped another part of equipment, I sneaked to the plant and hid the object. Later I'm going to return and collect it... Hope, I'll make it...\n\n
		P.S. In case I forget the place - I hid it under some pipes near the compressor building that is located near the main project building in the yard of the plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_unknow_zapisi_tomsona_name">
		<text>Big pile of papers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_unknow_zapisi_tomsona_desc">
		<text>A big pile of science papers, which are partially encrypted and full of scientific terms, formulas and terminological computations. Looks like they are only for scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_serdce_yantar_desc">
		<text>O-21 object. You feel strange extension of consciousness with undescribable clarity when near it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_serdce_yantar_name">
		<text>O-21 object</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_case_use_rub_name">
		<text>Case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_case_use_rub_desc">
		<text>A hard case with unknown contents. Locked with a code lock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_a_case_name">
		<text>Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_a_case_desc">
		<text>If you're the one I think you are, then you know, where Strelok's stash is. There you'll find the key-code for this case. And if i'm mistaken about your identity, then you better stay out of this matter for your own safety. Be aware: the main switch in the X-10 lab is booby trapped and connected to tanks with nerve gas. If disabled by an unauthorized stranger, all the lab will blow up and the nerve gas will begin to fill all the rooms. Instructions for disabling the switch are located in the case which is protected as well: there's a ceramic flask with compressed "Witch's Jelly" which will be released in case of an unauthorized attempt to open the lid. All the data (and the cracksman) will then be destroyed. So, if you're a stranger - leave this case and walk your way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_2_a_case_desc">
		<text>If you're reading this, than I was right about you: you're exactly the person I hoped. But I still have some doubts about you, though I hope they are unnecessary.\nThere is only one part of the code inside the case. Messenger has the other part. Meet him by the old village near the "Freedom" base.\nLooks like Monolithians declared war on you, heh, like in those good old times. I can't help you so far, as I have so many enemies now. You don't need excessive attention. Hope, you'll recognize me when we meet.\n Case password: 20061204</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_3_a_case_desc">
		<text>"rksr" is the remaining part of the code. Yes, you'll need to enter the passcode and then pull the switch. Hope, you'll find, what you seek. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_monolit_name">
		<text>PDA of a monolithian</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_monolit_desc">
		<text>PDA of a soldier from the "Monolith" faction. Only one record: "Brothers, one of the infidels got the ability to reach the sanctuary of the Holy Monolith. You must stop him at any cost! It's known that he's carrying the nickname "Marked One", doing bussiness with Barkeep and professor Sakharov. Photo is attached. There're information that he may have some companions. All of them should be destroyed, but he is the main target. Protective helmet, that is owned by him, should be collected and delivered to the Elders, or it must be destroyed if there are no other options."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pol_code_of_case_name">
		<text>Part of the case code</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pol_code_of_case_desc">
		<text>First part of the code to the laptop at the Radar control room: "cnfkrth"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_pda_scoryi_name">
		<text>Quick's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_scoryi_desc">
		<text>Quick's PDA.\nFirst record:\n"Sitnik and I are returning from a raid with plenty of loot! But Sitnik is strange, I don't like him. I noticed different knots on my bag after last rest halt - some stranger definitely messed with them. Sitnik is the only one who could do it. Ad he was the last to keep watch. I think, he is likely to betray me. This is surely my last voyage through the Zone. I have enough money to cure Mila now. I've wade through it for a long time! And now, when my goal is so close, I can almost feel the taste of a happy life for our entire family! I miss you, my dear!\nWe're heading to Sidor, we're close. I want to reach Cordon ASAP and say bye to Sitnik! He's somewhat fishy. I can't understand, what bothers me so much about him... But he's dangerous, I can feel it... That's it, I'm ending this and we'll go..."\nArchive record, high priority: Wife address (personal account): u18no00qbv5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_notebook_mercs_name">
		<text>Mercenary's notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_notebook_mercs_desc">
		<text>Mercenary's notebook.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_box_moneys_name">
		<text>Bag with money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_box_moneys_desc">
		<text>Bag with money.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_pda_preobr_name">
		<text>Preobrajensky's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_preobr_desc">
		<text>Professor Preobrajensky's PDA. Records:\n
		"Day 1. Time: 21-04.\nVolunteers appeared today, they agreed to guide me to the research area. We've got there smoothly - the guides turned to be quite experienced. They established our camp in a fast and professional manner. I even got enough free time and managed to take some readings.\n
		Day 2. Time: 19-25.\n It was raining all day today. We couldn't establish a fire so we had cold meat for breakfast. My devices can't work in the rain. So I just wandered around, collected some plants just to save my day. Hope, it doesn't rain tomorrow.\n
		Day 3. Time: 21-20.\n The weather improved finally. Didn't have my breakfast, just went to take readings. When I was in the field, my guides met with two men. All four talked and looked at me. I was working at that time. After 20 minutes the strange stalkers were gone. I asked about them at dinner but Toha just glanced at me and winked. I don't like it.\nDay 4. Time: 11-00.\nThose two stalkers showed up again about half an hour ago. I was inside my tent and the stalkers talked near the bonfire. I heard some especially suspicious phrases like "...there'll be no problems with him..." and "...the customer has been waiting". Seems like they are venturing something. This is no good..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_stebel_ri_name">
		<text>Stem of a plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_stebel_ri_desc">
		<text>Stem of the Ranunculus insolita.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_lekar_for_sidor_name">
		<text>Philter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_lekar_for_sidor_desc">
		<text>A healing philter made of the stem of Ranunculus insolita.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_gribnik_name">
		<text>Mushroomer's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_gribnik_desc">
		<text>PDA of a stalker named Mushroomer.\nLast record:\n"There's some strong virus in the tank that we've found. For sure we'll benefit from it. I believe there're people in the Zone to get interested in something of this kind."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_leshyi_name">
		<text>Goblin's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_leshyi_desc">
		<text>PDA of a stalker named Goblin.\nLast record:\n"Got rid of Mushroomer. Now, when we found such a valuable thing, I don't need him any longer. I've already got customers for the virus. One dose was sold to Adder, he's a bandit, I guess. He mentioned something about Sidor. Wants to poison him? That would be good. The old prick has owned that fat place for too long."</text>
	</string>
</string_table>