<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Hello, Stalker! I hope you came here to help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Got it, I'll stay on guard. Thank you, Zaharich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Oh, really... I think I know where they moved the camp, son. But if I am right - it's bad, really bad. In the entire Darkscape there is only one such place - hidden and protected from all sides. On the road from the Dark Valley there is a tunnel in the narrow part of the canyon. In that tunnel, if memory serves me well, there was a shed where the road workers kept their tools for tunnel maintenance. It seems to me, that's where they headed. But if that's true, you probably won't find them alive. A controller took a liking to that shed, evil and tough. He lures people there and eats them, but sometimes he leaves for a few days. If they went there, he got them for sure, which is sure going to make him happy, that accursed evil creature. If you go there, equip well, and be careful. If the controller is there - you are in trouble, and will have to fight. Also - the tunel is full of anomalies, so don't believe everything you see. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1_1">
		<text>I don't know it myself, was just going to ask if you saw it. They said it was a comfortable place, protected from all sides and hidden.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>Moved where?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1">
		<text>We had no contact with them for a while, I was sent to find out if anything had happened to them. I heard they moved the camp, and we haven't heard from them since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1">
		<text>Which scientists? Those that were taking measurements here from the very beginning? I saw them, I used to bring them fresh food from time to time, when they had trouble getting their food supplies. It's been a while however, but why do you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_0">
		<text>Listen, Zaharich, have you seen a scientists' camp here in the Ravine?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>I heard your conversation. What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_2_1">
		<text>I was just passing by.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Alright, be attentive. We were attacked by bandits from Kulgavy's band. They wanted to kick us out from the Sawmill, and they would have done it easily by now, because they are much better armed than we are, and all we have is hunting rifles. However, we managed to capture one of their scouts, and the bandits are hesitant to attack. He must know something they need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Interesting. Why don't you just release the captive and leave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>If we run now, we will run again and again. We must wipe this scum out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I don't even know how to help you. Let me scout out how many we are dealing with here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>I see you never dealt with criminals. Their word can't be trusted at all - we give them back the prisoner and they will just shoot us all. Whatever we do, we must be sure we'll make it out alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>What does this scout know? Have you tried getting it out of him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>We tried, but he's keeping his mouth shut. Bachinsky even punched him a couple of times, but that didn't help. We didn't really try too hard after that. And why do we even want to know the bandits' business? We are just trying to save our own hide here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>That information might actually help. Maybe I can make him talk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>OK, you can try, but if you start torturing him and he screams, the bandits might hear and start the attack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Did you see the kind of weapons my guys have? The bandits, by the way, have sub-machine guns and grenades, and also more men. I don't want to lose my guys. They are all that is left from the Scout group after the expedition failed. But if you are sure you want to help us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>%c[255,255,118,118]I'm sure. I want to see those guys six feet under!%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>You are right, we have to think this through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>Consider the situation yourself. Listen... Maybe you can make a deal with them? Or at least distract them, while we make a run for it? That would be nice. I'm begging you - go to their camp, take a look, talk to their boss, be attentive, and then report back to me, OK?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>OK, I'll go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenn_pomilov_dialog1_phrase_1">
		<text>Flea wouldn't budge, but he agreed to tell us where he hid the information if we let him go. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenn_pomilov_dialog1_phrase_2">
		<text>I say it's worth it. I suspect that if we get that info, we'll be able to get rid of the bandits for good. Tell Flea to tell us where he hid it, and we let him go if we can resolve this conflict to our satisfaction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenn_pomilov_dialog1_phrase_3">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_0">
		<text>Looks like you are in deep shit, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Why are you concerned? How would you like to be the first to take a hike?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Today is not a good day to piss me off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>I need the info you were carrying to your boss. How much do you want for it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>More than you can get, lame.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Name the price, and I will decide myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Are you that stupid? I am a captive here, what am I going to do with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>I can arrange a deal to let you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Make the deal, and I will tell you. The main thing for me right now is to save myself. I have a feeling there is going to be quite a brawl, and I might be the first to bite the dust. If you ensure my safety, I will let you know where I hid the info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>OK, I'll talk to Yuri.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Yuri promised to let you go if you tell us where you left the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>All right, the hell with it! Somewhere here, not far from the Sawmill, I dropped my backpack with a note. It was dark at night, and then they hit me over the head when they grabbed me, so I don't remember exactly, but you should be able to find it with no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>If I don't, you are going to be the one with a problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Greetings, living soul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Hello to you too, grandpa. How is life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Life, or rather what's left of it... Little by little, day after day... as many as god wills it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>How did you happen to get in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>I didn't get here, the Zone grew around me. I used to live not far from here, in the village to the North. During the evacuation I decided to stay. And so I live here on whatever nature provides. The radiation here is not too bad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Why didn't you stay in the village? Why do you live in this hut?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Bandits kicked me out about a year ago, heathens.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>sorry about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Hey, grandpa, did anyone come to see you  lately, besides me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>There was a young lad, very talkative... Laughing and telling jokes all the time, even though he looked pretty raggedy himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Raggedy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Someone was after him, so he came here to hide out. I realized it right away, even though he didn't tell me anything. I've seen it before.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>But why did he come to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Very few people know about my hut: only the Scouts at the Sawmill, and now you. It's pretty deep in the woods, a good place to hide when someone is after you. He didn't look like a murderer or a thief, I can see right through people. He had kind eyes, and that's why I let him in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>And where is he now? Left?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>You see... It's a sad story. Greed got the best of him. So many it killed! Only the bullets and the beasts killed more. He stayed here for three days only. In the evening I used to tell him some stories I had heard from locals. Once I told him about the Death-zone and the "Light" artifact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>What is this "Death-zone"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>That's a place nearby, a real death trap. The Evil forced the earth to pump up and rise up in the air, and holds it like that. The Evil is so strong there, that it kills all life that touches it. Nothing can pass by it, everyone drops dead - animals, people, even birds. And you can't trick it: neither with a scientific suit, nor with a gadget. It's also treacherous - it lures the unsuspecting with pretty things. Rumour has it that at the center of the place lies an artifact called "Darkness". Whoever finds it, will discover many of the Zone's treasures and the hidden places that one can't see with a naked eye. That's the legend...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>So the Talkative went to look for that artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>Yes. I tried to talk him out of it, but he didn't heed the old man, and left for his death. He never came back, may god take mercy on his soul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Tell me, grandpa, where is this "Death-zone"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Do you want to die from the Evil Force too? Come to your sense, save your soul!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>No, I'm just curious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>In the woods, to the West of here. Stay away from that place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>Listen, Zaharich... I need to get in there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_18">
		<text>Greed got you too.. Oh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_19">
		<text>It's not greed. I need some information, and a part of it was with the lad that got lost in the "Death-zone". Maybe I should ask the scientists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_20">
		<text>What kind of information could be so important? However... There is a way. It is very risky, almost as dangerous as the Evil of that anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_21">
		<text>We'll pick the lesser of the two evils.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_22">
		<text>Legend has it, that the death radiation of that zone is many times amplified radiation of one extremely harmful artifact. The artifact was formed near an old soviet power transformer, and it somehow amplified its harmful effect and spread it over a large area, creating the "Death-zone".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_23">
		<text>Supposably.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_24">
		<text>The point is, that this artifact called "Darkness" was at one time a part of one whole artifact, that was destroyed by one overly curious stalker. The second half is called "Light" and has an opposite, healing effect. Together the two halves balance each other out. So, if someone has the "Light", he can enter the "Death-zone" unharmed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_25">
		<text>Where do I find this "Light"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_26">
		<text>Therein lies the problem. The stalker that split the artifact in half, perished a long time ago, and took the secret of its whereabouts to the grave with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_27">
		<text>Dead end?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_28">
		<text>I don't think so... I will tell you a secret. I know a stalker, rather not even a stalker... So he knew that curious guy, and knows where his grave is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_29">
		<text>Tell me his name.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_30">
		<text>Hold on, don't be in such a rush! Oh, youth...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_31">
		<text>What is it, grandpa? Did you forget his name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_32">
		<text>A name like that you don't forget.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_33">
		<text>Then what is it? Maybe you can tell me in exchange for something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_34">
		<text>I will tell you for free, but believe me - it is better for you not to know it at all. And I am not in a habit to even utter his name, just in case...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_35">
		<text>Who is it then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_36">
		<text>Let's do this: I will give you a book, you'll read it and find out. The main character of the book is the one you need. It's all because I don't want to utter his name, not to summon evil. Here, take it, read it, and then I will tell you where you can find this... man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_37">
		<text>You've indeed fogged this issue to a real mystery, grandpa! OK, give me the book.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I've read the book.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Do you understand who I was talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>But the Dark Salker is a myth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Well, if you think so, go up the hill southwest of here. This "myth" often appears there, and not alone. And one more thing! Do not shoot the dog, understand? Or you will regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Every day I get more and more convinced that the Zone is a land of miracles. OK, will he lead me to the grave of the stalker that used to posess the "Light"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I think so. Just be very careful with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I was wondering around and found something interesting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>What kind of nonsense is this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>I found a note that you were going to switch allegiance to another boss, and then set Kulgavy up so he wouldn't wring your neck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>You bitch! Give me the note or die!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>If you kill me, the note will be delivered, and that's not going to be good for your health. So I suggest you get the hell out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>OK, frayer, we'll meet again someday in a dark corner!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>If we both live long enough!</text>
	</string>

<!-- NEW OGSR QUEST CONTENT -->

	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>Good day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Who the hell are you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>Just a stalker. And you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Just a stalker? Bullshit. Who sent you?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>I don't get it.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>I'll say this nice and clear: get the fuck out.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>What's that supposed to mean?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_9">
	<text>I'm the law. Got it?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_10">
	<text>Okay, you've made your point.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_11">
	<text>I live by thieves' laws, fair and square. You won't understand, so get the fuck out.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_12">
	<text>Come on, this is not some prison.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_13">
	<text>Yeah? So I shouldn't live by the thieves' laws anymore? It's in my blood. I can't live any other way, I'd rather tear out my own teeth. I don't give a shit who you are. You come here and disrespect me and my way of life. Tell me, how should I kill you? With a bullet, or slowly with a knife? Maybe by suffocation? Maybe one of my guys behind you will suddenly snap your neck?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_14">
	<text>Fuck you, motherfucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_15">
	<text>Calm down. I respect you and your law.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_16">
	<text>Ahem... you don't look like a pig, so that's good. Oh and about hot water, I could go for a cup o' chifir, but I got no water. Care to get me some?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_17">
	<text>Oh, no problem.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_18">
	<text>Wait, that's not why I came here.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_19">
	<text>Then go get the water and hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_20">
	<text>What the fuck do you mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_21">
	<text>This place is deserted, it's just forest everywhere, so when I saw some people I just wanted to check out what's going on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_22">
	<text>Shit, well... you don't seem like a cop. Say, can you read? That shit bores me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_23">
	<text>Books... what? If you're bored, I can tell you something interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_24">
	<text>Interesting? Okay, let's have a little chat about our mourners' affairs. You wouldn't happen to know Owl, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_25">
	<text>He's the leader of a group of stalkers, right? They were in some trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_26">
	<text>No, who's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_27">
	<text>Nevermind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_28">
	<text>What kind of trouble?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_29">
	<text>In the Cordon, I found a diary belonging to a group of Stalkers. There were five of them, but they were hunted down one by one. Owl was one of them. They had interesting information on them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_30">
	<text>Interesting! Almost as interesting as The Count of Monte Cristo. You're quite the storyteller.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_31">
	<text>This is not fiction, it's a true story. I can even be called a witness to some of this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_32">
	<text>Bullshit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_33">
	<text>Let The Zone take me if I'm lying.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_34">
	<text>Prove it, then.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_35">
	<text>I have some personal belongings from these stalkers.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_36">
	<text>Don't you dare walk away from me.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_37">
	<text>Ah, I knew you had something interesting in your pockets. You should sell it to me.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_38">
	<text>I can't do that. I have to uncover the secret of these stalkers.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_39">
	<text>For how much?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_40">
	<text>I can give you fifty grand, or a unique gun that nobody else has in The Zone. Choose.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_41">
	<text>Money.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_42">
	<text>Guns.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_43">
	<text>Right on! Business is looking good all of a sudden. Goodbye, America!</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_44">
	<text>Don't leave, motherfucker! If you don't sell it, we'll take it ourselves. At least you will be with money, rather than having a few extra holes in your body. For the last fucking time, hand it over.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_45">
	<text>No, I won't.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_46">
	<text>How much will you give me?</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_47">
	<text>Oh, so you're still peeing. Who's a fucking thief... you want that thief's mouth... Fuck him, guys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_48">
	<text>Take it easy! That's not what I meant.</text>
	</string>	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_7_1">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]What's that supposed to mean?%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_8_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]I get it.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_14_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]Fuck you, motherfucker.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_15_1">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]I respect you and your law. Relax.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_17_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]Oh, no problem.%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_18_1">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Wait, that's not why I'm here.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_25_1">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]I know of him. He's the leader of a group of stalkers, they were in trouble.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_26_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]No, who's that?%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_35_1">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]I have some personal belongings of these stalkers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_36_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]Don't you dare.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_45_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]No, I won't.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_12_1">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Come on, we're not in jail.%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog1_phrase_38_1">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]I can't do that. I have to uncover the secret of these stalkers.%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	

	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>Here's the water. What kind of chifir?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>What do you mean, "What kind of chifir?" You're an errand boy, and I'm sick of talking to you. Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>Got it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog2_phrase_4">
	<text>Bastard!</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>One of your guys told me that there's a serious situation developing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>Just who are you talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Troll. I met him near the rookie village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_4">
	<text>Okay, but the work is dirty, you know? Of course, I've already been told by Troll that you're not afraid to work with people like us. You gotta have balls in order to work with us. The work is going to be both bloody and run-of-the-mill, but always muddy. You have to use force, but you also have to use your head. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_5">
	<text>Sounds good, please continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_6">
	<text>Ugh... fuck you, man. I don't like how this sounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_7">
	<text>That info you gave me on those stalkers and their expeditions is very valuable stuff. Just how valuable I'm not sure, I'll need to discuss it with my guys. How much money do you need to make sure you have enough for the rest of your life, so that you don't have to work bullshit jobs anymore? I'll be more specific: there's a rumor that somewhere deep in The Zone there's a hidden place with unique artifacts. I've had my guys try to dig up more info. These flash drives have some general clues, but...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_8">
	<text>From the info I had, I get it. I didn't understand that it was about something so valuable, but you know better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_9">
	<text>I'm telling you, if this treasure trove is as good as we think, then every single one of my brothers will cash out as millionaires! And you too, if you play your part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_10">
	<text>Get to the point. What is my role in all of this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_11">
	<text>You'll be working as a horse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_12">
	<text>...What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_13">
	<text>It's simple: I'm giving you a tip, and you're giving me hooves, hooves! Heh-heh-heh. Don't worry, I won't put you up to this, I see that you're a man. But a man should work. You will do my tasks here, in this area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_14">
	<text>Where do we start?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_15">
	<text>Let's start with your name. Since you don't have one, you need to come up with one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_16">
	<text>I suppose "Marked One" won't do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_17">
	<text>Huh. Well, if you're gonna run with us, you need a new handle. Make your choice, and from now on that is how my brothers will refer to you:\nCocky \nGreyhound \nShiv \nDragon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_18">
	<text>Cocky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_19">
	<text>Greyhound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_20">
	<text>Shiv.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_21">
	<text>Dragon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_22">
	<text>I figured that's what you were gonna choose. Cocky, since you were not afraid to come to me alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_23">
	<text>Ah, so the greyhound can bark to my orders. Hah!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_24">
	<text>Hah! You will stick a Shiv into the ribs of suckers on my orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_25">
	<text>You're burned, asshole. Because a dragon is a rooster, only with a comb all over his back... I suspected that you'd choose that. Get out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_26">
	<text>Okay, what now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_27">
	<!--<text>Надо найти и слить одного лоха. Погоняло у него соответствующее - Чухан. Вернее, раньше он на Хмурого отзывался, но со временем скурвился, перестал мыться и харю брить, завшивел, пердел, когда пацаны кушали. Короче, мы решили его опустить, так и сделали, ну и погоняло сменили. А этот Чухан взял и свалил, да ещё и в отместку сп.здил мой именной чифирбак. Короче, надо эту тварь найти, замочить и чифирбак мой вернуть. Уяснил?</text>-->
	<text>We need to find one sucker, and we need to make him bleed. His name is Chuhan - he used to take orders from Frowny, but over time he became a bum; he quit shaving, got smelly, started farting whenever the guys were eating. So we had to teach him a lesson, but then he took off with my chifir mug. Bring my mug back, and make him pay. Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_28">
	<text>Got it. Give me a tip where he hangs out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_29">
	<text>Not far from here, somewhere near the tunnel to the Cordon. You gonna go or are my boys gonna drop you off?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_30">
	<text>I'll go by myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_phrase_31">
	<text>Your guys can take me.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_1">
	<text>What are you and your men doing here? This place is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_2">
	<text>Why the fuck do you care? Sniffing around like some fucking cop. You better get out of here, mutt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_3">
	<text>I just want to help you and your boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_3_1">
	<text>I'm not connected to the police nor "Duty". Forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_4">
	<text>Okay, but the work is dirty, you know? Of course, I've already been told by Troll that you're not afraid to work with people like us. You gotta have balls in order to work with us. The work is going to be both bloody and run-of-the-mill, but always muddy. You have to use force, but you also have to use your head. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_5">
	<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_6">
	<text>Ugh... fuck you, man. I don't like how this sounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_7">
	<text>That info you gave me on those stalkers and their expeditions is very valuable stuff. Just how valuable I'm not sure, I'll need to discuss it with my guys. How much money do you need to make sure you have enough for the rest of your life, so that you don't have to work bullshit jobs anymore? I'll be more specific: there's a rumor that somewhere deep in The Zone there's a hidden place with unique artifacts. I've had my guys try to dig up more info. These flash drives have some general clues, but...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_8">
	<text>From the info I had, I get it. I didn't understand that it was about something so valuable, but you know better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_9">
	<text>I'm telling you, if this treasure trove is as good as we think, then every single one of my brothers will cash out as millionaires! And you too, if you play your part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_10">
	<text>Get to the point. What is my role in all of this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_11">
	<text>You'll be working as a horse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_12">
	<text>...What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_13">
	<text>It's simple: I'm giving you a tip, and you're giving me hooves, hooves! Heh-heh-heh. Don't worry, I won't put you up to this, I see that you're a man. But a man should work. You will do my tasks here, in this area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_14">
	<text>Where do we start?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_15">
	<text>Let's start with your name. Since you don't have one, you need to come up with one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_16">
	<text>I suppose "Marked One" won't do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_17">
	<text>Huh. Well, if you're gonna run with us, you need a new handle. Make your choice, and from now on that is how my brothers will refer to you:\nCocky \nGreyhound \nShiv \nDragon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_18">
	<text>Cocky.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_19">
	<text>Greyhound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_20">
	<text>Shiv.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_21">
	<text>Dragon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_22">
	<text>I figured that's what you were gonna choose. Cocky, since you were not afraid to come to me alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_23">
	<text>Ah, so the greyhound can bark to my orders. Hah!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_24">
	<text>Hah! You will stick a shiv into the ribs of suckers on my orders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_25">
	<text>You're burned, asshole. Because a dragon is a rooster, only with a comb all over his back... I suspected that you'd choose that. Get out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_26">
	<text>Okay, what now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_27">
	<text>We need to find one sucker, and we need to make him bleed. His name is Chuhan - he used to take orders from Frowny, but over time he became a bum; he quit shaving, got smelly, started farting whenever the guys were eating. So we had to teach him a lesson, but then he took off with my chifir mug. Bring my mug back, and make him pay. Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_28">
	<text>Got it. Give me a tip where he hangs out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_29">
	<text>Not far from here. You gonna go or are my boys gonna drop you off?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_30">
	<text>I'll go myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog3_1_phrase_31">
	<text>Your guys can take me.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>Where's Chuhan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>There's a bus over there by the tunnel. That's where he was last seen. Go wipe him out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>You got it.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>Nice, bro! Holster your piece. You better sit down, smoke, talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Shut up, you lousy prick! Give me the chifir mug.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Why not? There's no rush. What are we going to talk about?%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>To our lives, the thieves' lives! Hey, did you sit down?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>No, I didn't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>I did my time, four years. Article 113. Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>I don't remember the penal code by heart. I know only article 666 - "For the rape of cattle."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>Tough, brother, tough, ha, ha, ha! Check out your jokes. Okay, jokes aside. I give you a lead on some real swag, and you let me go. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_9">
	<text>Then go quietly. But give back the mug first, and don't ever show your face around here again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_looser_dialog1_phrase_10">
	<text>Shut up and die.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_1">
	<text>I've brought the mug.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_2">
	<text>Yeah? Give it here! Come, have some chifir and let's talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_3">
	<text>Alright, okay. Let's see... What is this shit you bozo? This fag-chifir's got holes in it! You trying to make look like a faggot?! I'll rip your damn throat out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_4">
	<text>Faggy? Hey, what's so gay about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_5">
	<text>'Cause it's got holes in it, see? Someone drilled a hole in it to cover with your fingers while drinking. That's how they mark fag tableware so real men won't drink from it. Utter shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_6">
	<text>Honestly, I'm not aware of such subtleties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_7">
	<text>No shit, you never did any time. Whatever, if you don't know then it don't count. But the chifir is fucked regardless, seems Chuhan got his last word in before death. You capped him though, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_8">
	<text>Of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_9">
	<text>Then we'll move on to the next task. I know what you're thinking, Cocky: what the hell was that thing with Chuhan? You're right, it was just a test. And regarding Owl and that treasure they're after, my guys made good progress uncovering more info thanks to that flash drive. They found out that these stalkers found a lot of fancy artifacts and somehow used some kind of anomaly to capture them and hide them... Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_10">
	<text>Then we'll move on to the next task. I know what you're thinking, Greyhound: what the hell was that thing with Chuhan? You're right, it was just a test. And regarding Owl and that treasure they're after, my guys made good progress uncovering more info thanks to that flash drive. They found out that these stalkers found a lot of fancy artifacts and somehow used some kind of anomaly to capture them and hide them... Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_11">
	<text>Then we'll move on to the next task. I know what you're thinking, Shiv: what the hell was that thing with Chuhan? You're right, it was just a test. And regarding Owl and that treasure they're after, my guys made good progress uncovering more info thanks to that flash drive. They found out that these stalkers found a lot of fancy artifacts and somehow used some kind of anomaly to capture them and hide them... Do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_12">
	<text>They hid their artifacts in a spatial anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_13">
	<text>You really pay attention, don't you? My guys have also learned that this anomaly is somewhere in the North, but we don't know exactly where. There is one person who knew of this Owl and his expedition; he's known as Thrush, a wannabe huckster. Guess what? He owes us a lot of money, and has been in debt to us for a long time. We periodically shake down those who come snooping around, just to persuade them to beat it. Thrush is one of the last guys we haven't gotten around to yet. Go talk to him about Owl and the expedition, and get the money from him. He owes us a hundred grand. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_14">
	<text>Got it. Where can I find him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_15">
	<text>I think he's here in Darkscape. My driver knows more precisely, he will drop you off. Or will you go by yourself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_16">
	<text>We'd better get going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog4_phrase_17">
	<text>I'll walk.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>So where is this huckster, Thrush?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>He should be over there, behind those rocks on the left side of the road. He's an idiot, he won't try to cheat the boss. Pressure him and he'll bend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>I'll figure it out.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>Any idea where this guy is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>I believe he's down the road, a hundred yards away. At the old stop.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Okay, let's check it out.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog4_phrase_1">
	<text>Are we here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog4_phrase_2">
	<text>Kind of... but keep watch. I smell a setup.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog4_phrase_3">
	<text>I'll check it out.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog5_phrase_1">
	<text>Well, where'd that one go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog5_phrase_2">
	<text>Кароче, дальше по дороге будет заправка. Но там братва неправильная рядом сидит, я туда не поеду... У запарвки хаза небольшая, там на втором этаже видели этого штриха. Сразу не вали его, сначала пусть инфу сольет.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_driver_dialog5_phrase_3">
	<text>Sounds simple enough.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>There you are. Thought we wouldn't find you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>I'm from Kulgavy's band.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Man, I knew it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>I've got two pieces of news for you: bad news and not so bad news. Which do you want first?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>Come on... let's go with the bad one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>The interest has increased this whole time. Now you owe the guys 100,000 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>What interest! I owed ten grand, and a month later one hundred?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_9">
	<text>And the second news is, you have to tell me everything you know about Owl and his expedition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_10">
	<text>You found out... Man, listen to me, please. I see that you're not as much of a punk as the rest of them. Perhaps you joined them recently? I want to explain to you why I couldn't get the money back in time. I'm just planning to start my own business. I bought a lot of equipment - food, medicine, clothes, bullets and other things stalkers need. Just business, nothing criminal. However, these bastards found out about it and attacked me, demanding a cut. You know how it is, they say it's their turf so they need a piece of any of the action that goes on here. Taxes and all that. But I hadn't even sold anything yet! A shipment of my goods disappeared somewhere in The Zone, but the bandits didn't want to hear it. I was left with nothing but debt. Please understand my position. Can you explain that to Kulgavy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_11">
	<text>Shut up and pay up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_12">
	<text>Yeah, you're out of luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_13">
	<text>All I have is 35,000 rubles. You can take them and choke on them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_14">
	<text>Give it to me. And watch your tongue; just for that, another 20 grand is added to your debt, so you still owe 85,000. Now tell me everything you know about Owl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_15">
	<text>He told me a little bit, I just remember there was an intention to get some kind of "key". What is this key and what it opens - no idea ... You'll find more info in his spare cache, in the Dark Valley. Here are the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_16">
	<text>Where's that "key"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_17">
	<text>I think it's somewhere in the Dark Valley. Owl's personal cache was there, but it was hidden in a tricky place. Here are the approximate coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_18">
	<text>Oh, man, if you knew how hard it was for me. I even went to Duty for protection, to no avail. If you help me, I will give you a very valuable hint on Owl and his stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_19">
	<text>It's a deal. I'll pay Kulgavy out of my pocket.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_20">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]It's a deal. But what about the money?%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_21">
	<text>I have a plan: help me find my lost goods, then I can sell them like I planned all along and pay Kulgavy properly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_22">
	<text>Any idea where they are?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_23">
	<text>It's nearby somewhere, in this damn forest. It was supposed to be delivered on a truck. The driver contacted me on the radio two days ago and told me he was about a kilometre away. Then the connection was cut off and that's the last I've heard from him. Here are the approximate coordinates of the place where he last radioed us. If you find a car there, bring it right here. And I'll tell you everything I know about Owl and his expedition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_24">
	<text>Okay, the task is clear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog1_phrase_25">
	<text>Man, you're my Savior! I do not know who you are, but now for you my prices will be as low as possible. Come a little later, I will offer the best equipment.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>Take your car. Over there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>Dude, you saved me! Now I can set up trade in these places and pay off the racketeers. I don't understand... you seem like a decent guy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>I'm doing it for the rewards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog2_phrase_4">
	<text>Yeah, well... I still wish you good luck. Come to the fire on the old sawmill, which is to the south! There's a stalker camp there, that's where I'll set up shop. For you - the lowest prices! About Owl: he told me a little bit, I just remember that there were intentions to get some kind of "key". What is this key and what it opens - no idea ... You'll find more info in his spare cache, in the Dark Valley. Here are the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog2_phrase_5">
	<text>Well, thank you.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_1">
	<text>Here I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_2">
	<text>So, you got the money from Thrush?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_3">
	<text>He didn't have any money. However, I managed to acquire all the goods he was planning to sell. Is this enough?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_4">
	<text>No money? Well, at least you got this, but as for Thrush? He needs to be stepped on. I'll have my guys unload the cargo. And what about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_5">
	<text>No money? Well, at least you got this, but as for Thrush? He needs to be stepped on. I'll have my guys unload the cargo. And what about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_6">
	<text>No money? Well, at least you got this, but as for Thrush? He needs to be stepped on. I'll have my guys unload the cargo. And what about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_7">
	<text>Thrush told me of a stash belonging to Owl, and gave me approximate coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_8">
	<text>Okay, that's something. Have a rest, Cocky, have some chifir, smokes, booze. Then get ready to move your hooves; go check out that stash once you're rested up. Clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_9">
	<text>Okay, that's something. Have a rest, Greyhound, have some chifir, smokes, booze. Then get ready to move your hooves; go check out that stash once you're rested up. Clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_10">
	<text>Okay, that's something. Have a rest, Shiv, have some chifir, smokes, booze. Then get ready to move your hooves; go check out that stash once you're rested up. Clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_phrase_11">
	<text>Will do.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_1">
	<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_1_1">
	<text>So, you got the money from Thrush?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_2">
	<text>He only had 35 grand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_3">
	<text>Fuck, Cocky, what the fuck are you doing, dickhead? He's a huckster, he always has something stashed away you fucking idiot! You should've shoved your fucking gun down his throat and make him see the light at the end of the fucking tunnel! Get over here you moron, I'm taking that 35k and I'm taking 10 grand out of your fucking pocket for your incompetence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_4">
	<text>Fuck, Greyhound, what the fuck are you doing, dickhead? He's a huckster, he always has something stashed away you fucking idiot! You should've shoved your fucking gun down his throat and make him see the light at the end of the fucking tunnel! Get over here you moron, I'm taking that 35k and I'm taking 10 grand out of your fucking pocket for your incompetence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_5">
	<text>Fuck, Shiv, what the fuck are you doing, dickhead? He's a huckster, he always has something stashed away you fucking idiot! You should've shoved your fucking gun down his throat and make him see the light at the end of the fucking tunnel! Get over here you moron, I'm taking that 35k and I'm taking 10 grand out of your fucking pocket for your incompetence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_6">
	<text>Is it necessary to threaten people like that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_7">
	<text>What are you, a fucking infant? Do you still have your innocence or something, you little twat? Of course it's necessary. Absolutely fucking necessary, otherwise my authority, my reputation is at stake. Or are you saying me and my boys are fucked up? No? Well, then people like him need to pay up. Don't ask such stupid fucking questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_8">
	<text>Yeah, if I did, I wouldn't stand on ceremony with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_9">
	<text>45,000? I don't have that much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_10">
	<text>Take off everything you're wearing and give it to me. Let that be a lesson for you. Now, what about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_11">
	<text>Thrush gave me information on a stash in the Dark Valley that supposedly belongs to Owl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_11_1">
	<text>Thrush gave me information on a stash in the Dark Valley that supposedly belongs to Owl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_12">
	<text>Finally, some good news. Have a smoke and then hit the road. Go find that stash, and do not disappoint me again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_12_1">
	<text>Finally, some good news. Have a smoke and then hit the road. Go find that stash, and do not disappoint me again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_13">
	<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_14">
	<text>What about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_15">
	<text>Finally, some good news. Have a smoke and then hit the road. Go find that stash, and do not disappoint me again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_1_phrase_16">
	<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_1">
	<text>Hey, here I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_1_1">
	<text>So, you got the money from Thrush?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_2">
	<text>Yeah, here it is. Feel free to count it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_3">
	<text>Great work, Cocky! We're gonna have to reward you. But the job ain't done yet. What about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_4">
	<text>Great work, Greyhound! We're gonna have to reward you. But the job ain't done yet. What about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_5">
	<text>Great work, Shiv! We're gonna have to reward you. But the job ain't done yet. What about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_6">
	<text>Thrush gave me info on a stash that belonged to Owl. It's in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_7">
	<text>Now that's a lead. Come, rest up a bit, have some chifir or a smoke, or some booze. Then go scratch your hooves on the road and check out that stash, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_2_phrase_8">
	<text>I'm on it.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_1">
	<text>Hey, here I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_2">
	<text>So, you got the money from Thrush?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_3">
	<text>No, he didn't have it. He was planning to pay you back after he sold some goods, but his shipment got lost. I found the shipment, returned it to him, and now he'll be able to pay up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_4">
	<text>Cocky, I don't understand just what kind of fucking idiot you are. Who do you think you work for, me or this faggot huckster Thrush? I sent you to collect, to collect from this motherfucker, to take his money and bring it back to me, yet instead you go and essentially bring money to him? You fucking retard. Now this faggot will feel like he has leverage over ME. Are you trying to ruin my fucking reputation? Well, you won't succeed. The only thing you'll succeed at is getting yourself buried alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_5">
	<text>Greyhound, I don't understand just what kind of fucking idiot you are. Who do you think you work for, me or this faggot huckster Thrush? I sent you to collect, to collect from this motherfucker, to take his money and bring it back to me, yet instead you go and essentially bring money to him? You fucking retard. Now this faggot will feel like he has leverage over ME. Are you trying to ruin my fucking reputation? Well, you won't succeed. The only thing you'll succeed at is getting yourself buried alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_6">
	<text>Shiv, I don't understand just what kind of fucking idiot you are. Who do you think you work for, me or this faggot huckster Thrush? I sent you to collect, to collect from this motherfucker, to take his money and bring it back to me, yet instead you go and essentially bring money to him? You fucking retard. Now this faggot will feel like he has leverage over ME. Are you trying to ruin my fucking reputation? Well, you won't succeed. The only thing you'll succeed at is getting yourself buried alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_7">
	<text>Hold your horses, boss. You see, if Thrush gets his business up and running, then we can collect that hundred grand and a lot more. He'll have to pay taxes too, you see?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_8">
	<text>And what if he just disappears now that you got him his goods? You were trying to be clever, but it turns out you're a fucking idiot. You were to acquire one hundred grand and bring it back to me. You have one last chance: pay up now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_9">
	<text>Okay okay, here's a hundred grand, and I'll go deal with Thrush. Also, about Owl: his stash is in the Dark Valley somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_10">
	<text>I don't have that much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_11">
	<text>Give me everything in your possession right now. And what about Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_12">
	<text>Well then, you better go take a look. Take a quick rest if you need it, then off you go. You better not disappoint me again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog5_3_phrase_13">
	<text>We need to find his stash, which is in the dark valley. That's where I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>Ah, you've showed up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>How do you know me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>Don't be alarmed, Cocky. Kulgavy's brothers are always aware of each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Don't be alarmed, Greyhound. Kulgavy's brothers are always aware of each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>Don't be alarmed, Shiv. Kulgavy's brothers are always aware of each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>So you're from the boss? But what are you doing here? And how'd you get here before me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>Ever heard of a radio? They've been around forever. I'm a local watchdog, and I'm often dispatched to solve problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>Maybe you know how to open Owl's stash? This is very important, the godfather himself is interested in it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_9">
	<text>I've checked it out. It's old and heavy, a crowbar can't pry it open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_10">
	<text>Can it be lockpicked?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_11">
	<text>I've tried, it's not going to work. I don't advise going there right now, there's a group of stalkers there who might come up asking questions. That's why I'm sitting here, to get away from those idiots. There's only one thing we can do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_12">
	<text>Tell me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_13">
	<text>We're gonna break it open with an anomaly. It's possible to "activate" an artifact and create a small anomaly from it. You need to activate an artifact that will create a springboard anomaly; do this on the door and then it'll be fucked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_14">
	<text>But then how do we get in with an anomaly in the doorway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_15">
	<text>We're gonna need a special artifact that creates a weak anomaly that might even disappear once it fucks up that door. I had one like this, but I sold it to some thug. Find him, get the artifact from him, and use it on the door. Then we're in business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_16">
	<text>Give me his coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog1_phrase_17">
	<text>He's here, very close by.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_1">
	<text>How's everyone doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_2">
	<text>Ah, this chifir is so sweet. Cocky! Come in, grab a seat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_3">
	<text>Ah, this chifir is so sweet. Greyhound! Come in, grab a seat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_4">
	<text>Ah, this chifir is so sweet. Shiv! Come in, grab a seat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_5">
	<text>I checked Owl's cache in the Dark Valley. There was a note with a hint about the key.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_6">
	<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_7">
	<text>This is not really a key, it's a special artifact that can be used to penetrate the spatial anomaly that contains the Klondike artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_8">
	<text>Interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_9">
	<text>Owl wrote that he went to retrieve the key in the Radar area. That's all we know for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_10">
	<text>Alright, I'll tell you what I know myself: while you were doing the job, my guys were getting some information about where this Klondike actually is. Radar, you say? That place is full of Monolith fanatics. Dangerous... I'll give you some money and equipment. You need to go to Radar and find this key.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_11">
	<text>Okay, but where exactly should we look for Owl's key? Without a clear lead, we could spend a year searching that place if it wasn't so deadly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_12">
	<text>I'm putting you in contact with one of our boys. A real treasure hunter, although he plays for keeps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_13">
	<text>Would he happen to be named Diplomat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_14">
	<text>No, where did you hear that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_15">
	<text>At the Dark Valley cache, I met someone who had already investigated it. He helped me open it in fact. That's the name he gave me, he said he was under your employ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_16">
	<text>Strange... you see, Cocky, Diplomat supposedly died in an anomaly but no trace of him was ever found. So he's back? Why the hell didn't he come see me first? This stinks, I don't like how this smells at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_17">
	<text>Strange... you see, Greyhound, Diplomat supposedly died in an anomaly but no trace of him was ever found. So he's back? Why the hell didn't he come see me first? This stinks, I don't like how this smells at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_18">
	<text>Strange... you see, Shiv, Diplomat supposedly died in an anomaly but no trace of him was ever found. So he's back? Why the hell didn't he come see me first? This stinks, I don't like how this smells at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_19">
	<text>Alright, if I see him again I'll let you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_20">
	<text>Need a ride, or are you gonna walk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_21">
	<text>I'll walk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog6_phrase_22">
	<text>Let's drive.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>You again!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>Calm down, Cocky. Did you show up for the job or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>Calm down, Greyhound. Did you show up for the job or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_4">
	<text>Calm down, Shiv. Did you show up for the job or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_5">
	<text>I don't get it: Kulgavy told me you perished in an anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_6">
	<text>I'm not dead. Open your eyes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_7">
	<text>Why are you hiding from the boss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_8">
	<text>I owe him money. Getting the point?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_9">
	<text>Well it's not my business. So what's happening?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_10">
	<text>I've spotted three fanatics, maybe scouts or maybe they're looking for something. Here's the plan: we waste two of them and make the third tell us where we can find Owl's key.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_11">
	<text>Sounds good to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_12">
	<text>Well, then let's move it, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog2_phrase_13">
	<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>What's the plan?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>Wait for them to start praying by the fire. Have you ever seen these freaks? Check this shit out. Then they'll be too distracted so we can sneak up and whack two of them easily. Remember to keep the third alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Let's do it.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog4_phrase_1">
	<text>I think we got them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog4_phrase_2">
	<text>We made some noise though. Go get the information from this freak, I'll cover us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog4_phrase_3">
	<text>Here we go.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_1">
	<text>Monolith... Death to the infidels...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_2">
	<text>Listen to me carefully. If you want to live and keep praying to your rock, then answer my questions. Have you seen a stalker called Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_3">
	<text>Death! Burn in hell, heretics!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_4">
	<text>No, that's not what you were supposed to say. Taste my boot, you fucking fanatic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_5">
	<text>Aah! Aah!! No, no, no! Monolith, save me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_6">
	<text>Your rock can't save you. Now tell me, where is Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_7">
	<text>I didn't see him! I don't know a stalker like that. We don't know the names of heretics, we just shoot to kill!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_8">
	<text>Have you seen any stalker come from the warehouses recently?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_9">
	<text>Yeah, they're heretics from Freedom. There are few of them. I don't know who exactly what their names are, I swear. The last time we saw them was here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_10">
	<text>Second question: where's the artifact key to the Klondike?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_11">
	<text>Kill me. I will never tell you that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_monolith_man_dialog_phrase_12">
	<text>Yeah, judging by your reaction, you know what I'm talking about. Let's continue the interrogation...</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_1">
	<text>The fanatic won't talk about the key, but it seems he saw Owl. He saw a stalker with some Freedom members in this area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_2">
	<text>Hmm... well that's better than nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_3">
	<text>According to the map, we should be looking for him here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_4">
	<text>Shit, his brains gotta be boiling up there. Okay, let me think... shit, I need some weed or chifir. You keep going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_5">
	<text>And you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_6">
	<text>Next time you see Kulgavy, tell him I'm ready to make up for my debt and I want to make amends. Alright?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog5_phrase_7">
	<text>You got it, I'll tell him.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>Those fanatics are something else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>Ah, man! Good to see you. You don't come across many people like you here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Did you say you had a job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog3_phrase_4">
	<text>Yes. As you can see, my business is slowly progressing: clients have already come in. But stalkers are afraid to come to this place due to the bandit presence. I need someone to spread the word about this place, specifically in the Cordon, Bar, and Dark Valley. Do me a favor: talk to camp leaders in these places, tell them about this place, be my marketing guy! Do that, and I'll give a solid chunk of what I've already earned: 40,000 rubles. Will you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog3_phrase_5">
	<text>I can do that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog3_phrase_6">
	<text>That's a lot of running around... maybe later.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>Hey. Tell me, are you on good terms with the stalkers here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Well, we're not fighting, are we?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>Just wanted to spread the word that there's a new trader in town, in Darkscape more specifically. The swag's not bad, and he has better prices than Sidorovich. Spread the word, okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Ah, you must work in advertising! Heh-heh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>Oh, come on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_6_1">
	<text>Do you have a Jellyfish artifact? Get me one and I'll tell everyone I know about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_6_2">
	<text>Do you have a Gravi artifact? Get me one and I'll tell everyone I know about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_6_3">
	<text>Do you have a Wrenched artifact? Get me one and I'll tell everyone I know about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>Alright, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="drozd_quest_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>I haven't got one.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog4_phrase_1">
	<text>So how's it going? Sidorovich is not after you yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog4_phrase_2">
	<text>Fuck him, he's old and ugly, ha-ha-ha-ha! I take it you've done as I asked?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog4_phrase_3">
	<text>I've been to every location and talked to everyone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog4_phrase_4">
	<text>Wonderful! I've already had some new customers. Here's the reward I promised, and something extra:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_trader_dialog4_phrase_5">
	<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog6_phrase_1">
	<text>Again you're ahead of me. How did you get through the Barrier?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog6_phrase_2">
	<text>Be more attentive. In short, I've scouted the area. I found a place that might have what we're looking for. Some kind of cache the fanatics have been using. I'll show you the way, but don't go too deep into this place or else you'll fry your brains.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog6_phrase_3">
	<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>

	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog7_phrase_1">
	<text>Is it here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog7_phrase_2">
	<text>I think so. Have a look around, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog7_phrase_3">
	<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog8_phrase_1">
	<text>I found a cache, but it was full of junk, except for this here:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog8_phrase_2">
	<text>What?! Raven's brigade knows about all this? Someone in our crew is a rat, that's for damn sure. So they took the key from right under our noses. And they want to set up a meeting in a specified place. Shit, you gotta go tell the boss. If he doesn't kill you on the spot, we'll see what comes next.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog8_phrase_3">
	<text>Kill me for what? Ugh... well, I'll see you later.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_1">
	<text>Boss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_2">
	<text>Ah, Cocky! Sit down, let's talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_3">
	<text>Ah, Greyhound! Sit down, let's talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_4">
	<text>Ah, Shiv! Sit down, let's talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_5">
	<text>Someone beat us to the cache in Radar. In place of the key, I found a letter addressed specifically to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_6">
	<text>From whom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_7">
	<text>Here, see for yourself: (show the letter from Radar).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_8">
	<text>What the fuck is this? Raven?! His eyes were shut forever a year ago, and his brothers joined my crew. Someone is making fun of me, but I'm not going to fall for that. We're gonna have to work carefully.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_9">
	<text>What do you suggest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_10">
	<text>I suggest we find out who they are and what the fuck they want. You go to the meeting in my stead, see who shows up and see what they want. I'll have some guys cover your ass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_11">
	<text>No problem. Can I get a ride?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog7_phrase_12">
	<text>No problem, just give me a moment to rest.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>I knew he'd send you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Raven? But I was told that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>Yeah, that bastard Kulgavy told you I was dead, I know. A good reason for you to doubt his reputation, isn't it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Why would he lie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>You're just a tool for him to gain access to the Klondike artifacts and other means of wealth. As soon as you bring him the key, he'll kill you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>I don't believe you, man. Who are you? Maybe you're just an impostor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>Okay, let's do this: we'll organize a face to face meeting. Bring Kulgavy and we talk to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>That's not gonna work.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>What the hell?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>Nothing personal, Cocky. This is not a challenge to you, but to Kulgavy. I give you my word that I will not lay a finger on him, I just want to talk. I'm waiting for him here in person - so tell him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>Nothing personal, Greyhound. This is not a challenge to you, but to Kulgavy. I give you my word that I will not lay a finger on him, I just want to talk. I'm waiting for him here in person - so tell him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog2_phrase_4">
	<text>Nothing personal, Shiv. This is not a challenge to you, but to Kulgavy. I give you my word that I will not lay a finger on him, I just want to talk. I'm waiting for him here in person - so tell him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog2_phrase_5">
	<text>Okay, I'll tell him.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>As neh. y-na. uy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>You on watch?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Yeah, what's it look like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>How long have you been in The Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>A year. Hey, you don't look like a sucker. How about a drink?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>I'll pour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>Pour it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_9">
	<text>Nice!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_10">
	<text>Why aren't you sobering up? The godfather can punish for such drunkenness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_11">
	<text>Ah, yeah, fuck, best to forget about the fucking stuff. You know, recently, a guy told me something weird called "The Dead Brigade". Have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_12">
	<text>Nope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_13">
	<text>They say nobody truly dies in The Zone. Not people, not beasts. You can put a bullet right into someone's head, but then one day you'll meet them again in The Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_patruln_dialog1_phrase_14">
	<text>Sounds like a load of shit.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>What's up, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Everything's fine... Hey, let's go outside and talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>Come on, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>Give me a break.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>So what's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>Well, here's the thing. We need to help a kid out. Don't be nervous, we won't be doing anything we shouldn't be doing. It's chicken shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>Be specific.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_4">
	<text>We all settled here a few months ago. These houses were empty so the boss ordered me to clean up before we all settle in. Anyways, in one of the attics I found an old safe. It's locked, of course. Help me open it and maybe we can both make a profit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_5">
	<text>You weren't able to open it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_6">
	<text>Well, here's the thing. It's in the attic of the boss's house. Can't really go make a mess of things right over his head, you see? And I'm already on a short leesh with the boss. Try to crack it open. If you succeed, we both profit, and if not you won't get into too much trouble if you're heard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_7">
	<text>Interesting, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog2_phrase_8">
	<text>I have a hint where the key may be; look more closely at the safe.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_seif_dialog_phrase_1">
	<text>Godfather, it looks like some of our guys can't be trusted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_seif_dialog_phrase_2">
	<text>Oh, really?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_seif_dialog_phrase_3">
	<text>Six was hiding this right under your nose: (show him the "Poacher's Hand" artifact)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_seif_dialog_phrase_4">
	<text>Well now... alright, give me that. And I'll go deal with Six.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_seif_dialog_phrase_5">
	<text>Hey, plowman, and the money will not fall off?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_seif_dialog_phrase_6">
	<text>Like from a bush:</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>I cracked open the safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>Oh? What was inside?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Nothing much, some canned meat and vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_4">
	<text>Check it out: (show him the "Poacher's Hand" artifact)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_5">
	<text>Woah! I knew there was something valuable in there!</text>
	<!--<text>Пи.дишь, с.ка! Я точно помню, внутри чё-то светилось сквозь щёлочку, как будто брюлик там был. Не гони, не по-пацански это!</text>-->
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_6">
	<text>Not so fast. I think I'll hold onto it, and if you have a problem with that, I'll tell the boss that you wanted to steal swag from under his nose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_7">
	<text>You cheat! Fuck you, I won't forget this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_8">
	<text>Bullshit! I remember something was glowing in there. I'll cut you a deal: I give you three normal artifacts, and you give me the one that was in the safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_9">
	<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_shesterka_dialog3_phrase_10">
	<text>No deal.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_1">
	<text>Boss, we've got trouble!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_2">
	<text>Who? What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_3">
	<text>I saw Raven, or someone who introduced himself as him. He says he wants to talk to you. He got two of our boys!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_4">
	<text>That's bullshit! I saw him die myself. Someone is dressed up as him and wants to take his old position. Fuck this, I'm going out there. Cocky, cover my ass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_5">
	<text>That's bullshit! I saw him die myself. Someone is dressed up as him and wants to take his old position. Fuck this, I'm going out there. Greyhound, cover my ass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_6">
	<text>That's bullshit! I saw him die myself. Someone is dressed up as him and wants to take his old position. Fuck this, I'm going out there. Shiv, cover my ass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog8_phrase_7">
	<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog9_phrase_1">
	<text>What now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog9_phrase_2">
	<text>I'll go first. I'll go up to them and take a look around, find out what's going on and try to put things right. You will come with me. If anything strange happens, we jump off the bridge and lay low. Our guys will have us covered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog9_phrase_3">
	<text>Wouldn't it be too dangerous to send you alone? They've got snipers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog9_phrase_4">
	<text>Nah, everyone knows my face. I am the authority figure, this is some limp dick wearing a costume. As soon as I raise my voice, he'll squeal and give himself away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog9_phrase_5">
	<text>I'll follow you.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_1">
	<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_2">
	<text>I need to talk to you. Did you see how Kulgavy was found guilty of treason?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_3">
	<text>I have no idea what's going on. Maybe you can clarify the situation?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_4">
	<text>You see, our Kulgavy was very scared of Raven. Firstly, he was scared because he saw it was in fact Raven, and not some impostor. Secondly, because he killed the Raven a year ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_5">
	<text>I didn't know that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_6">
	<text>I witnessed the murder. It was about dominance over the gang and big bucks. Kulgavy did not have the same authority as Raven, and he wanted to change that. He lured Raven into a meeting, murdered him, and hid the body. I know because I was Raven's bodyguard. I failed to protect him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_7">
	<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_8">
	<text>Kulgavy buried Raven, but he was still alive. He must not have known, or he just assumed Raven would expire soon enough. I dug Raven out of that grave, and before he died he told me a secret: that he had found a special artifact called Simulacrum.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_9">
	<text>What the hell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_10">
	<text>This artifact lets you briefly take on the appearance of the last person to touch it. Raven told me about it before he died. So I used it to avenge Raven. You following?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_11">
	<text>So Raven wasn't on the bridge; it was you, disguised?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_12">
	<text>That's right. Once he saw Raven, he lost his shit. Gave himself away. Showed weakness. That's when everyone saw it was time for a new beginning.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_13">
	<text>Why didn't you just kill him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_14">
	<text>That's not an option. I need to get respect from my brothers, and to do that, I need to humiliate Kulgavy first, to tell everyone that he killed Raven. Such guys will never forgive him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_15">
	<text>What do you want from me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_16">
	<text>Talk to those still loyal to Kulgavy. Tell them Raven is back, as if he actually survived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_17">
	<text>What about the Klondike?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_18">
	<text>If I take charge of this gang, then we will continue to search for it together - all the necessary information is already in our hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_19">
	<text>Well, I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_20">
	<text>I'm not leaving my boss to die, unlike you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_21">
	<text>Just think about it! Once you find the key, Kulgavy will dispose of you just like he did Raven. While you're not an immediate threat to his rule, your reputation will be too damn good. Everyone will see just how capable you are. You're still new, you never knew him or any of the other top brass before. You'll never truly be considered one of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_22">
	<text>Fuck you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_23">
	<text>Go straight to Terminator back at Kulgavy's crib. Kill the bodyguard if need be. Terminator was like a brother to Raven, he'll come...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_24">
	<text>They're not gonna believe me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_25">
	<text>You're just gonna have to do what I told you to do! I will do the rest myself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_farm_assistant_dialog9_phrase_26">
	<text>Okay, I'll take my chances.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_1">
	<text>Wake up! Shit is going down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_2">
	<text>What the... hiccups! What the fuck is this?! Where am I? Where is Raven?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_3">
	<text>Don't worry, goddamn it, Raven's been in the grave for a long time. You know that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_4">
	<text>I saw him with my own eyes!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_5">
	<text>It was a ruse, a plot against you. Take a look at Diplomat's PDA: (show Diplomat's PDA)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_6">
	<text>Well, fuck... let's finish this. What a whore! I had a hunch that it was a setup, and it was! I'll fucking kill that asshole slowly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_7">
	<text>He's gone now. By the way, I found this rat's stash and guess what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_8">
	<text>Come on, man, isn't that what I think it is? The key?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_9">
	<text>That's right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_10">
	<text>Holy shit, Cocky. Now we'll heal, now our gang will grow. I'll buy a summer house on the Canaries, a private yacht, the whole fucking thing. By the way, I forgot to tell you my boys found the exact place where the fanatics keep their shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_11">
	<text>Holy shit, Greyhound. Now we'll heal, now our gang will grow. I'll buy a summer house on the Canaries, a private yacht, the whole fucking thing. By the way, I forgot to tell you my boys found the exact place where the fanatics keep their shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_12">
	<text>Holy shit, Shiv. Now we'll heal, now our gang will grow. I'll buy a summer house on the Canaries, a private yacht, the whole fucking thing. By the way, I forgot to tell you my boys found the exact place where the fanatics keep their shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_13">
	<text>How far?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_14">
	<text>You're gonna have to really scratch your hooves on the road. It's not in the Dark Valley, you can't even get there by car. It's a place called Dead City, ever heard of it? The place is said to be cursed, and hardly anyone even knows how to actually get there. But we have that information. I'll take my best guys with me, we're gonna need them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog10_phrase_15">
	<text>I'll meet you there.</text>
	</string>

	
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Fuck knows, he's not right in the head. He just sits and swears quietly now. What happened at the meeting?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>Let's go out on the porch and talk. Call the gang.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_1">
	<text>I hear you're from Raven's old gang.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_2">
	<text>I was... why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_3">
	<text>What ever happened to Raven?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_4">
	<text>What's the big deal, I don't get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_5">
	<text>Your Godfather is back. He wants you back at his side, and the rest of Kulgavy's brothers too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_6">
	<text>What the fuck are you talking about? He was wasted a year ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_7">
	<text>It was Raven at the meeting. Kulgavy went there and shit his pants once he saw who it was.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_8">
	<text>Do you take me for a sucker? I don't believe in the Dead Brigade!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_9">
	<text>Kulgavy tried to kill Raven and take over, but Raven survived and recovered. Now he's is back in business, and Kulgavy has to answer for his crime.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_10">
	<text>You're full of shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog2_phrase_11">
	<text>He'll explain it to you himself.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>Everything okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>Oh yeah. That scum paid the price for Raven's death.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Now what? How are you gonna get out of this? The disguise doesn't last long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_4">
	<text>I'll make sure to name Diplomat as my #2. That'll make him a sort of deputy, people will obey him, so he'll take over afterwards. I'll give you a lot of money, just let me get to the Klondike...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_5">
	<text>Yeah, about that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_6">
	<text>Back at Radar, after you left, I lingered a little longer and got the same "key." I had to make a big deal out of it and even pretend to be dead, he-heh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_7">
	<text>It's not the first time you've played a dead man. What's next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_8">
	<text>We've got the key, but fuck knows where the lock is. Our dear departed Kulgavy knew...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_9">
	<text>Maybe we shouldn't have killed him right away, then we could've found out where the Klondike is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_10">
	<text>No shit. Too fucking late for that though. Either way, leaving him alive would've been too much of a risk. I have a plan anyway: one of Kulgavy's guys was able to locate more info about the Klondike or the expedition. He's called Troll.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_11">
	<text>That's a familiar name.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_12">
	<text>You know him? Well, you have to find him and ask him about the Klondike. If he doesn't tell, make him tell at any cost. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_13">
	<text>Yeah, give me his coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_14">
	<text>Yeah, give me his coordinates. Can someone give me a ride?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog3_phrase_15">
	<text>I'm sick of running around, let me have a smoke.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_1">
	<text>Just the man I was looking for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_2">
	<text>Heh! I know why you came here. You want a hint about the Klondike, right? Heh-heh! You and Raven are quick witted. Or is it not Raven? Who's in charge now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_3">
	<text>How did you find out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_4">
	<text>I sniff around, like an informant. It's my calling to know shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_5">
	<text>So you know for sure about the Klondike's whereabouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_6">
	<text>I'll be honest: I value my skin above all else. You're with Raven (or whoever it really is), following his orders. How do I know you won't kill me once I give you the info?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_7">
	<text>I'm not like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_8">
	<text>I don't believe you, Cocky. I don't believe you! Okay, let's make things nice and simple. I want to live, and you want the Klondike. I'll tell you all about it, but only if you hand me all of your guns. Only then will I tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_9">
	<text>I don't believe you, Greyhound. I don't believe you! Okay, let's make things nice and simple. I want to live, and you want the Klondike. I'll tell you all about it, but only if you hand me all of your guns. Only then will I tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_10">
	<text>I don't believe you, Shiv. I don't believe you! Okay, let's make things nice and simple. I want to live, and you want the Klondike. I'll tell you all about it, but only if you hand me all of your guns. Only then will I tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_11">
	<text>Sounds like it'd be easier to waste you and take the info from your corpse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_12">
	<text>The info is only in my head, dumbass! Are you some kind of Controller now? Heh-heh! You give me all of your weapons, then I take off and in 5 minutes I'll send the info to your PDA. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_13">
	<text>%c[255,255,118,118]Do you think I'm a fucking idiot? Spill the beans or my knife will spill your guts.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulgband_informer_dialog1_phrase_14">
	<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Fine, but you better hold up your end of the bargain or else I'll catch you. (Give up all of your weapons)%c[default]</text>
	</string>

	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_1">
	<text>I'm back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_2">
	<text>Cocky! You better have good news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_3">
	<text>Greyhound! You better have good news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_4">
	<text>Shiv! You better have good news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_5">
	<text>The informant had to be gutted, but I have the Klondike info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_6">
	<text>I know where the Klondike is now. And the informant went off into the sunset.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_7">
	<text>Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck! It's a pity that Troll had to be dealt with, but the main thing is that we're one step closer to the Klondike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_8">
	<text>Heh-heh, gone, you say? We'll have to lure him back into our brigade, he's useful. Well, the main thing is we're only one step away from the Klondike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_9">
	<text>It seems to me that the fanatics are guarding it ruthlessly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog4_phrase_10">
	<text>Yeah, it's gonna take a while... I'll take the whole gang with me, we don't have shit to do here. Meet me at the spot you showed me. Me with the key, you with the info. Then we'll proceed.</text>
	</string>

	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog5_phrase_1">
	<text>Here I am. How's it going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog5_phrase_2">
	<text>It's a shitty place, but we won't be here long. Lead the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog5_phrase_3">
	<text>It's right here: (point out the place on the map)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog5_phrase_4">
	<text>Don't make too much noise, we don't need witnesses. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog5_phrase_5">
	<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog5_phrase_6">
	<text>Wait, let me have a smoke.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog11_phrase_1">
	<text>Everything okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog11_phrase_2">
	<text>This is a bad place... all sorts of evil spirits are waddling around in crowds... Do you have the "key" in front of you? We're ready to move on, the boys are waiting. Lead the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog11_phrase_3">
	<text>Then let's go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog11_phrase_4">
	<text>Wait, let me have a smoke.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog12_phrase_1">
	<text>How are we doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog12_phrase_2">
	<text>Looks like it's over. No more sneaking in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog12_phrase_3">
	<text>Right.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_1">
	<text>So, are we in the right place or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_2">
	<text>This should be it, this pit according to this. How clever, this doesn't look like a stash at all. Nobody would think anything of it. Well, if you have the key, go use it. My boys will cover.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_3">
	<text>So what's the next step?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_4">
	<text>You go down there, use the key, and grab everything you see. Every fucking thing. Bring it to me, and we'll divide it amongst ourselves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_5">
	<text>Of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_6">
	<text>And one more thing. Let me make this clear: don't you dare try to hide anything or run away with shit. You'd never get away. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_7">
	<text>You wound me, Kulgavy. I'm no rat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_8">
	<text>It had to be said, you understand. Alright, move it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog13_phrase_9">
	<text>Alright, I'll be quick.</text>
	</string>
	
		
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog14_phrase_1">
	<text>Check this out, Godfather! What jewels were lying there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog14_phrase_2">
	<text>Give it here! At last! Heh-heh... now we'll share the loot... STOP. Do you hear that? The fucking cops are here! Duty!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_dialog14_phrase_3">
	<text>Where?!</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="cit_kulgband_glavar_loose_dialog_phrase_1">
	<text>What the fuck? I don't get it. Setup?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_kulgband_glavar_loose_dialog_phrase_2">
	<text>Goddamn it. Well, you do what you want. I'm out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_kulgband_glavar_loose_dialog_phrase_3">
	<text>Where to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_kulgband_glavar_loose_dialog_phrase_4">
	<text>I'm gonna go to a local bar first, get drunk. Then I'll decide where to start a new gang.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_1">
	<text>This is the pit. What do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_2">
	<text>Hell if I know. You tell me, Cocky: do you see a cache full of riches here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_3">
	<text>Hell if I know. You tell me, Greyhound: do you see a cache full of riches here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_4">
	<text>Hell if I know. You tell me, Shiv: do you see a cache full of riches here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_5">
	<text>They're stashed within the space anomaly, you bastards. This looks like the place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_6">
	<text>Well, I've got the "key" so let's go try to crack this open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_7">
	<text>Okay, and this is... What else did I want to say...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_8">
	<text>Spit it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_9">
	<text>Uh, good luck to you, you bastard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_10">
	<text>Don't worry, it's gonna be all right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog6_phrase_11">
	<text>Come on, let's do it.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_1">
	<text>Raven, are we in heaven or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_2">
	<text>Holy shit! Look at all of this. Each one is unique. Who knows how much they're worth! We have to figure out how to distribute it. Let's get everything back home, take a brief rest, and then we'll figure it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_3">
	<text>Well, we still have to get out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_4">
	<text>Man, after all we've been through, we deserve no less. Let's get out and then cash out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_5">
	<text>Man, after all we've been through, we deserve no less. Let's get out and then cash out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_6">
	<text>Man, after all we've been through, we deserve no less. Let's get out and then cash out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_bridge_kulgband_man1_dialog7_phrase_7">
	<text>Let's go!</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_1">
	<text>Alright, so how do we share the loot?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_2">
	<text>It's a pity about Raven. He escaped death once, but couldn't a second time. Wait, what is that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_3">
	<text>Hey, what the hell?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_4">
	<text>It's not fucking Raven... It's not his face, I swear!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_5">
	<text>Are you hungover or something? Wipe your eyes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_6">
	<!--<text>Да не, точняк не он! Смотри, как-будто маска с фэйса у него сходит: было как у Ворона, а стало как у... Решалы? Кинул, с.ка? И ты с ним в сговоре был? На.бать братву хотели?!</text>-->
	<text>No, he's not! Look, it's like he's got a mask that looks like Raven! It was like Raven, but it wasn't. It was... Diplomat? What the hell is going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_telohr_2_dialog3_phrase_7">
	<text>Don't worry, bro, let me tell you what...</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

