<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
    <string id="talk_about_psy_emission">
		<text>Well, there are two most known sources of emission: the ill famous Brain Scorcher and the "Rostok" plant territory.
		That is the reason for so many zombies being encountered there.
		It is rumoured that there's one more powerful emitter at the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant and it is the one to cause psi-surges. But nobody has been there, so it's up to you to decide, whether to believe it or not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zombied_stalker_1">
		<text>The main difference lies in the behavioral patterns: when undisturbed by anything, zombies keep staggering aimlessly hither and thither. They can be recognized from a distance by typical wobbly gait and inarticulate muttering. 
They never apply any tactical action in combat so as to cover or to avoid gunfire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_snork_1">
		<text>They have quickly gained animal instincts in exhange for the intellect. These instincts help them survive in the Zone. Mutation which followed the Blowout, not only enabled these animals to survive, but granted them new abilities to fit the dangerous environment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_snork_2">
		<text>The abilities I mean are as follows: faster regeneration, which is common for all the Zone establishings, predation and, undoubtedly, sharp scotopic vision.
Initially being stronger than upper limbs, their hind legs have got ankle joints with unique flexibility. The snorks' anatomical features make them move slowly on all fours most of the time, 
but allow them to perform long impetuous jumps and deliver forceful blows with their lower extremities.</text> 
  	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_snork_3">
		<text>Snorks' favourite places for habitation are mostly radiated areas in certain proximity of the so called "Brain Scorcher". In these areas snorks have additional advantages in hunting large prey and, unfortunately, humans.
Snorks may also be encountered in artificial tunnels and caves, in basements and ruins. \nTheir population goes up towards the center of the Zone, and they are quite rare in the periphery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_snork_4">
		<text>Not by Chernobyl dogs, that's for sure. Though both of them are animals, snorks have still got humanlike alpha activity of the brain action currents, which is different from that of Chernobyl dogs. 
		By controllers... That is a difficult question to answer. There are no places in the periphery of the Zone to be inhabited by both kinds, so we have never had a chance to observe a snork influenced by a controller. 
		Closer to the center, for example - in Pripyat, the population density of mutants increases greatly and this possibility is more likely. The main question is if a snork's brain has enough of the "humanlike basis" left for a controller to establish a psi-connection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_snork_5">
		<text>There are plenty of mysteries about snorks. Why have all of them got gas masks, military boots and holsters? Why do all of the animal units have same injuries of spinal column? Why are they all so much alike in general?! They don't breed - no female individuals exist, so how have they not been exterminated by other mutants up until now? 
How many they were, those dead disaster fighters, which became starting material for snorks? And the main thing! Has anybody ever seen a snork's body with a week's prescription of death coming? At least the bones? Or any body fragments? There are no answers yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_snork_6">
		<text>I suppose that the likeness of all snorks comes from their origin - one and the same starting material for all of them. Where this material came from is another thing. But there is no doubt that they descend from humans. 
		There must be a reason for these creatures' emergence, no matter if they are clones or duplicates. And it will be impossible to ever exterminate them until we locate and destroy the mysterious source of there reproduction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_chimera_1">
		<text>The origin of chimeras is unknown. As a matter of fact, this is true for most other monsters as well... Chimeras are remarkably viable and malicious. Once one of them has clutched at you, it will never let you go. Either the prey dies, or the hunter. And the contact pressure of the mutant's maxilla is comparable to that of an industrial press...
		 Chimera preys everything indiscriminately, even when not hungry. When hungry, the predator becomes even more dangerous and may even attack other of the kind and it doesn't disdain for carrion. The preferable food of a chimera are mutated boars and, unfortunately, humans... There's something feline about this creature, so impetuous and silent.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_chimera_2">
		<text>Chimera's every sweeping move is followed by short-time period of utmost immobility, during which the predator vanishes into the scenery, leaving the prey perplexed, either it was a hallucination, or the wind swayed some bushes... 
		If you don't know exactly what you are looking for, there is a high chance to spot the animal squatting on the ground just a blink before the fatal jump.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_chimera_3">
		<text>You see, this creature's behavior is utterly unpredictable. It can be neither understood or explained. I have tried researching chimeras at one time. But it was very soon that I realized that nothing would come out of it. Our attempts to make contact with the monster were unsuccessful. Though it has two heads, they seem to have a central mind... And there was a feeling that this mind is somewhere far... 
		Every chimera has got its own unique qualities. That makes any most careful observation of one individual absolutely useless in understanding another one. Besides, the chimeras flatly refuse any contact. 
		I suppose it to be the only Zone's establishment endowed with intellect, with which it is impossible to establish any communication, even at primitive level.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_chimera_4">
		<text>With no difference from ordinary chimera in its outer appearance, electrochimera is capable of creating volatile static charge of electricity, which, upon discharge, inflicts damage within 2-5 meter radius. Due to the soil in the Zone being saturated with anomalous energy, the radius of discharge may go up to 15-20 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_chimera_5">
		<text>Loss of the discharge power is greater in vertical direction than in horizontal one. So, relatively safe values are reached at above 3-4 meters. Naturally, this process is greatly influenced by precipitation, especially thunderstorm. \nFamiliarity with this feature helped some hunters to survive an encounter with electrochimera. 
		They managed to shoot down the monster from high rocks, buildings or alike by shooting about two full magazines (!) of armour piercing bullets at the creature's heads.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_chimera_6">
		<text>It is significant that sometimes the so called "Kolobok" artifacts are found in the gastrointestinal tract of chimeras. 
		I venture to give utterance to my theory that swallowing of these artifacts makes ordinary chimeras become electrochimeras. 
\nIt has turned out to be impossible to study the inner organs of a chimera in a laboratory so as to measure the exact properties of 
the electromagnetic fields the creature is able to generate due to one simple fact. And this fact is that nobody ever succeeded in 
capturing a chimera alive and all those specimen that finally were delivered to us turned out to be in very poor condition. Bluntly 
speaking, they resembled sieves due to obvious reasons.</text>
	</string>
<string id="talk_about_krovosos_1">
<text>Although everybody has heard about bloodsuckers, there are only few lucky ones to have survived an encounter with that monster. 
As for me, I have seen them only on some photos. According to the witnesses, bloodsuckers are tall humanoid stooping creatures with many 
tentacles around their mouth. Apparently, these mutants prefer solitude, though sometimes they have been spotted in groups of up to 5 units. 
Their favourite areas of dwelling are abandoned places like catacombs, tunnels, damp basements, etc. They may be encountered in the vicinity 
of the Agroprom Research Institute and the tunnels beneath it, in the Dark Valley and Wild Territory and, of course, in the ill famous village by the 
Army Warehouses. Stalkers even call it no other name than "the Bloodsuckers' village". \nBloodsuckers are famous for their distinguishing character - 
the ability to become almost invisible. They mostly use it for hunting and camouflage, as they try to approach the prey undetected. When already 
close enough to the victim, the monster strikes it with his strong sharp-clawed paw. In most cases the very first blow is fatal.</text>
</string>
<string id="talk_about_krovosos_2">
<text>Upon running into a bloodsucker, one must be sure to be able to discriminate 
between the two states of the mutant's behavior. The first and the most probable state is the 
attack. In this case it is very important to determine the sector of the danger and be 
ready to open destruction fire. By the way, the best effect may be achieved by firing right 
between the monster's eyes, which give the creature's position out even in the invisible state. 
It is also very important not to give way to panic, not to run away, as the bloodsucker will 
surely run the victim down. \nThe second state is the quiescent mode, which actually means that 
the mutant is unaware of your presence. The most reasonable act will be to retreat, paying 
attention to retracing your path. Of course, if you are confident of your powers, then it is 
advisable to secure yourself and others against the monster by shooting it down with an accurate 
shot in the head by means of some powerful weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="talk_about_krovosos_3">
<text>Well, the undamaged tentacles of a bloodsucker are a very interesting object of research, 
and its rarity ensures a stable price. Most probably they are mutated mouth organs - tongue, 
cheeks and lower jaw. By means of these tentacles the bloodsucker feeds on its victim's blood, 
leaving only a desiccated mummy-like corpse... In conclusion, it should be mentioned that one 
shouldn't consider himself dead upon encountering a bloodsucker. Knowledge of its strong and weak 
points greatly increases the chance to take the monster over.</text>
</string>
<string id="talk_about_plaque_rat_1">
<text>"Plague" rats are mutated test animals which escaped from vivariums. That is why they are mostly encountered in the X-18 laboratory complex. As a result of unknown laboratory tests, their brain tissues have been changed so as to be used as a substrate for cultivation of mutant flies.</text>
</string>
<string id="talk_about_plaque_rat_2">
<text>Flies are carriers of a gene, which causes intense mutation of cerebrum and thus prepares favourable conditions for larvae. The changes went so far, that they lead to irreversible damage to the brain and, finally, to pseudodeath. 
It was at that laboratory, that flies' influence was tested on humans also, but the experiment was not completed. The human brain rejected the flies' eggs if not being treated in a certain way. 
As for now, those mutated flies may be observed among some zombies... The flies are able to inflict numerous tiny wounds which cause ample bleeding and may easily become infected. The term "plague rat" came from the name of the project "Plague of 21st Century".</text>
</string>
<!--Kruglov i Semenov rasskazyvayut o zone-->
<string id="talk_about_horrortime_1">
<text>Ok, listen. Regarding the Zone, it is appropriate to say that periods of relative stability are followed by short phases of instability - Blowouts. 
Phases of instability are notable for swaps of anomalies, emergence of artifacts and strong changes in the monsters' activity. 
Sometimes these phases are followed by changes in global psionic fields, resulting in local emissions - the so called "Psi-Surges", also known as "Horror Time". 
During these psi-surges a number of unstable short-living phantasms and floating anomalies may be observed. Psi-surges cause stalkers to suffer vertigo, severe headache and hallucinations. 
The most of the "Horror Time" generated establishments disappear without trace as soon as the Psi-Surge is over.</text>
</string>
<string id="talk_about_horrortime_2">
<text>That's right. The floating anomalies are formed when the old anomalies are replaced with new ones. That means that floating anomalies are intermediate phase between two stable allocations of the ordinary anomalies. 
That is why the floating anomalies are unstable as well and mostly disappear by the end of Psi-Surges.</text>
</string>

<string id="talk_about_horrortime_3">
<text>Phantoms are a result of psi-fields' interference with the human useful consciousness. It has been determined that the quantity, form and type of phantoms depend on the psychic state of every specific individual. 
Most of the phantoms may be observed by most people, but few of them may be seen by one person only. Obviously, such phantoms are establishments of his own consciousness.</text>
</string>

<!--Dialogi s odinochkami na Svalke-->
<string id="stalker_garbage_1">
<text>The Zone is more habit-forming than any drug! Stay in th anteroom (I mean Cordon) for a week and that's it! Somethings starts gnawing you, forcing you to walk again on the verge of death... 
You are very lucky if there turns up some client by that time, so that you don't raid into the Zone in vain just because you cannot live any more without it, but for a paid job to make profit from. 
It is mostly due to profit that people come here. The artifacts used to bring in a big revenue. It wasn't at all easy money, but... It was ok. 
People mature here, turn from hikers into stalkers. Some of them even stop thinking about profit only and start enjoying the dangers and mysteries of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_garbage_2">
<text>Many are still earning money by searching for artifacts and selling them. Though they became much cheaper than before...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_garbage_3">
<text>At first, the scientists kept bombarding stalkers with orders, private collectors bribed the military and kept hanging about all anterooms of the Zone, buying everything stalkers brought to them. 
It got much more difficult for us now. Of course, the artifacts keep appearing after every blowout, but many of them are no longer worth the risk you experience to get them. 
The scientists and collectors have got plenty of them by now, so the laws of supply and demand had their effect. Such artifacts as "Wrenched", "Jellyfish" and the like would not be bought almost at all, so many experienced stalkers even stopped picking them up. 
A joy for rookies! Better for them to enjoy those low-cost artifacts than to try raiding deep into the Zone. A rookie deep in the Zone is a dead man. Proved by the Zone itself.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_garbage_4">
<text>Of course I do. "Kolobok", "Battery" and other middlings are still worth quite a lot, so nobody ever scruples to pick them up. And it would be a very good luck to find a "Soul"! The scientists are still begging for this artifact, but few stalkers were lucky enough to find at least two "Souls"... 
And only a complete fool would agree to sell the only one he had - it's advantages are really remarkable. Probably it is only the "Red Star" transmute that has got alike properties. Transmutes are very expensive artificial artifacts that one may order at professor Sakharov's laboratory at Yantar. But one has to get there first...</text>
</string>
</string_table>
