<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="military_trader_who">
		<text>Military? What are you doing in stalker camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_17">
		<text>It's gonna be a good day. Here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_16">
		<text>Great, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_15">
		<text>Well, come visit me, I have it all right here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_14">
		<text>Nope, I don't have such money. See you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_13">
		<text>I'll take control one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_12">
		<text>I'll take both.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_11">
		<text>Huh, it's tough times now, dear. Seriously - take it both for thirty five grands or control module alone for twenty five. How about that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_10">
		<text>Why so young pal is so greedy, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_9">
		<text>Three joints.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_8">
		<text>Of course. How much?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_7">
		<text>No need to get it, I have it. Wait... Yes, here it is. Also I have robotic aiming module as an upgrade. Do you want it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_6">
		<text>Well, I need control module for "Warder" APC. Can you get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_5">
		<text>Talk to me, I can get plenty of stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_4">
		<text>No, I don't need a shooter for now, but another thing, a little bit trickier..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2_1">
		<text>What, you want some rare shooter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_2_2">
		<text>Listen, Zadov, I have a business with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_0">
		<text>Oh, another customer! Come here, don't be so shy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_about">
		<text>You, quiet here, sergeants are nervous. Keep your gun in your pants. We're not military anymore, we're on our own for last couple of months. Officially we're M.I.A. Serving in Institute is a suicide, man. When it became impossible I made a deal with sergeants and we "desappeared". But there's still a bond with friends, we trades artifacts for ammo, meds and other equipment. Just need some more money to leave Zone. However, when somebody alarmed Institute, we got a jackpot. Military in Institute received enormous amount of excellent equipment and now we sell it, inexpensively. So don't be shy, check it and we can make a deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_trader_buy">
		<text>Well, show me your stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_0">
		<text>Sup, Bartender, how you got here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_1">
		<text>I'm not him, I'm his brother. We have a deal with the bandits: loot for equipment and food. Also I sell the junk that they bring to me. Got it? So what's your business? Are we trading or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit_trader_2">
		<text>Of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_trader_lc_info_0">
		<text>Listen, do you know how to get to Wild Territories from here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_trader_lc_info_1">
		<text>Best way is through City-32, check this coords. That's the way for wise guys, like you and me. Beware of snipers in the ctiy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_trader_0">
		<text>Hi, merc!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_trader_1">
		<text>You don't croak either, goner. Need for some expensive superior equipment? Looking for something special?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="merc_trader_2">
		<text>Yeah, allright!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_lc_info_0">
		<text>You're here a long time, as I see. Maybe you know some short paths from Red Forest to the Southern Zone? There are lots of troubles when travelling through the Warehouses...</text></string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_lc_info_1">
		<text>Yes, I know. My clients should stay safe, huh? There are two paths to the Southern Zone: one to Dark Valley, other to Yantar. There are dangerous places over there so follow paths carefully! Say hello to Sidor, if you see him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_0">
		<text>You must be "Monolith" supplier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_1">
		<text>You're almost right, stalker. Don't ask me about my business here. Just remember - "Monolith" isn't just a bunch of fanatics like they appear. They have... patrons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_2">
		<text>And what about the emission? This is Red Forest nearby!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_3">
		<text>I have special helmet from "friends" from outside. Don't even try to get it - it has self-destruction system, you'll kill us both. Listen, my employer asked me to warn you about Reactor hall. He'll contact to you by himself maybe but for now the message for you is "Not all the things are what they seem..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monlit_trader_4">
		<text>Well, I'm tired of all of this!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

