<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>

<!--Quest murder Stranger-->
<string_table>
<string id="trader_relation_bandit_1">
<text>Something incomprehensible has happened to me lately. Someone tried to run over me. I'm not in a hurry to start a fight. Can you help me?</text>  
</string>

<string id="trader_relation_bandit_2">
<text>Yes, some of the guys are not happy with you. Some of the lads have hinted about getting rid of you. But I can calm them down. Fork out 10,000 and all will be settled.</text>  
</string>

<string id="trader_relation_bandit_3">
<text>Funny you should mention that. Some of the guys want to tar and feather you. All this can be sorted out, but you'll have to pay 30,000.</text>  
</string>

<string id="trader_relation_bandit_4">
<text>Many stalkers in the Zone have been talking about you! The lads are extremely dissatisfied with you. To repair this serious damage to your reputation is expensive. Pay 50,000.</text>  
</string>

<string id="trader_relation_bandit_5">
<text>Okay. Take the money.</text>  
</string>

<string id="trader_relation_bandit_6">
<text>That's a lot to pay for respect.</text>  
</string>

<string id="trader_relation_bandit_7">
<text>Agreed. Well the loot triumphs over evil. Take the money.</text>  
</string>

<string id="kkill_fraer_done_0">
<text>I've killed the Stranger.</text>  
</string>

<string id="kill_fraer_0">
<text>What jobs do you have?</text>  
</string>

<string id="kill_fraer_1">
<text>I have something exactly for you. Some shitass has turned up and is bothering me a lot. He is throwing his weight around and is trying to undermine my business by humiliating me in front of the lads. But all this is not here to stay - waste the turd and you'll get a very good bandit cloak. Borov is a man of his word.</text>  
</string>

<string id="kill_fraer_2">
<text>Does this guy have a name?</text>  
</string>

<string id="kill_fraer_3">
<text>He's smart. They just call him Stranger. It's necessary to make him go away quietly, without messing up.</text>  
</string>

<string id="kill_fraer_4">
<text>I won't cock up the job and shame you.</text>  
</string>

<string id="kill_fraer_5">
<text>Excuse me. But I won't cringe if he dies.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_0">
<text>Well hello there.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_1">
<text>What do you want?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_2">
<text>I'm tired of being a Loner. I want to join your clan.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_3">
<text>Good. Invest 10,000 roubles to our common fund, and you can join us.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_4">
<text>Oh, nothing, just dropped by.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_5">
<text>I don't have the money now. I'll come back later.</text>
</string>

<string id="borov_meet_again_6">
<text>No worries. Take the money.</text>  
</string>

<string id="chto_namutil_0">
<text>What's your problem with the Duty guys?</text>  
</string>

<string id="chto_namutil_1">
<text>Brother, help me. Finish off this asshole Bullet for me! The brotherhood will be very grateful to you. If you kill this bastard, I'll tell you where the hill with a Duty chief Skull's cache is located. Do him in, and I cross my heart - I will wait for you here!</text>  
</string>

<string id="chto_namutil_2">
<text>For that reward, of course I will help. Just make sure you're here when I'm back!</text>  
</string>

<string id="chto_namutil_3">
<text>Fuck you...</text>  
</string>

<string id="chto_namutil_4">
<text>Well simpleton, blah, you better pray you never get caught by my brothers.</text>  
</string>

<string id="chto_namutil_5">
<text>You'd better not waste time - there are some blind dogs nearby, you know... </text>  
</string>

<!--The prisoner thug near the Duty entry-->
<string id="cherep_treasure_0">
<text>I killed your enemy. Now, what were you saying about Skull's hiding place?</text>
</string>

<string id="cherep_treasure_1">
<text>There is a secret place where Skull uses to temporarily hide the loot from his victims. I heard a rumour recently that he had hidden a nice SVD there. Strike me dead if I lie! And maybe you could find something else there.</text>  
</string>

<string id="cherep_treasure_2">
<text>Well, you better be telling the truth.</text>  
</string>

<!--Dialogues with bodyguards Hog-->
<string id="prebandit_0">
<text>Hey, slow down, are you in a hurry?</text>  
</string>

<string id="prebandit_1">
<text>Yes I am, I'm going to see Borov.</text>  
</string>

<string id="prebandit_2">
<text>Why? What do you want from him?</text>  
</string>

<string id="prebandit_3">
<text>There's something to natter about.</text>  
</string>

<!--Entry into Bandits through Hog-->
<string id="borov_ask_document_0">
<text>What is it you wanted to ask?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_1">
<text>Well? Have you brought the document?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_2">
<text>Not yet.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_3">
<text>Too bad. I won't wait long. Do you understand?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_4">
<text>Yes, I think so.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_5">
<text>I brought it, here you go.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_6">
<text>Not bad Marked One! Well, I keep my word. You got the job done without mistakes - here's the key to the lab. Listen Marked One, don't you piss yourself when you go down into the lab? Looks like you are really tough... Maybe you would like to join us?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_7">
<text>Well. Why not?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_20">
<text>Well then, you can consider yourself one of us now. Welcome to the life of thieves.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_21">
<text>Well. You have helped us once, so we won't touch you now. But in the future we better not cross paths.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_22">
<text>I've already been told that you had helped Bullet to die sooner, he-he. You're the man.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_8">
<text>No. Thanks for the invitation, but I prefer being a Loner.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_9">
<text>Well, we're even. You're safe for now, but in future we better not cross paths. Heh-heh-heh.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_10">
<text>See you later.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_ask_document_11">
<text>Not bad Marked One, well, I keep my word. You got the job done without mistakes - you get the key to the lab.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_0">
<text>Be healthy.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_1">
<text>So, it's Marked One himself! I've heard about you. There are rumours about you being pulled out of the death truck alive. By the way, you have a cool nickname "Marked One". And for some reason I was called Borov.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_2">
<text>I was sent by the informant.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_3">
<text>Informant, you say? Hmm ... Well, what do you want?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_4">
<text>Just one thing ...</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_5">
<text>What's the matter? Speak up.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_6">
<text>I'm looking for the key to the door to the X18 lab...</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_7">
<text>And why I should give it to you? Just because you have beautiful eyes?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_8">
<text>I can pay money for it.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_9">
<text>Do you have a lot of money to pay? Do you ... Well ... Hmm. I know who sent you. Barkeep, and we remain neutral with him. Well, we need someone who does not belong to our group and can do one little task for us.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_10">
<text>What kind of task? You need someone killed, I suppose?</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_11">
<text>Why would we want someone killed? We need to steal some documents from Barkeep, but it must be done in such a way that he doesn't suspect us. These documents are kept in his room, guarded by his men. Get the job done quietly, and I'll give you the second key to the laboratory.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_12">
<text>Okay.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_13">
<text>I'm not ready yet.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_14">
<text>I came here on a tip from your man.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_15">
<text>Yes, I know. You rescued him. That's why we haven't touched you. I am listening.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_16">
<text>Do you have a lot of money to pay? Do you ... Well ... Hmm. I know who bestowed the honour on you to descend into this hell, he he. Barkeep. We remain neutral with him, but I need a desperate man, able to execute a non-trivial matter for me.</text>  
</string>

<string id="borov_enter_bandit_17">
<text>Yes, I know. You rescued him. And, importantly, you, at his request, had a hand in the demise of Bullet. So you can join us. Don't be a stranger. What do you say to my proposal?</text>  
</string>

<!--Dead stalker-->
<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_0">
<text>What are you staring at?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_1">
<text>Good Lord! Who or what are you?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_2">
<text>I was a human once ... the scientists tried to make a controller out of me, but something went wrong. They tried to let me die, but that failed too, so now I live in this container.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_3">
<text>Wow!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_4">
<text>...</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_40">
<text>I can't but ask: what's it like? I mean, this existence.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_400">
<text>That depends on the point of view to evaluate. On one hand, I feel no physical pain, I have no need for sleep or food. The experiment made me part of the Zone, granted me access to its knowledge, which in itself can be considered a reward. In addition, I lost the majority of the threads connecting me with the habitual material world. My connection with the conventional body shell... It is nothing more than... uh, a "speaker", bringing my speech  to you in a clear verbal form. Its destruction is unable to cause the death of my mind, so one can consider me immortal.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_401">
<text>Interesting... Could you please tell me more about the knowledge of the Zone?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_402">
<text>Every living thing, coming into the Zone, to some extent, becomes a part of it. And the longer a creature stays in the Zone, the more in harmony it comes with the Zone. As a result, it forms a small part of the Zone's very essence. Of course, the degree of mutual integration and their symbiosis and influence on each depend on many factors which together can be called a "personal preference", or vice versa, "immunity". Another determining factor is the length of interaction. Over time, the thoughts and messages of a being start getting into the Zone, and the being starts catching messages which in essence are the thoughts and messages of other beings in the Zone...\n\n All the above applies more to the creatures that came to the Zone - Zone's mutants initially are more closely related to it.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_403">
<text>This is all very complicated...</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_404">
<text>It's easier to feel than to explain. To facilitate understanding, here's an example: \n \n Lets say a new danger appears in the Zone, for example, an anomaly. If the first dead victim is a blind dog, it will send an information envelope to the Zone containing details of pain and despair coupled with the preceding symptoms that characterize this anomaly - with specific smell, sounds and other feelings. Once the Zone obtains the information envelope, this information is made available to most of the inhabitants associated with it. So, an experienced pseudo-dog, having faced this same anomaly for the first time, will be able to avoid it. \n\nThis introduction of collective wisdom allows organisms to survive among the many dangers of the Zone. As stalkers share information with others through their network, the inhabitants of the Zone, to a greater or lesser extent are united to a similar "network".\n\nThat's how I have become aware of some of the features and secrets of the Zone. Clear?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_405">
<text>More or less. Returning to your existence...</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_406">
<text>That's one side of the coin. The other is... Let me ask you: What is your attitude to immortality?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_407">
<text>Hmm... This is an ambiguous question that cannot be answered in just a few words.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408">
<text>It's possible to dream of immortality, but it's also possible to be afraid of it... From it emanates an inevitable horror... In the course of affairs, I have a request of you. Interested? As a reward, I will share all of my knowledge with you.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_4080">
<text>And what is your request?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_40800">
<text>Actually, there are two parts. First, I ask you to find and bring me some anomalous formations or, what you call, artifacts. After that, you will have to make a series of manipulations with them, and bring me the obtained results. \n\n There are no time limits, so you need not fear that my request will distract you from the other cases.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_40801">
<text>I agree, perhaps. Tell me.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408010">
<text>Thank you! So now you have to find three rare artifacts. Remember, or better write down what I tell you - this will help you in your search. \n\n The first of these artifacts you may have already encountered: stalkers call it "Cobblestone", because that's what it looks like - an unremarkable shapeless gray-brown formation. The artifact always appears only near large metal structures. The most striking telltale sign that the artifact has formed is the presence of a psi-area and strong distortion of radio signals within a radius of 250 metres from the artifact. Don't worry, the "Cobblestone" isn't hazardous, apart from its radioactivity. \n\n Keep that in mind.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408011">
<text>I've marked it down. What's next?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408012">
<text>The second artifact I need is called "Firefly". I find all the details of its origin difficult to define, but I know enough: The "Firefly" appears only in the "Electra" anomaly and only in the rain. If you don't remove the artifact from the anomaly, it will be destroyed once the rain stops. Don't worry, you won't have to go into every "Electra" you encounter: the artifact causes the anomaly to discharge continiously. Also its most significant distinguishing feature is that its presence changes the colour of the anomaly to pale green, to which the artifact owes its name. \n\n Is that clear?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408013">
<text>When raining... Constantly triggers the anomaly... Colour change of the "Electra" to pale green... Marked it down. What about the third artifact?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408014">
<text>The third artifact is the most unusual - you will probably be the first person to discover it, so you can give it a name. Its peculiarity is that it's only visible during the phenomenon that you call a "Surge". It is this abrupt increase in the anomalous energy that leads to its manifestation; the rest of the time it's invisible.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408015">
<text>Sounds like some devil's chameleon... Wait! You mean I'll have to gad about the Zone during a Surge?!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408016">
<text>No, of course not, this would lead to your death. If you are lucky, hopefully this "Chameleon", as you've called it, will appear not far from your shelter. As I mentioned before, there's no time-frame for this mission. Neither there is any other way to obtain the artifact.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408017">
<text>Not a trivial matter... But I'll try to help.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408018">
<text>I'm counting on you! As for the second part - we'll discuss it when you have collected all the artifacts.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_408019">
<text>Ha! We'll see what happens...</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_40802">
<text>No, I cannot yet.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_4081">
<text>Maybe next time.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_phrase_41">
<text>Well, I'll go...</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_0">
<text>Hello again! Glad to have you around. To what do I owe this visit?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_505">
<text>Thank you! Seems like everything got sorted!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_51">
<text>You had some request, didn't you?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_510">
<text>So, I want you to find three rare artifacts. Remember, or better write down what I tell you - this will help you in your search. \n\n The first of these artifacts you may have already encountered: stalkers call it "Cobblestone", because that's what it looks like - an unremarkable shapeless gray-brown formation. The artifact always appears only near large metal structures. The most striking telltale sign that the artifact has formed is the presence of a psi-area and strong distortion of radio signals within a radius of 250 metres from the artifact. Don't worry, the "Cobblestone" isn't hazardous, apart from its radioactivity. \n\n Keep that in mind.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_52">
<text>I think I found everything you had asked for.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_520">
<text>You have no idea, how glad I am to hear that!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_521">
<text>You're welcome.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_53">
<text>I assume there is a second part of the request?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_530">
<text>Yes. Well, it's not a "part" of it, but only the last small touch. Your task is to put all three artifacts into the "Fruit punch" anomaly which is on the first level of the laboratory, and bring back the resulting artifact to me. Just don't try to activate it or put it on your belt - it will lead to your instant death!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_531">
<text>Well, I'll be careful. See you soon!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_54">
<text>I've fulfilled your request. Here's what turned out.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_540">
<text>Thank you friend! Your help was invaluable to me! I can't thank you enough: here's a little something for you.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_541">
<text>And thank you, too. Yet I'm very curious, what was all your task about?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_542">
<text>You remember, we agreed on the ambiguity of the question of immortality? So, immortality is a gift only if one has the ability to part with it. Otherwise it's a punishment akin to the agony of a paralysed person, not being able to put an end to their torment. Such was the other side of my existence. Now that I have the artifact, I am the master of my fate. I can activate it whenever I want.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_543">
<text>Hmm... Well, okay. Glad To have helped you.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_55">
<text>It seems to me that the disorder in the lab has become worse, didn't it?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_550">
<text>Yes, it did. The Baby is getting off the hook. And I really, really beg you to make him stop! I can no longer tolerate his presence! Help me! Please!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_551">
<text>You're mighty fed up... What 'Baby'?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_552">
<text>Baby giant. After the death of its parent the baby huddled somewhere for a while, but then hunger drove him out of hiding. Now the trouble began! The Baby began to eat everything, from rats to the remainder of the laboratory equipment. You can't imagine the bedlam he's caused. Only the Zone knows how many artifacts he's swallowed that had caught his eye! Since then, he suffers, and does not give me any rest. He goes into hiding, then again the hysteria begins... \n\n I beg you, please help me!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_553a">
<text>I'll help, why not. It might also help to diversify the menu at the Bar...</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_554a">
<text>The menu?.. I doubt that. You see, the Baby has become a little tank by now. As you know, pseudo-giants themselves are tough, and the artifacts he has gorged provide him with additional protection.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_553b">
<text>Not this time, sorry. I don't have that much ammo.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_554b">
<text>You won't have waste your ammunition - because in this case, it would be useless. You see, the Baby has become a little tank by now. As you know, pseudo-giants themselves are tough, and the artifacts he has gorged provide him with additional protection.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_555">
<text>Well, what do you suggest in this case?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_556">
<text>A handmade anomaly - that's what you need. Just bear in mind: you only get one try - the Baby won't fall into the same trap a second time, even if you lay out ten of them. The anomaly must be sufficiently powerful and tenacious to cope with it, something from the "major" group of artifacts. I think the "Goldfish" would be ideal. \n\n What do you say? Will you help me?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_557">
<text>Ok, I'm sold. Where do I find your "Baby"?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_5570">
<text>It roams on the second level of the laboratory. I don't think there's any way you can miss it.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_5571">
<text>Yeah, I got it. I'll tell you later how it went.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_558">
<text>I'll help, but later. I have to get hold of the necessary artifact first.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_5580">
<text>Okay, I'll be looking forward to your return.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_56">
<text>How's your "little giant" problem? Still alive?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_560">
<text>It is, unfortunately. Will you help?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_57">
<text>I solved your "little" problem.</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_570">
<text>Phew, thank you, Marked One! Finally, I can meditate in peace. Well done stalker!</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_5701">
<text>What reward do I get?</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_5702">
<text>Well, aren't the artifacts from the "Baby" enough of a reward? What is this world coming to, that greed is overwhelming it?..</text>  
</string>

<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_2_phrase_5e">
<text>I just happened to be nearby, I'm already leaving.</text>  
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_11">
<text>Bandits! Those sons of bitches were taking me to the old factory. I don't know what they were planning to do with me. I saw them take another guy in there before and I never saw him again. They have another of ours, Sergei. They keep him in the basement of that big unfinished building. Help him, would you? Otherwise they'll... you know...</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_2">
<text>Do you know what they have at the factory?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_21">
<text>I haven't heard much. All I know is that their boss Borov has one key to the underground there. There used to be a lab inside, or something. I did hear that Borov has been eager to get inside, but can't without the second key. Umm... if you're thinking of trying to get inside, think twice before you do. It's full of thugs.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_211">
<text>Got you. Thanks, I'll keep it in mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_3">
<text>I'll try to help your guy.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_41">
<text>It is a pity for my friend... He was a good companion. But all the same, I am indebted to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_411">
<text>These things happen.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_51">
<text>Thanks for the help!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_511">
<text>So long!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_captive_dialog_61">
<text>You don't give a damn about other people... There's nothing for us to talk about.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21">
<text>Thank you brother! You freed my partner. Here, take this - in gratitude.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2111">
<text>That's a bargain.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212">
<text>I guess you're familiar with this place. What's interesting here?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2121">
<text>To the north there's a bandit camp. To the east - an old factory, and to the southwest there's a deserted pig farm, and some kind of gate beyond that. I can't say what's there, never been that far.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21211">
<text>Can you tell me more about the bandit camp?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212111">
<text>More... They settled in an unfinished building just north of here. Their chief is Borov - a real beast, we've been looking for him. We were sent here to kill him, actually.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21212">
<text>What's going on in the factory?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212121">
<text>We managed to find out that there is an entrance to some kind of vault there. But there are plenty of gangsters guarding it.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2121211">
<text>What kind of vault? What's inside it?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21212111">
<text>I don't know. We don't meddle there. I only know that Borov has one of the keys to its entrance.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21213">
<text>A real pig farm? With actual pigs?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212131">
<text>Salivating for some real pork chops, huh? Heck, the Zone is full of boars! Eat one - before you know it, you will glow in the dark, you won't need a flashlight anymore! Okay, just kidding, just kidding... The farm has been abandoned for a long time, some stalkers have settled there now. They didn't make a good impression on me and I usually trust my gut feeling.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21214">
<text>What's this gate you were talking about?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212141">
<text>I can't figure it out. Just an old gate except it's locked and well guarded. We haven't set foot in there.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_21215">
<text>I see, thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_212151">
<text>You're welcome! Come back any time if you need anything.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_213">
<text>Just the two of you went on a scouting raid?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_2131">
<text>There were two others. I don't know where they have gone, I've heard nothing... Maybe they were killed by the bandits.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_214">
<text>Take care of yourself.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_31">
<text>Ah, my friend... my friend, how will I make it now?.. Thank you brother! At least you tried to help. I keep my word.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41">
<text>Thanks for your help! What more do you want to know?</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_61">
<text>You refused to help me when I asked for it. Get out of here, we have no more to discuss...</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_611">
<text>So long!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_71">
<text>Man, the bandit guard is still alive, you need to finish him off!</text>  
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_72">
<text>Man, the bandit guards are still alive, you need to finish them off!</text>  
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_11">
<text>Hey buddy! Help me! I'm a Duty scout. Help me to get out!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_111">
<text>I'll try.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_112">
<text>There's nothing I can do for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_21">
<text>Thanks brother! I owe you one. Look what I found out - it may come in handy, you never know... Borov - he's their ringleader, in his store, he has a lot of goods. He has one of the keys to the dungeon in the old factory. My guards were gabbing that there used to be some kind of laboratory there. Only, getting to Borov won't be easy.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_211">
<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_2111">
<text>It's time to get back to my friends. It would be good to leave here alive...</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_21111">
<text>Good luck!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_31">
<text>We need to get out of here before the bandits decide to check this place out! Need something? Then hurry!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_311">
<text>No, nothing.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_41">
<text>Hey buddy! There's a switch on the wall - it opens the door to the cell.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_hello_411">
<text>Okay, I'll take a look.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_11">
<text>Hey, do you want a cool gun? I found something near Yantar... it was hidden in a cache. Among other stuff, there was a gauss gun. It's in excellent condition, I assure you - it will kill anything outright within a hundred metres. I'll sell it to you, if you're interested. It's only 800 roubles, it will take a few minutes for me to bring it.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_111">
<text>Here's the money.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_112">
<text>No thanks, I don't want it.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_113">
<text>Nah, keep it. I don't have the money.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_21">
<text>Got the money? Only hurry up, someone else has asked about it... he will be back soon.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_3">
<text>Excellent. Wait here, I'll get it.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_rob_dialog_31">
<text>I'll wait here.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_11">
<text>Dude, give me a medkit!</text>
</string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_111">
<text>Here you are.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_112">
<text>Sorry, I don't have a medkit.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_21">
<text>Thank you, my friend, you rescued me, no words can express my gratitude. If I live long enough to run into you again - I will repay my debt to you. But for now, I can share some interesting information with you. To the south of here there is a farm, where free stalkers have settled. One of them is selling a gauss gun very cheaply, for only 800 roubles. I was on my way to buy it when you came along - but as you can see, I got into deep shit... So, if you have the money, get it.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_211">
<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_4111">
<text>I owe you and I repay my debts. Come on.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41111">
<text>Great. Now I'm going to rock.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_4112">
<text>Sorry, but I have other plans.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41121">
<text>Well, then good luck to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_412">
<text>See you around!</text>
</string>

</string_table>
 

