<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>

<!-- Dialogi o transmutah -->

<string_table>
	
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_0">
		<text>Professor, they say you can create transmutes. Is that true?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_1">
		<text>Indeed, I know the procedure and I manipulate with artifacts and transmutes from time to time, but it is a VERY expensive process, do you understand? The transmutes are very rare and expensive to be considered toys! But I could certainly create them for you, if you manage to bring the necessary components and a certain sum of money, of course. Take a look at what I can propose:\n\n"Sky". Greatly increases the muscle tone of the bearer, boosting tear, rupture and hit resistance of the tissues. Is highly radioactive, though.\nPreparation cost: 35'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Night Star", "Moonlight", "Battery".\n\n"TdW". The name has been given by our German colleagues, who had been the first to create it. Heightens the psi-emission immunity.\nPreparation cost: 55'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Moonlight", flesh's eye.\n\n"Capricorn horn". Due to its unique attributes, it grants additional protection against bullets and blast waves.\nPreparation cost: 100'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Night Star", "Mama's Beads", "Gravi", "Droplets".\n\n"Hermes". A double-faced artifact: on one hand, it boosts the bearer's fatigue, on the other - incinerates his tissues.\nPreparation cost: 35'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Moonlight", "Plasma Cactus", "Slime".\n\n"Sponge". Protects against radiation and excessive temperatures.\nPreparation cost: 75'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Mica", "Shell", "Fireball".\n\n"Honeycomb". Neutralizes the negative influence of various toxins on human organism.\nPreparation cost: 20'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Pellicle", "Wrenched".\n\n"Red Star". Promotes faster health restore and wound healing.\nPreparation cost: 150'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Soul", "Mica", bloodsucker's tissues pattern.\n\n"Eye". Boosts wound healing, but reduces the bearer's resistance to psionic influence. This artifact has a unique ability: when placed on the owner's body, it keeps most snorks and burers from attacking.\nPreparation cost: 85'000 rub. Necessary ingredients: "Goldfish", "Mica", controller's hand.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_01">
		<text>Professor, may I request more transmutes from you, please?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_02">
		<text>Of course, young man, you are always welcome! What exactly are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_1">
		<text>The "Sky".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_2">
		<text>The "TdW", if you don't mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_3">
		<text>The "Capricorn Horn", please.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_4">
		<text>The "Hermes". I'm sick and tired of dragging myself about the entire Zone in full marching order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_5">
		<text>The "Sponge". Or else I either start to glow very soon, or become a drunkard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_6">
		<text>The "Honeycomb".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_7">
		<text>The "Red Star". I look like a mummy because of all those bandages.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_trans_8">
		<text>The "Eye".</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_5">
		<text>Whoops, I haven't got enough money. See you later, Professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_6">
		<text>Here you are, young man, the requested transmute is ready!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_7">
		<text>Ready, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_8">
		<text>Wow! I hope it's worth the money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_9">
		<text>Excellent work, Professor, I'm impressed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_10">
		<text>Can you make more, please?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_trader_transmut_11">
		<text>Sure, Marked One! Luckily, I've got plenty of free time right now.</text>
	</string>

</string_table>