<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_13">
		<text>Well... Uhhh... I'm leaving. [Flees]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_12">
		<text>[Master] He wants to kill us, Vasiliy. [Vasiliy] Kill us? How could he kill us, he's pathetic. [Master] He can't kill us. We are sick of talking to him. [Vasiliy] Yes, that's enough. Get out of here while your protection still works, stalker, and do not ever come back. [Chorus] NOW GO AWAY!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_11">
		<text>You are monsters! You have to be destroyed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_10">
		<text>[Master] Yes, we feed on them. In case you have not noticed, what we have here isn't a complete life support equipment, we need to feed ourselves somehow. [Vasiliy] Stupid stalkers, stupid scientists, stupid military. They come to this city. OUR city. We subjugate them to our will, lead them to our shelter. And when they die, we eat them. [Master] Delicacies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_9">
		<text>Is that why there are so many corpses? You eat them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_8">
		<text>(You feel a cautious attempt to find a weak spot in your consciousness) [Master] What a good protection. Where do we come from? Tell him, Vasiliy. [Vasiliy] We have been brought here, in that flask. We were going to be recycled. Oh, but we aren't guinea pigs that you can dispose of... WE recycled THEM. [Master] Excellent recycling. The water here now is very nutritious. [Vasiliy] Very nutritious, Master, excellent water. They decompose, we feed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_7">
		<text>I do not intend to submit to you, calm down. Where are you from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_6">
		<text>[First] He wants to know what we are, Vasiliy. [Second] What a curious stalker. Is he a scientist? I, too, used to be a scientist. Let's explain it, Master. [First] Well, well, explain. [Chorus] EXPLAIN. [First] This garbage in the suit that you see in front of you is Vasily. He also wanted to know what we are. He found out. We explained it to him. [Vasiliy] And what you see right behind me in the ventilation shaft and then - it is the Master. The Master must be obeyed. [Chorus] OBEY! (The pressure on your mind increases sharply then weakens again)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_5">
		<text>What the hell is going on here? Who or what is that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_4">
		<text>(The pressure on your consciousness increases sharply, but then fades) [First] We can not enter his mind, Vasiliy. [Second] He is aggressive, Master. He is well protected. [First] Maybe he's a scientist that came to study us? [Second] Maybe we can kill him? [First] No, we can not kill him, his mind is not available, the protection interferes. [Second] Then we have to talk to him, Master. [First] Yes, talk. You can talk to him and it will give us time to think something out. [Chorus] We'll talk to you, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_3">
		<text>Now, get the hell out of my head, you freaks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_2">
		<text>(You feel like something is trying to get into your mind, but to no avail) [First] We do not feel him, Vasiliy. [Second] He is protected from us, Master. [Chorus] Why can't we feel you, stalker, are you protected?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_1">
		<text>Um... I... came to find the source of the emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_intro_dialog_0">
		<text>(You hear two voices in your head) [First] Strange guest we have today, don't we, Vasiliy? [Second] Yes, a strange visitor. How did he get here? [First] Really, how did he get here? [Chorus] How did you get here, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_reward_dialog_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Deal then, Prokhorov. Thanks for the nice offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_reward_dialog_1_1_1_1">
		<text>About you... I keep my promises. Here you are - our heavy armor, "SKAT", which is very appreciated by stalkers, as far as I know. And there's a gun, just from the storage. I tried to pick the best one for you. And take this cartridge box as well. And here's your "Friend-or-Foe" transponder. It will make us all recognize you as our friend, so you don't have to worry upon meeting a patrol now. It is water- and shock-proof, and powered by a radiogenic element battery, so you don't even need to use it in any other way but just carry it with you. Don't try to pry it open though; it has a protection and the circuit will self-destroy. And, well... Take care of yourself, Strelok. And if you ever want to exit the Zone, I'll leave details at the checkpoint for you to contact me. I'd attach you as a consultant at the research institute on the Zone, based in Kiev. No dusty work, an easy life, and your knowledge would be very valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_reward_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>Well, that's a good end, Colonel. And what about me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_reward_dialog_1_1">
	  <text>Good. All right, I just got in touch with the authorities. Can you believe it - these freaks already sent a death notice to my family! I talked with my wife, she was in shock, already desperate about not even having a body to bury and here I am, safe and sound all of a sudden. I also talked with the kids, they're waiting for me to come home. Thank you, once again. I really did not expect to get out of here. A car will soon be sent to pick me up, then I can expect a long debriefing at the special department. I hope all those hows and whys won't prevent me from getting home by tomorrow. And never again do I set foot in the damn Zone! Fuck it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_reward_dialog_1">
		<text>Oh, yeah, just took a nap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_reward_dialog_0">
		<text>Are you with me, Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_final_dialog_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Alright then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_final_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>Don't worry, everything will go as I promised. You have my word.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_final_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Hmm. Let's hope nobody does anything stupid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_final_dialog_1">
		<text>Yeah, this was a long road. Get some sleep while I go talk to the checkpoint chief, I have to report to the command. I'll be back in about half an hour. Just don't browbeat the Spetsnaz soldiers, okay? They're a bit nervous, you see. And you don't have a friendly appearance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_final_dialog_0">
		<text>Yes, it seems we've made it, Colonel. I'll need to rest for a bit, I'm exhausted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_final_dialog_10">
		<text>Here we are, Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_escape_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Gather your things, then. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_escape_dialog_1">
		<text>I know, we got jolted here, too - even the walls shook. And immediately after my head got better, the voices stopped. It's like having a roof removed, or as though everyone in my head died off. Thanks a lot, Strelok. I owe you. There's only one more thing remaining - I still need to get away from here. Could you take me to the checkpoint at the Cordon? Don't worry, with me along they won't touch you, as I have a transponder up and running. Then I'll talk with the higher-ups about you. I think they won't mind to recruiting you as a Military Stalker. I'll get you some of our deep-Zone raid equipment, and one of our transponders - it will make us all recognize you as a friend of the army. Plus I'll set up an easy way out of the Zone for you, in case you happen to want to leave it. That certaily isn't as much as what you have done for me, but it is all I can promise.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_escape_dialog_0">
		<text>It seems the Master is dead. I blew the charge. The blast even made the ground shake.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_bomb_ready_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Got it. Alright, give me that can. And if anything... Well... Don't think badly of me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_bomb_ready_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, everything is ready. I tested some of the media separately, just to make sure it worked - it burned through a concrete slab. The bomb has been arranged in this old milk can, which is also made of aluminium, it'll add some heat. The can is hermetically sealed, and here you can see the switch, in the hole on the lid. All you have to do is to drag the can as close as possible to the things and flip the switch. It'll ignite the icendiary composition inside. As it flares up you won't have a lot of time to escape, so don't linger! The detonation delay is only two and a half minutes, I couldn't make any longer flame retardant, so activate it and run like hell, got it? The blow will expand, reacting with water, so it might even fill the whole tunnel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_bomb_ready_dialog_0">
		<text>Are you done with the bomb?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_bomb_assembly_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Alright, I'll rest for a bit. That stuff was kinda heavy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_bomb_assembly_dialog_1">
		<text>Excellent. The guys already have collected some rusty iron. It will take four hours, now, so you can get some slack. All we need to do now is to grind it down to dust, and mix it in the right proportions. By the way, you can ask Bosun, he might need help with something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_bomb_assembly_dialog_0">
		<text>Here, I found all the components you needed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_12">
		<text>Got it, I'll go look for your Chinook. Let's make some monster soup.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_11">
		<text>Aluminium, Magnesium for the ignition, and rust. Lots of rust. There are bulks of rusty iron here, I'll make guys gather it, but for the aluminium and magnesium I'll have to send you, Strelok. Go to the crash site of our Chinook. I suggest that you get the rim of the landing gear, and a large piece of cladding. We'll then have to grind it down, mix it up with the rust, and if everything turns out ok, we will have our Thermite bomb ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_10">
		<text>What does it take?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_9">
		<text>We'll simply use a Thermite bomb. The thermite burns at extremely high temperatures. With a large amount, it will be enough to boil a pool of water. And if we're lucky, and the combustion temperature is sufficient, then the water will begin to decompose to hydrogen and oxygen, which will in turn burn and explode, adding to the destruction. Make that thing detonate and no living thing will survive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_8">
		<text>That's still a lot, how do we do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_7">
		<text>We don't need to boil all the water, just what's in the room with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_6">
		<text>How would you make such a huge amount of water boil?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_5">
		<text>Then here's the plan; we boil the water in there, and we cook that fucker alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_4">
		<text>I think it will. This is definitely a living thing, high temperatures should hurt it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_3">
		<text>Flooded, uh? Hmm, then I have another idea that might work... Do you think boiling that thing would kill it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_2">
		<text>There is something, large, and alive. Similar to the brain at Yantar, but this one is out of its flask, and way larger. And I can't use my weapons there; the whole thing is flooded with water.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_1">
		<text>Well done, Strelok! Now tell me, what did you find there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_make_bomb_dialog_0">
		<text>I made it into the lair.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_ready_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Understood, I do a quick reconnaissance and come back immediately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_ready_dialog_1">
		<text>Seems pretty good. Hold on. [Gives you the psy-helmet] See? Just be very careful... There. Good! Now, at first, get in there just to reconnoiter. Don't try anything yet. Find out what is in there, what Master looks like, and quickly get back. We will think of what to do next.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_ready_dialog_0">
		<text>So, how did it work, with the helmet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_14">
		<text>Well, here you go, then. [Give the psy-helmet to Prokhorov]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_13">
		<text>Nothing special, I've got everything I need here. The radio will provide additional parts and I've noticed a solderer somewhere here. Leave it to me, I'll be done in half an hour. The lair is flooded, you say? You'll have to put on some scientific suits or a military stalker armor. They have an enclosed life-support system, and they rely only on the air inside the suit. Keeps you breathing for a long time, simply by filtering and absorbing the carbon dioxide from it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_12">
		<text>Great! What do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_11">
		<text>Let's say this pattern is set to one specific frequency and amplitude. We could try to alter it a bit, so that the parameters are adjusted automatically, corresponding to the strength of a particular emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_10">
		<text>So what do we do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_9">
		<text>Seems like there's some different parameter of this radiation, frequency or amplitude... In the city itself the radiation amplitude is weaker, thus inbounds are blocked by the helmet. In the lair though, it is not enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_8">
		<text>Then why doesn't it work in the lair?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_7">
		<text>...It looks like Sakharov decided to use wave interference - he set the helmet to emit a signal similar to the radiation acting upon the helmet, but opposed to it. As a result, the waves cancel each other and do not reach the brain. A very effective scheme.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_6">
		<text>So?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_5">
		<text>So, let's see. Hm. The radiating antenna... Yeah, but this one is obviously a recieving one. Very good of the professor! Well, this helmet is a radiation counter-transmitter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_4">
		<text>Yes, Sakharov created it. Here you are. [Show the psy-helmet to Prokhorov]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_3">
		<text>Let me think... So, did Sakharov make this helmet, by any chance? Let me give it a look. I worked as an engineer before joining the army, an electronician.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_2">
		<text>Yeah, though it was quite difficult. But I think I found his lair. Though I can't get in, there is an emission that even my helmet can't cope with. In addition, it is thoroughly flooded with water.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_1">
		<text>What is it? Did you find the intel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_helmet_dialog_0">
		<text>Colonel, about the Master..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_14">
		<text>Got it. See you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Well, good luck then. Ask Bosun if you need any equipment. The moment you find something significant bring it to me immediately, got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_12">
		<text>Alright, I'll go search for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Yeah, that's the problem, they fled. One stole the reels and flew into the city. Then the second, too, who covered him. And all the data is in their PDA. Where they are now - I have no idea. But you have a protective device, you can find them and retrieve the data from their PDA. Search the city, they couldn't have gone far. Just remember: no matter what happens, you must be here in the shelter at nine every evening. Master awakens at nine, and by this time we'll have the doors locked tight, and we won't open them until six in the morning. Remember, half an hour before the time is up we'll activate the siren. The moment you hear it, stop whatever you are doing and run to us, sprinting, okay?\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_10">
		<text>And how? Where did these two guys go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_9">
		<text>You understand that this thing has to be destroyed. While it rules the city, we cannot break out, it would cook our brains. And if we stay, we'll just all die of starvation, that's it. But I've got another idea. I think those scientists didn't just go to the river for stupid samples. I'm a former artilleryman, I know how triangulation works. They probably found the source of the radiation. And those two who allegedly went to collect water samples were most likely sent to this river to scout. And they apparently found something, since all that shit happened. We need to find their data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_8">
		<text>Well, that's already a more complete story. So what do you suggest to end all this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_7">
		<text>It started with the night. What a nightmare. Creepy hallucinations, minds breaking, the voices in my head. People started losing their marbles, wooping things up. They grabbed some guns, and a shootout started. It was complete shit. And then we became flooded with beasts and zombies, and it was a mess. We somehow barricaded ourselves on the second floor and held it. The hallucinations worsened. A couple of soldiers shot themselves. At two in the night, it became clear we'd all be crazy or dead by morning if we didn't do something quickly. We dismantled the barricade, fought our way to the vehicles, jumped into the armors and drove the hell out of this town. The first one finally made it out, and we ended up in a swamp. The third one ran into a "Vortex" and got sqeezed, with all the people inside it. We still somehow had communication so I called for an emergency evacuation. It took half an hour to persuade the higher-ups to despatch a night flight, but in the end they sent us a Chinook. It got to us, landed, we quickly loaded the wounded, boarded, and - well, took off. As we were just over the city, I went to the cockpit and the pilot looked at me weirdly and said: "Master ordered to bring you back". And he headed the chopper directly towards the ground. I rolled over, grabbed some handrail and then, a blow... And I can't remember anything else. Only scraps. Some subway tunnel, with wagons. A bridge. And the voice of the Master, giving me orders. I somehow arrived here alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_6">
		<text>And what happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_5">
		<text>No, I didn't; it talks to me instead. I hear it in my head, at night. I've been trying to drown it in vodka, the voices fade as I drink. The guys here twist a finger at their temple, they think I'm crazy, but I'm not, I know it exists. And you will know if you listen carefully. So after we came here and began the study, things went strange. Well, we're in the Zone after all, but still there were some very strange coincidences. Some that were too weird, even for the Zone. After about a week, the scientists said they had a clue to what was going on, and they started comparing everything with Yantar. They talked about Sakharov's research and about their own observations, some Kaymanov emmiter, and non-standard radiation parameters. Triangulation of some sort needed to be done, and they climbed buildings with their devices to measure radiations at different points, apparently. And the day before it started, a couple of scientists headed to the river to take some water samples. A sampling like any other. Since they were going out, I gave them an escort. And they disappeared for a long time, but it only started to really bother us by the evening. The remaining scientists were nervous, whispering stuff. And just when I was about to send a team to look for them, they came back. But they were scary. Pale. Without samples, and without the escort. All mumbling some nonsense about some Master, and that he was supposedly awake and not very happy. The head of the expedition, professor Seversky, locked himself up with them and questioned them for a long time. He came out very nervous and went directly to his place to report to his HQ without saying anything to us. And the scientists that went to the river got a sedative and were put to bed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Did you talk to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_3">
		<text>I'll tell you, I'll tell you... I've already told everyone but they won't believe me, dammit. Basically, there is something under this town. Something alive. And it like a controller, only much stronger. Master. It calls itself Master.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Wait, not so fast. Tell me what happened to you. From the very beggining.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Yeah, I really need help, stalker. This thing is still picking in my brain, I'm not myself anymore. Fucking Master...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_quest_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Salutations, Colonel. Bosun says you need help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_22">
		<text>Well, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_21">
		<text>A couple of days passed, then Prokhorov came and told us what happened. At first, everything seemed fine. It was, well... all as it should be. The protective gear helped, they had these special helmets with the slip rings. They were recording measurments, collecting samples, poking in anomalies with their stuff. And that night, insanity started. In mass. People began to go mad. Ones started tearing their own throats with with bare hands, others began smashing heads against the walls, some simply put guns in their mouths and... Then the beasts flooded. The people inside, who managed to stay with their heads clear, barricaded themselves. Most scientists had gone mad and fled in every direction in complete confusion. That was the situation - in the night, surrounded by creatures, with the guys inside going off one after another. By morning, those who were still able to think tried to escape. The survivors boarded the APCs and drove blindly out of the city. The first APC exploded, the second one drowned in the lake, and the third got into a powerful "Vortex" and got smashed. Prokhorov was among the group of foreign scientists who survived from the second APC. He called for an evacuation on the radio, and they sent a cargo helicopter. They even managed to land and take off, but then the emissions caught up on the pilots, and they crashed. Well at least they didn't manage to fly that high, and they didn't fall into any anomalous field. But what happened next, Prokhorov has not yet been able to tell. He doesn't remember anything from the fall. And as for how he reached us - he doesn't know, and he had to go through the entire city... Well, since then, we're keeping him here. He can't be evacuated, and he cannot leave with us. And yeah, it also seems he's been a bit mind damaged after all this. He smokes continuously and keeps talking about some master of the city, saying that he needs to kill it, otherwise all of us here are doomed. Speak to him, you might think of a way to get him out of here, and how to bring us along. At the same time maybe he could help us, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_20">
		<text>And what happened next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_19">
		<text>We opened the door, pulled him in and shut the door back as quickly as we could. That shit was crazy. The Colonel's face was white as a sheet, spattered in blood. He was drooling, unable to speak calmly, kept screaming and mumbling something in panic. His armor was completely trashed, his helmet badly dented, it was a wonder how he managed to reach us. We forced him to drink half a bottle of vodka, cut off what was left of his protection, and put him to bed. We spent the whole night on tenterhooks, then in the morning we went to investigate. The Colonel didn't come - he slept continiously for two days in a row. We went to the building where they had been - the old gym, at the central square. And there, my friend, it was Hell. A terrible mess, furniture piled at the door as if they had tried to lock themselves in, blood all around the building, the equipment just good to be put in the trash. But at the same time - not a living soul, and what was even worse - no corpses. It became clear that shit had gone down, there, and since that night, everything in the city has become sharply worse. The central part is now akin to Yantar, whoever's got a brain simply wouldn't go there. Controllers appeared where they weren't before, and a lot of zombies with them. They're roaming the city in bulks now. Stalkers who used to come for the artifacts don't set foot here any longer. Yeah, that's our global situation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_18">
		<text>And what did you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_17">
		<text>Well, Town-32 has always been quite an inhospitable place, but lately, everything has gone to real shit. About a month ago a major scientific expedition came here, with all the high-tech stuff they could carry and a full military escort. They started taking all their measurments, trying some brand new research, the usual thing. We helped them with small things, traded a few rare artifacts to them, but mostly they didn't bother with us. They had protective suits that, as I understood, protected them from the local radiation. And it seemed to work pretty well, actually. And then a couple of weeks ago, we were sitting the night out, playing backgammon. It was about four in the morning. And suddenly there was this wild knocking on the door, and someone screamed "Help!", and so on. Normally we never open the door at night - it would be dumb to open it, after all, with the whole town crawling up at night... But then I suddenly recalled the voice. It was Colonel Prokhorov yelling outside! The security chief of the expedition! Yelling so hard, I almost couldn't make out his voice. I was very suprised of him to turn up here, away from all their protective equipment and APCs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_16">
		<text>What's going on in this city? I mean, sure, we're in the Zone, but it still seems a bit too much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_15">
		<text>Well, let's start from the very beggining. This town is an eerie place. You can't spend the night in it, you'd go mad. It has something to do with psyche; you have terrible hallucinations, stuff distorts around you... Basically you just go nuts. But although it's so wild and eerie, it also holds a lot of valuable artifacts. Finding them is hard, though, even while the sun shines. Once we went for a raid in this place of evil, and stumbled accidentally on this old bomb shelter with strong hermetic doors. As we didn't really had enough time to get through the city, so we dared locking ourselves in for the night. And not only did we survive, but none of us went mad, though the fear left its mark on some. We remembered this place, shared it among our friends, and soon it began to be used as a permanent cache in which we used to keep useful supplies and where we could wait out the night. Soon all stalkers got to know about this asylum, and often various groups met here at sunset. Now, simply waiting from sunset to dawn - that's boring. As a result, people started playing cards, dices, and the like. We even brought a pool table from the building cornered with the city committee, a diesel generator, a couple of tables with cozy seats. A duty was established to keep the place clean and make sure no monster ever came in... We tied a civil defence siren on top of one of the old buildings, powered it from the generator. We play the siren at dusk to inform those in the city that it's time to cut bait and run for a shelter. As the holy place is never empty, finally there arrived a long-staying stalker, someone no longer expected on the Mainland, who remained behind the bar to monitor things, to keep this outpost of civilization in order. And that guy's me. That's the story, so now I'm here on duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_14">
		<text>But how did this whole bar appear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_13">
		<text>We were together at the time we made our way into the Zone. From the northern part, from Belarus. We found a lot of artifacts, many of them unique. Then, after the second emission made new parts of the Zone accessible, you came that way. I followed you here and founded the bar. You went further to investigate, and I settled, setting up a base. Eventually, commerce established a little.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_12">
		<text>Tell me how do you know my team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_11">
		<text>So that was true... I'm sorry, they were good guys. So that's our situation, uh? Well, in that case, I'll try to give you a hand to my best, old friend. Ask whatever you're interested in, and I'll tell you what I know, as well as the reason I called you here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_10">
		<text>They died. Fang was shot down by a mercenary near the warehouses, and Ghost fell the victim of a controller in the laboratory under Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_9">
		<text>Hey, then what about your teammates, Ghost and Fang, do you know what they're up to?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_8">
		<text>Well, I can remember stuff from since I woke up. The rest restores slowly. It's still not completely back but sometimes I dream of my past, and I remember fragments when in a familiar place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_7">
		<text>Bloody hell. Don't you remember anything at all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_6">
		<text>Dead serious. I came to my senses at Sidorovich's, with this mark on my arm as a little bonus that came with the written-off death truck they rescued me from...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_5">
		<text>Come on.. You? Amnesia? You're kidding, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_4">
		<text>Basically, it seems to have something to do with me going to the center of the Zone. I lost my memory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_3">
		<text>Protective helmet - that's great! We really need to restore our connection with the rest of the Zone, or we'll run out of supplies... Wait, what do you mean by "almost died"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_2">
		<text>Um, well, in a sense, I really almost died. And as for the City, I have a special protective helmet Sakharov gave me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, it was me. Greetings, Strelok! I'm glad to see you are doing well. Where have you been for so long? Rumours already had it that you perished at the Radar, and there was no sign of you being still alive. How did you manage to pass through the City, by the way? There's now a bigger fry than there was at Yantar! We've been stuck here for a week, unable to leave. We're already low on water and food, and unless something is done soon, we'll be in trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_barman_quest_dialog_0">
		<text>Hi, was it you that called for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_0">
		<text>I need answers to several questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1">
		<text>Ask away, I'll try to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_11">
		<text>Where are my things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_111">
		<text>The leader usually keeps all the confiscated stuff. His room is on the top floor. My things were taken there when they caught me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1111">
		<text>Thanks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_12">
		<text>How can I get out of here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_121">
		<text>When they were leading me around I noticed a sewer grate under the stairs on the first floor... If you managed to open the cell it would be possible to get out of here using that sewer... It's best to go West and then you can use the tunnel to get to Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1211">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_14">
		<text>Who captured us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_141">
		<text>We're being held by the Mercs. Nobody really knows who they are but there are rumours that they work for some foreign intelligence services. The location of this base is top secret - no one knows how to get into the Dead City. Many people are very interested in this information, especially Freedom and Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1411">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_14111">
		<text>If you manage to get a map of the Dead City, a successful assault will be inavitable. The Mercs or the bandits probably have one. You could try to get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_141111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_15">
		<text>What do you know about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_151">
		<text>The city is split into two sections. We're on the Merc's side. To the south beyond the square is where the bandits are. They're holed up in the school building southwest of the city. In between the bases, there is a run down five-floor building and a few relatively intact ones. If the shit hits the fan, you can sit it out there. There are also some garages and a couple of small houses around that area. There are a couple of five-floor buildings and a dozen garages on the bandits' side too. The former city council building is on the other side of the square.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1511">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_16">
		<text>Who's in charge here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_161">
		<text>A truly nasty guy they call Dushman. I've seen him carrying around a folder with some documents a couple of times. I reckon there's something interesting inside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1611">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_17">
		<text>Nope, nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_11">
		<text>Strelok! Where the hell have you been??? I haven't seen you or the guys since the last raid! I was getting worried!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_21">
		<text>So, do you feel better? Can you think clearly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_0">
		<text>Strelok???</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, Strelok! Who else would you be? I'm Doc, don't you recognize me? What happened to you, friend? You don't look well. We went into the Zone together for 2 years. You really don't remember me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_11">
		<text>No, I don't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_2">
		<text>You don't??? Strelok, what the...? You're not joking around, are you? Man... What about the guys, our guys? Fang, Ghost? You remember them, don't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_21">
		<text>I don't remember Fang, and Ghost is dead - I found his body at Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_3">
		<text>Ghost!!?!?! Dead??!!! Dammit, how could that happen?! He... He was one of the best. What happened to all of you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_31">
		<text>I don't know what happened, I don't remember.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_4">
		<text>Wait, I need to calm down. That's some shitty news. I think it's all linked with your last trip into the Zone. When we saw each other last time, you left me the key from the stash at Pripyat and the instructions of how to find it. I've managed to keep it - hid it from the Mercs. Here, take it, hide it well. Perhaps you'll find something there. You said that there was some trick with the "Monolith". But I don't think you understood it fully yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_41">
		<text>I see. Where are we? I don't remember how I got here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_5">
		<text>We're in the Dead City! In the Merc's camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_6">
		<text>We're in the Dead City!.. In the Merc's camp...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_0">
		<text>By the way, I have information about the Mercs. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_1">
		<text>Depends on the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_11">
		<text>I have a map which details the location of their base, guard posts, the way to get in without being noticed and a lot more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_111">
		<text>Sounds valuable. I'll give you 3000 for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_1111">
		<text>Deal. Here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_11111">
		<text>Great! Here's your reward. Soon stalkers will argue about whether Mercs even existed at all!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_1112">
		<text>Not, that's not enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_11121">
		<text>As you wish, I'm not giving you any more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_13">
		<text>Nothing worthwhile. Just the usual gossip. Sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_cit_reward_131">
		<text>If you find out something more specific come back. I'll pay you.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
