<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_21">
		<text>Let's move up the street. If anything happens, cover me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_211">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_31">
		<text>Thanks for the help, Marked One. That was a hard fight. We can rest here. If you want to keep going, I'll tell you more about the area. If you go back and turn right you'll reach the bus station. That area is open and not very safe. If you go forward you'll end up in front of the hotel. To the right of it is the "Monolith" base. Those guys have no limits. Behind the base is the stadium. We were planning to get to the station through it. That's all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_311">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_41">
		<text>Thanks for the help. Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_followers_start_dlg_411">
		<text>So long!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_9">
		<text>Well, let's try. At least it has some chance of success. I'll link the helicopters to your transponder code, and when you get close enough to the complex, they will attack at a low altitude. Be careful not to get caught in the rocket fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_8">
		<text>More than enough. While the helicopters attack, I can slip inside unnoticed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_7">
		<text>...Of course, the "Monolith" elite will probably be there in full force. So, let me think. I won't be able to provide any soldiers, our losses in the CNPP operation were too great, almost all we sent were killed. But I have a subordinate operational element of attack helicopters. Will that be enough for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_6">
		<text>Alive and they continue to experiment. They must be stopped at all costs. I'm going to get into the complex and destroy them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_5">
		<text>Holy shit! And are they still alive? Our intelligence didn't uncover such data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_4">
		<text>I learned the location of the main C-Consciousness laboratory, and I'm going to attack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_3">
		<text>Wow. What's that for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_2">
		<text>I need military support, preferably aircraft or armoured vehicles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_1">
		<text>Yes, what do you want, Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_military_dialog_0">
		<text>Colonel, listen, it's great to see you here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_13_1">
		<text>Hmm. Okay, you convinced me. Whatever the consequences - we'll do it. I'm afraid we may not get another chance, and if so - we need to use whatever assets we have, no matter how meagre they may be. Although this is a suicide mission, you will receive our support. I know the approximate location of the main C-Consciousness lab, and now, after disabling  the Scorcher and destroying the main monolith base at the CNPP, we will be able to break through. Our group will approach their base from the North side and will wait for your PDA's signal on the network. Once you reach there, they will begin their assault from the north, giving you the chance to get into the lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_13_2">
		<text>I'm afraid not, Marked One, these tall words are not sufficient grounds for a suicide operation with an uncertain outcome. Sorry, I can't risk the lives of my best men for the sake of you reaching a personal goal, which personally - is a mystery to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_12_1">
		<text>The price is the issue, General. Even so, for them, judging by all the facts known to us, the end justify the means. How many more people, will they kill on the way to their goal? Thousands, millions... maybe the entire world? Will the price of achieving this, be what we are willing to pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_12_2">
		<text>The road to hell is paved with good intentions. Experiments of this class must not be done by uncontrolled scientific groups, pursuing their personal goals, but by the official Research Institutes under the strict supervision of world science. Otherwise, we will get what we have here now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_12">
		<text>Is it possible, that their efforts are for the good? And by our actions we may stop them from finishing the job and putting everything in order, and perhaps advancing humanity to a new level of evolution?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_11">
		<text>You want to get in to attack and destroy them, do I understand you correctly? But what will happen? Are you sure that the results will be positive, and things won't get out of control?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_11_1">
		<text>They need to be destroyed. They are the link between the Zone and the noosphere. As long as they are alive, we are not able to control or stop the energy coming out from there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_11_2">
		<text>They need to be destroyed. Using the energy coming out of the noosphere they are almost gods, their opportunities are almost boundless. It's dangerous not only for the Zone, but also for the whole world.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_10_2">
		<text>Yes, they are alive. They were able to connect to the noosphere, and now they control everything that happens in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_10_1">
		<text>Yes, they are alive. They were able to connect to the noosphere, but they can't fully control the energy pouring out from there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_10">
		<text>So it seems. Yes, I was aware of the work of this group of pseudo-scientific criminals here before the events of the first emission. There is also the documentation that you found earlier and handed over to Barkeep. But how is it, that they are still alive? I thought they were all killed during the first emissions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_9_2">
		<text>You've probably heard about the C-Consciousness group. Their experimental merger with thenoosphere got out of control and led to the formation of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_9_1">
		<text>You've probably heard about the C-Consciousness group. They sought to gain limitless power over the minds of people and as a result of their experiments, they created the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_9">
		<text>That's heavy stuff, tell me more about what's at stake?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_8_2">
		<text>I found the cause of what is happening in the Zone. Now we can fix it and possibly destroy the Zone itself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_8_1">
		<text>I found the cause of what is happening in the Zone. Now we can fix it and make it a safe haven for all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_7">
		<text>For what reason, Marked One? I don't have any people to spare for military adventures.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_6">
		<text>I need the support of your fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_1">
		<text>What is it, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_dolg_dialog_0">
		<text>General, I have something to ask you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_13_1">
		<text>Yeah, okay, you convinced me, man. Let's try to kick their ass. Our chances aren't great, but we are seasoned fighters, we've held the fucking Barrier for over a year. From negotiations with Duty, we already know the approximate location of these freak's laboratory, and after your thorough cleaning of the centre we will be able to break through to support you. Our team will descend to their base from the south side and will wait for your PDA's signal on the network. Once you arrive - they will begin the assault, covering your attack on the lab. Good luck, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_13_2">
		<text>Sorry, Marked One, you spoke too many words, and made too little sense. No offence intended man, but I won't sacrifice my best fighters in order for you to achieve some obscure goal. I just can't trust you enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_12_1">
		<text>The question is, what will it cost us, Lukash. Even so, for them, judging by what I have learned, the ends justify the means. How many more people, they will kill on the way to their goal? Thousands, millions ... maybe the whole world? Will the price of achieving this, be what we are willing to pay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_12_2">
		<text>The road to hell is paved with good intentions. Experiments of this class must not be done by uncontrolled scientific groups, pursuing their personal goals, but by the official Research Institutes under the strict supervision of world science. Otherwise, we will get what we have here now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_12">
		<text>Are you sure of that? Is it possible that they were just trying to make the world a little better by creating the Zone, and our actions will only disrupt them from putting everything back in order and start bringing the experiment to completion? The Zone can be very useful to all mankind, so many discoveries have been made here already, from them, many unique technologies and materials can be created...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_11">
		<text>You want me to help you get in and destroy them, do I understand you correctly? And what does it mean? Are you sure we won't be in deeper shit afterwards?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_11_1">
		<text>They need to be destroyed. They - are the link between the Zone and the noosphere. As long as they are alive, we are not able to control or stop the energy coming out there and the Zone will become more dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_11_2">
		<text>They need to be destroyed. Using the energy coming out of the noosphere they are almost gods, their opportunities are almost boundless and their objectives are unknown. Perhaps they will eventually enslave the world, absorbing it into the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_10_2">
		<text>Yes, they are alive. They were able to connect to the noosphere, and now they control everything that happens in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_10_1">
		<text>Yes, they are alive. They were able to connect to the noosphere, but they can't fully control the energy pouring out from there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_10">
		<text>I've heard, yes. They made plenty of marks, we recently heard Duty talking about them on a closed channel. But how is it, that they are still alive? I thought they were all killed during the first emissions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_9_2">
		<text>You probably heard of the C-Consciousness. Their experimental merger with the noosphere got out of control and led to the formation of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_9_1">
		<text>You probably heard of the C-Consciousness. They sought to gain limitless power over the minds of people and as a result of their experiments, they created the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_9">
		<text>Wow, man, you got to the bottom of it, I knew you would. Then tell me something, what did you find out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_8_2">
		<text>I found the cause of what is happening in the Zone. Now we can fix it and possibly destroy the Zone itself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_8_1">
		<text>I found the cause of what is happening in the Zone. Now we can fix it and make it a safe haven for all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_7">
		<text>You sound serious. What is it, Marked One? I don't have a lot of people, the Barrier is constantly eroding my men.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_6">
		<text>I need the support of your fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_1">
		<text>What is it, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_freedom_dialog_0">
		<text>Lukash, hi, I have something important to ask you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_29">
		<text>Yes, you're right. I can't make the same mistake twice by going alone, I won't tolerate it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_28">
		<text>Listen, don't be in such a hurry. If their main base is there, then it's most likely their security will be much tighter than what it was at Chernobyl, and most probably be the elite of the "Monolith" - those who were not completely brainwashed. This is what I advise. If you're going to attack them, you will need serious help. You can try to involve Duty, they are always happy to clear the Zone. And maybe even sweet talk Freedom into helping you. In general, it would be nice to use both of them at once, but then they'd have to reconcile somehow, so as they didn't battle each other in the assault. Well, it could be worth a try to convey the news to the military on the mainland, if you still have a connection with them. They screwed up big time at the CNPP and they're not happy, so it's probable they'll help. If you transfer the coordinates of this base to them, they won't miss opportunity to strike with all their remaining forces. So think it over, which of your allies to ask. And then, let the battle begin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_27">
		<text>What is there to do. I plan to kill them. Everyone. For all that they did to me. I remembered that I found a way how to get to their base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_26">
		<text>And what do you plan to do about it now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_25">
		<text>Yes, in time. I remembered. They have an underground laboratory, a control centre a little deeper in the centre of the Zone. A few kilometres from here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_24">
		<text>Holy crap, well it's plausible, all right then, what about the base - did you managed to find it? Do you remember now, or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_23">
		<text>They didn't know that they had got me mixed up with Ghost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_22">
		<text>And how did that happen then? Didn't they know you by sight?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_21">
		<text>Something like that. Everyone was given a job, I for example, was to "Kill Strelok". I had to kill myself. How ridiculous...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_20">
		<text>They addled their minds, then sent them out into the Zone as agents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_19">
		<text>The project is about consciousness. They have created the legend of the Wish Granter, so as to lure the most experienced stalkers to the centre of the Zone. And there they are caught and subjected to brainwashing, and tattooed here, just like me, then sent back into the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_18">
		<text>What do you mean? Why are they there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_17">
		<text>I almost got away with it, but I was caught in the end and put back into circulation. But before that, I found out that yes, the CNPP and the "Monolith" are one huge smoke screen. There is nothing there. It's a trap for fools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_16">
		<text>You shouldn't have taken the risk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_15">
		<text>Yes I was aware of it, but I got used to the Zone, I got careless.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_14">
		<text>Recklessly awesome of you, Strelok. You don't travel in the Zone alone, didn't you know that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_13">
		<text>Yes. Ghost and I were supposed to go together, but he got stuck at Yantar, I couldn't wait so I went alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_12">
		<text>Well, did you find out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_11">
		<text>No, it had nothing to do with the Brain Scorcher. I've been trying to figure out what the "Monolith" were doing at the Chernobyl NPP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_10">
		<text>What does that mean, the Radar got you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_9">
		<text>the "Monolith"s brainwashed me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_8">
		<text>Yeah, well finally, you got your memory back? I'm stunned. Well then, at least tell me something, where did you go when you disappeared and what happened to you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_7">
		<text>I remember absolutely everything. Chernobyl, and why I went there, and where the C-Consciousness are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_6">
		<text>Well, have you remembered something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_5">
		<text>I... I remember!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_4">
		<text>What, what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_3">
		<text>Wait a minute...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_2">
		<text>Wow, Strelok. You switched off, That's something I couldn't do. Are you all right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9_1">
		<text>Oh, that was something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_9">
		<text>Wait a minute, something is making me feel lousy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_8">
		<text>Strelok, what's happening? Are you alright?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_7">
		<text>Oh, shit, my head...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_6">
		<text>Hmm. In general, they're not at the Chernobyl NPP, it's not their main base. More precisely, if it was, you wouldn't have been able to get that far alone. You figured it out, then told me before you disappeared, saying that Chernobyl is one big smokescreen to lure anyone who tries to get to the truth about what is happening in the Zone into a trap. Supposedly, the legend of the Wish Granter is not real, it was intentionally made up so that stalkers who would try to get into the CNPP, would  fall into the clutches of the "Monolith". You threatened to tell everyone what actually happens there and how to get to the bottom of who is behind this. Well, we went there, and you disappeared.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_5">
		<text>Yeah, but I don't remember anything about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_4">
		<text>Holy shit, did you really hit your head so hard that you have forgotten everything? You scouted this place looking for them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_3">
		<text>Well, you could say that. In general, I can't find the C-Consciousness at Chernobyl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_2">
		<text>What happened? Is the "Legend of the Zone" having trouble, heh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_trader_dialog_4_1">
		<text>Hi, Dark Dealer. Listen, I need help with something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zdorovo_strelok">
		<text>Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otkuda_znaesh">
		<text>Who are you?! And how do you know I'm Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="my_zhe_sosedi">
		<text>Strelok, have you fallen from the moon, or just spent too much time at the Radar? I've previously lived in the hotel, right next to room 26. And now, as you see, I'm a new apartment... With view of the city... If you like, call me Dark Dealer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="strannyi_tip">
		<text>I have amnesia, I forgot a lot, now I'm slowly remembering. You're a strange one, you even know about room 26. Maybe we have met before, before I got to the "death truck"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="da_ne_boisya">
		<text>Well, in general... you assume... that we've met before. Honestly, it's not possible, I constantly heard about you - over the network. Anyway, had I known you, I would have been your enemy and shot you a long time ago. All the same, Strelok, and I didn't expect to see you alive. You'll need help - come on, you've started something heavy here, it will be a pleasure to watch. I've wanted to kick these fanatic's asses for a long time. Well, because of that, I decided to establish a small business here in Pripyat. Stalkers won't prevent the establishment a trading post in the Northern Zone now. I have items for sale, if you want to look.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_1_est_delicatnoe_delo">
		<text>I have one delicate task. We need to knock off a neutral stalker. His name is Arnie, he manages an establishment called the "Arena" in the Duty territory. He's a frequent visitor at the 100 Rads Bar. I think you know him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_1_znayu">
		<text>Yes, of course I know him. But why do you want him killed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_1_bereshsya">
		<text>Did you came here to ask questions or to make money? This guy, by the way, is not who he seems. But, I think you'll find out when you go to kill him... So, will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_1_nu_4to">
		<text>Oh yes, I've heard rumours that the manager of the Arena is dead. You did well, Strelok. Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_2_est_delicatnoe_delo">
		<text>Maybe you've done pretty well in your "career" with all your previous jobs. But I'm willing to offer you a really solid job. I have a job for a real professional. You must destroy... the leaders of the Freedom group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_2_znayu">
		<text>Are you crazy? They have a whole army at their base. How am I supposed to handle the whole group?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_2_bereshsya">
		<text>First, you don't have to deal with the whole group, only two - Lukash and Skinflint. And secondly, these scumbag Anarchists have deserved death for a long time. You, Strelok, are a Master nevertheless. Few people can deal with this job better than you. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_2_nu_4to">
		<text>Finally, these Freedom are finished. Without strong leadership, their group won't last long now. You did a fine job, Strelok. For you, apparently, taking out those two people in the middle of their base - was a piece of cake! Here's your reward...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_3_est_delicatnoe_delo">
		<text>Now, everyone knows that the leaders of the anarchists are dead. I'm very glad of this. But you must have already realised that General Voronin was next in my sights? He-he... Guess. What happens to Voronin now, depends on you, because he's your target. And Colonel Petrenko...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_3_znayu">
		<text>Hmm, the scale of your assignments doesn't surprise me. What did the Duty leader do to annoy you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_3_bereshsya">
		<text>You see, for all the purity, bravery and righteousness of Duty one small, but very unpleasant rottenness lies hidden. Duty is actually, none other than a militarized government espionage group which has only one purpose - to destroy the Zone and all that is connected with it. Namely, all of us. You and me as well. Don't ask me where I got this information. You accept the task or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_3_nu_4to">
		<text>Great! The leaders of Duty are dead, now it will begin - all the rest will tear each other apart in an instant for the sake of power. And I'm the only one who will benefit from it, he-he... For this, you deserve a considerable reward. Take it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_4_k_4emu_eto_vse">
		<text>Listen, what  other goals do you still pursue?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_4_a_ty_ne_ponyal">
		<text>What do you still not understand, Strelok? Apparently your head injury affected much more considerably. Now that you've killed the leaders of the major factions, their dealers and other hangers-on, which almost kept the old order - I now have the opportunity to establish a new world order! Admittedly, not without your help. He-he...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_4_raz_tak">
		<text>So, you just used me for your dirty games? I'm afraid I can't allow you to create this "new world order"...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_4_proshai">
		<text>You can't allow it? You want to stop me? You went for it, Strelok. You had a choice - to leave the Zone or at least to stop killing, "for the dubious benefits of this creature of darkness". Or, to be here in front of me, with blood on your hands... Your choice is obvious. And so are the consequences. I'm afraid, with your current reputation you won't last long... As for me and a new order - Hmm... was there actually a Dark Dealer?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_4_ne_ponyal">
		<text>I don't understand ... What do you mean, was there?</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

