	<string id="pri_decoder_docs_conclusion">
		<text>Pripyat stash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_decoder_docs_conclusion_txt">
		<text>The stash contained a short report on how Fang and I infiltrated the "Monolith" galleries under the station sarcophagus and found a suspicious-looking door. Fang said that he'd put together a decoder for the electronic lock for our next visit. After that we had to run for our lives. There were hordes of "Monolith" patrols there. Well. I also found the decoder in the stash and directions for finding the door. However, it seems that approaching the "Monolith" is extremely dangerous - last time we avoided going under the sarcophagus above the destroyed reactor and it seems that's where the "Monolith" is.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="pri_i_am_gunslinger_recall_article">
		<text>I'm Gunslinger!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_i_am_gunslinger_recall_txt">
		<text>There are no doubts. I remembered it all. Last year, in august, I, Ghost and Fang discovered that Brain Scorcher decreases its power strongly from time to time. May be it was due to unit cooling cycles. We broke through the center of the Zone in one of those moments. I still see enormous swarm of frigtened rats from CNPP in my dreams. When we found a suspicious door in CNPP and decided to go back and let Fang to make decoder for it, a Monolith patrol attacked us. I lost Ghost and Fang in battle and retreated to reactor hall of fourth unit. There was the sinister Monolith - "Wish Granter". I was wounded seriously, losing all my strength, but I can never forget the "Monolith"'s call. Finally I passed out and didn't make it to Monolith - that saved my life. Fang and Ghost found me and managed to bring me out of the station. I was unconscious and didn't remember this part clearly. Just remember arguing between my friends about me. Fang said that I can't make it, but Ghost pulled me out. Finally they broke through and brought me to Doctor. After I woke up, I headed to the North, but didn't reach the stash - surge happened. It brought me back to Doctor, being wounded again. Next time I finally reached the stash, but there were really bad news. Fang and Ghost decided to go back to CNPP without me and got into merc ambush. Fang died. I didn't wait Ghost in our stash (he was already dead in Yantar lab), just went back to CNPP there was another trap but nobody who can pull me out of there. Monolith washed my brain and I was sent back to the Zone in death truck with amnesia, tattoo on my hand and task to kill myself.</text>
	</string>	
