<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="dialog_guider_2_0">
		<text>Thank you for using my services. I've grown tired of being on the road. I'll sit down and have a rest ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_run_run_run_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>The motherfuckers, run quickly!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_run_run_run_dialog_1_1">
		<text>No time to explain! Come on, run! The military are planning a nuclear strike on the Generators!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_run_run_run_dialog_1">
		<text>What's going on, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_battle_run_run_run_dialog_0">
		<text>Marked One, it's great that I found you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dialog_guider_2_1">
		<text>Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_0">
		<text>Sidorovich, do you have some personal errands? I need money to repair my loot...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_1">
		<text>I'm always grateful for help with orders, but unfortunately, I have little. Here's what I can offer, choose:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_no_job">
		<text>No, no work for you yet.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Guitar Sidorovich -->
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_2">
		<text>Find the guitar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_3">
		<text>Several newcomers arrived the other day, well, they wanted to drink vodka and sing some songs so they asked for my guitar. They begged and pleaded, they swore they would look after it ... In short, I gave it to them. But they were bunglers, they got as drunk as skunks and misplaced the guitar somewhere here in the camp; now they cannot find it because they don't remember a damn thing ... Marked One, can you try to find it? There's a reward, of course, not great, but the case is also a piece of cake. It's a pity because the guitar is in good condition, not broken at all. It has sentimental value. Ask stalkers in camp, may be someone knows something.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- "Deal with the military" -->
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_5">
		<text>Do a deal with the military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_6">
		<text>We've got planned a small deal with a friendly representative of the local military forces, so to speak ... In short, we give him a dozen artifacts, and for them we get - a batch of new weapons, unrecorded. The military command mistakenly sent them, and they as usual - said nothing, he he. It's necessary to deliver a container of artifacts to the military under the bridge and collect the weapons in exchange. The box will be heavy of course, but you won't have to carry it back. Use the Zaporozhets that we have here in the camp to bring back the box of weapons from the bridge, Okay? It will be easier on you and I won't have to nurse you back to health after you've injured your back. So that's the deal, try to do it professionally... Well, will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_7">
		<text>I'll take it, where is the container ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_u_sidora_8">
		<text>That's good. So now go to Wolf - he'll give you the container. Bring the crate of weapons back to him.\nOh, and another thing: don't try to drive any other vehicle up to the military commander! I repeat, we have an arrangement that the messenger will come in a Zaporozhets. By the way, the rattletrap needs refuelling.\nWhat, did you expect that everything would be laid out on a silver platter? Well, good luck!\n Almost forgot! Here's your reward for the flash drive.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- "Rescue the stalker warriors from captivity at the checkpoint" -->
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_blockpost_plennik_0">
		<text>Rescue the prisoner from the checkpoint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_blockpost_plennik_1">
		<text>We had a novice here who decided to take a stroll... He thought he'd found a recreational park!.. In short, he stumbled upon a military patrol. But for some reason they didn't shoot him, they took him back to the checkpoint. I recently received an SOS signal from him, he said that he managed to escape from captivity but ran the wrong way. Now, to come back, he has to go through the checkpoint again and he said he can't cope with that. Marked One, I suggest you send the soldiers at the checkpoint to hell and save the poor soul. Naturally I don't expect you to assault the checkpoint all on your own. I will organize a special squad of 10 fighters, together you will quickly overpower the soldiers. Well, what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_blockpost_plennik_2">
		<text>So. Now I'll contact the special squad. They will wait for you to the east of the checkpoint, I threw their coordinates onto your PDA. You can go now. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- "Deal with the military" -->
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_0">
		<text>The military at the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_title">
		<text>The military at the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_find_military">
		<text>Determine why the military are at the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_tell_sidr">
		<text>Report to Sidorovich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvests_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_1">
		<text>So. I've been given information that a group of about five soldiers are hanging around near the camp. They seem to be looking for something in the gully with anomalies ... We ought to find out what they're looking for, or have found which is unlikely. Otherwise they would have left. In General, go and reconnoitre and find out what you can. But in any case don't shoot at them, understand ?! We don't need extra problems with the military. Get down to business?</text>
	</string>
	<!-- "Mercenaries at the Cordon" -->
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_start_0">
		<text>Mercenaries at the Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_start_1">
		<text>Recently, mercenaries were seen in the Cordon. They were moving north, and were later spotted in the forest at the Garbage. I was thinking: all this is no coincidence. We need to know what they are looking for. Generally you don't often see mercenaries here, they are clearly up to something. So I'm afraid we need to find out what their intentions are. Up to the challenge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_start_2">
		<text>I'll take it. What do I need to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_start_3">
		<text>I've got an idea ... Let's say we listen to them. I'll give you a directional microphone, through which we will be able to record their conversation. What are you smiling at? You seem surprised that I can come up with some good ideas! In short this: you need to get as close as possible to the mercenaries, without making any noise, and turn it on. Go on, get out of here. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- "Guest at the elevator" -->
	<string id="esc_start_kvest_qest_on_elevator_0">
		<text>Guest at the elevator.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_start_kvest_qest_on_elevator_1">
		<text>In general, this is the job: I heard a whisper that two novices noticed how someone sits and smokes in the attic of the grain elevator near the bridge. Clearly, they faded out of harms way - it was a convenient place for an ambush, and they didn't want to catch a stray bullet. Now I can't sleep, with such a suspicious situation so close  ... So find out what kind of mysterious guest had settled there and what the hell he's doing in the Cordon. Okay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_0">
		<text>Hey Barkeep, which of my faults were you thinking about when you decided to get rid of me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_1">
		<text>I ?! You ?! Don't give me that shit! Marked One, are you right in the head?! If I wanted you dead, you would not be standing here now and talking to me. Do you have reason to believe that I put a contract out on you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_2">
		<text>You'll love this here (show the rifle).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_3">
		<text>Yikes! So that's it... Hmm...\nWhere did you find this gun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_4">
		<text>Some guy at the Cordon tried to kill me with it, but after the first shot it exploded in his hands. The breach bolt shattered and blew off his head, so I couldn't ask him who he was working for. The rifle was lying beside the corpse. In your eyes I can see - you know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_5">
		<text>Yes, you're right - I do know something. Let me go on. I don't think anyone is hunting for you, Marked One. The stalker who shot at you - was a sniper, whom I hired to eliminate one man. It looks like he confused you with his real target.\nDamn it, now such turmoil will begin, you can't imagine...I'll be brief Marked One, and show you all my cards: It was necessary to have a stalker eliminated. It was ordered by serious people, and for a great deal of money. Apparently, this stalker seriously crossed their path. You understand, the customer didn't tell me all the details. I couldn't refuse him - it wouldn't have gone well for me. But at the same time, no one would have known that I had agreed. The contractor also had to go after the client.\nA local craftsman had made me some TNT cartridge. You know about these? A bullet fired from it flies in the same way as of conventional powder cartridge. But the explosion of TNT is so strong that it breaks the gun and kills the shooter. Everything would have turned out, but the sniper confused the target, the scumbag ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_6">
		<text>You bastard, Barkeep! I'll use this same rifle and make you a cripple for life!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_7">
		<text>Listen, don't get angry! Calm down, Okay? I had no choice - you can't say no to those people ... Marked One, now you know - I could use your help. At the same time I will share with you - a "surprise" as compensation. In such affairs one doesn't put a figure therefore as a last resort I employ a hitman. Your task is to remove this killer. But pay attention! It must be done only if he eliminates his target. That way no one will be the wiser. Don't think I don't have good reasons to remove him: if you fail, and then come back to me, I won't discuss the matter...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_8">
		<text>But the reward must be worthy. What is the purpose? What's he done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_9">
		<text>Yes it is. The stalker, as I understand it, found a passage to the Dead City. Fuck knows what deal he made to find out, but some people don't want him to get there. The passage, as I understand it, is through an old littered tunnel, and this dude planned to drag dynamite there so as to clear the blockage. The customer somehow found out about it and contacted me. I'm actually concerned myself, that he does not get there - that place is terrible, Marked One, there is nothing good to be found there... A passage through to there for us would be of no use, there is only crap to be found there... There you have it. Go now to the Cordon and remember: don't kill the assassin before he removes his target. So, I've forgotten nothing. And yes, I'm going to mark his position on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_10">
		<text>I killed the sniper and his target is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_11">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One, I never doubted you.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- We pass / fail the quest -->
	<string id="esc_complete_kvests_u_sidora_0">
		<text>I'm on the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_complete_kvests_u_sidora_1">
		<text>Which job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_complete_kvests_u_sidora_2">
		<text>About the guitar. I refuse to do it it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_complete_kvests_u_sidora_2_1">
		<text>About the guitar. Got it, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_complete_kvest_search_guitar">
		<text>Well, thank you, Marked One! I got my guitar after all. Here's a small gift for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_complete_kvests_u_sidora_7">
		<text>About the deal with the military. I refuse to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_complete_kvests_u_sidora_8">
		<text>About the deal with the military. It's done, "parcel delivered to the addressee," so to speak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_failorcom_0">
		<text>About the captive. I refuse to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_failorcom_1">
		<text>About the captive. I rescued him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_complete_0">
		<text>Good for you Marked One, well done! You kicked those warrior's asses! He he. Here's your well earned reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_complete_1">
		<text>Thank you! I will go now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_complete_2">
		<text>While I was looking for the captive, I found this military report. Take, you may find it useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_complete_3">
		<text>Thanks Marked One. I have yet to study the document. Here, take something else from me. A Medal of vigilance, so to speak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_complete_0">
		<text>As for the Soldiers at the anomaly. They found some artifact there, but are afraid to touch it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_start_2">
		<text>Interesting ... Listen, get me that artifact! Maybe it's valuable - I should be able to sell it to the scientists and earn good money. Since the soldiers have not picked it up, quietly sneak in, grab it and bring it here. Look, only don't shoot the soldiers... at least not at first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_complete_1">
		<text>About the soldiers in the anomaly. I got the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_completed">
		<text>Hmm, strange thing, very unusual. So rare. However, no benefit from it, as far as I know, but I will sell it to the scientists, and they will pay decent money for it. Take your share ... Good work! You - are a good fellow, you continue to please the old man...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_fail">
		<text>About the soldiers in the anomaly. I refuse to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_kvest_killers_mined_lager_complete_0">
		<text>About the Mercenaries at the Cordon. Well, let's hear what you managed to record...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_kvest_killers_mined_lager_fail">
		<text>About the Mercenaries at the Cordon. I refuse to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_kvest_killers_mined_lager_complete_1">
		<text>Holy shit! They'll pay for this ... Can you imagine, those freaks planted a bomb somewhere in our camp! Resentful fucking assholes. I broke off selling them arms a month ago, you see, they want to kill me now, along with the entire camp. Marked One, help me out! We need to find the bomb urgently and defuse it. Do it, I'll pay! But hurry, Okay? I'm afraid it will blow up soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_kvest_killers_mined_lager_complete_2">
		<text>Roger, I'll look for the bomb.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_kvest_killers_mined_lager_allcomplete">
		<text>About the Mercenaries at the Cordon. Everything is done: the bomb is defused, the mercenaries have been put down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_kvest_killers_mined_lager_2_complete">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One, you saved the whole camp. And an old man ... whose life was tattered and moth eaten, so to speak, he he ... For good work a good reward! You deserve it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_complete_0">
		<text>About the Guest at the elevator. I completed it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_complete_1">
		<text>About the Guest at the elevator. I refuse to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_complete_2">
		<text>Well, what was there? Did you find something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_complete_3">
		<text>There was some guy there, he tried to shoot me down. But his first shot was his last - the rifle blew the hell out and killed him. Here's his rifle, look at this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_complete_4">
		<text>Hmm ... not a bad gun. Oh my, what's this scratch on the butt? ...\nHey, this is Barkeep's brand. This is clearly his rifle. Strange thing, he doesn't usually give anyone his weapons... It is necessary to find out who he was, where he got the rifle and who told him to shoot you. Go to Barkeep and show it to him. Consider it a task. I think you don't mind going there to get some explanations, he he.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_complete_5">
		<text>To Barkeep? Okay, I'll kill the bastard!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- "We take the dynamite for Wolf" -->
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_take_dinamyte_0">
		<text>I need to take your box with artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_take_dinamyte_1">
		<text>Yes, I know. Here you go. Carry this container of artifacts to the military, who are under the bridge, they are waiting. Pick up a box of weapons, and bring it back to me. That's all.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- We give the dynamite -->
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_0111">
		<text>Whoa!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_0112">
		<text>Here, I've brought a box of weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_0113">
		<text>Good for you, Marked One, good job. Go to Sidorovich for your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_0">
		<text>It's about the deal. I've brought the container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_1">
		<text>Show me ... So, yeah ... One, two, three ... uh huh ... uh huh ... five, ten, yes. All right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_2">
		<text>Well, see you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_3">
		<text>Glad to hear it. Where is my box with the weapons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_4">
		<text>Don't worry, I've already loaded it into your tumbled-down car.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_41">
		<text>Listen, you have the wrong vehicle. We need to put something in the trunk, but it won't fit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_5">
		<text>In that case, it's time for me to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_6">
		<text>Don't worry, I have the box. Now remind those in the bunker: did they know that under the contract, you had to have to a particular vehicle to come here? I'll tell Sidorovich, why he was left without weapons. You are to blame.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_71">
		<text>It broke down, now it's just a useless pile of junk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_72">
		<text>Well, if it is necessary, I'll get another one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_81">
		<text>No, that will not do. I know the Zaporozhets, I sold it to him three months ago. And I have a contract with Sidorovich - All transportation is to be done with this machine, so I know what it's going to his people, and not some thug. Today, you drag the box to the bandits, and tomorrow we are ... under attack with our own weapons and you get away scot-free. No, that won't do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_82">
		<text>Bite the bullet! You can't have one foot on each side of the fence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_83">
		<text>--- Here is the text was not yet inserted. In general, the failure of this idiotic quest should be removed .--- Filon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_01">
		<text>The car is in place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_11">
		<text>What "place"? Come over here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_12">
		<text>Okay, now bring the box over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_trunk_0">
		<text>So, I've freed a little space in the trunk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_trunk_11">
		<text>All right, my soldiers have already loaded the crate into your car. You can go now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_trunk_12">
		<text>Come on! We need more space. Throw out the trash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_something_happend_0">
		<text>So, where were we?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_give_dinamyte_something_happend_1">
		<text>In fact, you gave me a bag.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- We talk to a special squad -->
	<string id="esc_talk_with_specotryad_0">
		<text>Well, are you ready to make some noise?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_specotryad_1">
		<text>Yes, we are ready. We can go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_specotryad_2">
		<text>Let's move out.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- We speak with the prisoner -->
	<string id="esc_talk_with_plennik_of_blockpost_0">
		<text>Hi! I've been looking for you. Why are you stuck here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_plennik_of_blockpost_1">
		<text>Phew, well, finally. I thought that I would have to hang around here forever. On the one hand - a portal, on the other - a military checkpoint, I didn't know which way to go. I fled here from the soldiers, but I went in the wrong direction, I was confused with fear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_plennik_of_blockpost_2">
		<text>Wow. Okay, let's go, I'll take you to the novice's camp</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Give vodka for the Old warriors "they do have anomalies" -->
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_0">
		<text>Hey soldier, what are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_1">
		<text>Get out of here before you catch a bullet! None of your damn business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2">
		<text>I'm going, going ... just don't get nervous!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_3">
		<text>Come on... Can't we talk? I'm very interested!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_4">
		<text>The parasite is curious, and...don't you have anything better to do? Well, fuck it - we're tired of hanging around and not being able to leave. Do us a favour - bring a bottle of vodka, and some snacks with that... mmm... Well, let's say, three loaves of bread and two sticks of sausage. Then I can, enlighten you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_5">
		<text>Here, two sticks of sausage and three loaves of bread. With vodka, as ordered. Well?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_6">
		<text>I don't have much food with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_7">
		<text>Too bad, then I have nothing more to say. Move on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_8">
		<text>Oh, thank you ... Heh, I actually just wanted to have some fun with you ... Well, okay, quid pro quo. Our helicopter crews have complained that here, in this small sector, strong radio interference occurs. Well, we were sent here to find out why. We searched back and forth... in short, we found a strange artifact. It emits strong radiation, and when you get near it you start to feel strange - feeling sick and dizzy. Here we stand, protecting it from the hands of others - suddenly it has become valuable, heh. We could make some money then... Okay, now you can go. If we see you here again, you'll have problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2_0">
		<text>Would you like me to help you get the artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2_1">
		<text>Well, actually, we wouldn't refuse your help... But that's one thing I don't understand: Why would you suddenly want to help us, knowing that you could catch a decent dose of radiation? Heh, by any chance, did you bump your head recently?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2_2">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2_3">
		<text>Well, actually, it's not that simple....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2_4">
		<text>Back to business... I decided to hit a jackpot. Well, why not. Go on, get out there and grab it for me, then I'll give you something useful for it. We have a special containment box, it will secure the artifact. And don't be silly, we are all nervous and sick of being here: try to steal it - and we will shoot you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_2_5">
		<text>Okay, I'm going, I'll try to pick it up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_3_0">
		<text>I got the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_3_1">
		<text>Wow! You look a little pale, are you okay? All right, hand it over before you start turning green.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_3_2">
		<text>Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_3_3">
		<text>No, you can't have it. I picked it up, so I'm keeping it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_anmaly_military_leader_3_4">
		<text>Well, thanks for helping, stalker. I didn't expect it. You saved us a lot of time while we waited for the research group in special suits to show up... I would have turned grey waiting here, heh! Here, take a bit of loot in gratitude from me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_military_near_anomaly_dialog_with_private_0">
		<text>Get out of here stalker, before you get shot!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_military_near_anomaly_dialog_with_private_1">
		<text>Oh, what a nerve! I'm going, going ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_0">
		<text>Hi! Why are you sitting there alone, why don't you come to the camp?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_1">
		<text>Well ... Fanatic is mad at me ... He gave me a task - to bring him a "Night Star" artifact urgently ... I failed. Now, because of me, he has problems and I cannot go back to camp. Fanatic is ferocious, he said: "I won't let you return until you bring the "Night Star", I'm very disappointed in you - and the customer is angry"... Just get one from somewhere, I don't care where. \n
		But I had thought it all out: I knew where to find the artifact, I waited a moment, then went to pick it up. I had gone thirty metres and saw how it glowed, I climbed through the bushes... And then suddenly a stalker hopped out of nowhere - grabbed my artifact and stuffed it into a container. At the same time: BANG! He caught a bullet. I looked - it was bandits. The reptiles waited until he pulled it out of the anomaly, then shot him. They hadn't noticed me hiding in the bushes, and after they shot him, I immediately took cover. They searched the poor guy, took the artifact away and went towards the Cordon. Well, I quietly followed them - hoping I might get the opportunity to steal their artifact container. But no - they went to the Darkscape at settled the gas station... I was afraid to get close to them, and catch a bullet. That's it. I didn't get the artifact from them, so I can't go back to camp. So I sit here alone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_2">
		<text>Okay, well, see you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_3">
		<text>You know, I can help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_4">
		<text>You can? Listen, I'll be very grateful if you help. Go, try to get the artifact from the bandits. Perhaps you can persuade them so there's no need to take it by force - they don't carry valuable things around, for certain they've already hidden in a secret place somewhere. I'll throw the coordinates of the location on your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_5">
		<text>Good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_start_6">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_0">
		<text>Halt simpleton! You've got balls! What are you doing here? On business, or are you tired of living?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_1">
		<text>Hmm, and Hello to you too. I'm here on business. I've heard you have "a Night Star" artifact here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_2">
		<text>What we have is our business, and who are you, dickhead? You ask questions like a cop...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_3">
		<text>This artifact is needed by a serious man. I came to get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_4">
		<text>Well, fuck your crusade. Do you expect me to drop everything straight away? Get out of here while you still have your balls!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_5">
		<text>Come on, calm down, we're reasonable people. What do you want for it? Money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_6">
		<text>No, the loot is not mine, but we can agree on a settlement. But I see you're a quick fellow ... Let's play for life. Not up to it, simpleton? If you guess the riddle, I'll give you the artifact, if not - we will shoot you, and we won't even bury you. Well then, we play?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_7">
		<text>I will not guess any riddles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_8">
		<text>Well, tell your puzzle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_9">
		<text>Now, listen, simpleton:\nThere are fifty lit candles in the room, clumsy Vladimir, the bent idiot, crashes into them and twenty blow out. How many candles will remain?\nLook, think carefully simpleton, don't miscalculate...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_10">
		<text>30 candles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_11">
		<text>20 candles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_12">
		<text>50 candles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_13">
		<text>Dope... that's not right! A deal - is a deal. Hold on, simpleton, now we will cut you down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_14">
		<text>You're right on! You guess was correct. In reality, the rest of the candles will burn down. I see that you're not just a fuck-up. Well, friend, we have been entertained. Okay, take your artifact and get out of here while I'm good in a good mood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_15">
		<text>I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_with_bandit_16">
		<text>Thanks for the hospitality.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_end_1">
		<text>I got the artifact from the bandits, here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_talk_end_2">
		<text>Thank you brother, you helped me a lot. Take this from me, as thanks for your help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_0">
		<text>... But how? How to do it? I can't imagine...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_1">
		<text>Hey man, what's wrong?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_2">
		<text>Sorry, but when I'm nervous, I talk to myself...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_3">
		<text>And the reason for this nervousness, if it's not a secret? However, it's none of my business, of course...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_4">
		<text>It's no big secret... Any help would be appreciated. Well, listen. I had a friend... his name was Figa. The other day, I met him in the territory of the Bar: you could see the fire in his eyes, his movements were sharp ... I realized at once - that Figa had discovered something interesting. Alright. He came across something unusual at Yantar and came looking for me, so we could go and reconnoiter together. I had just returned from a raid, and wanted to rest. The guy didn't want to wait, he said that he could cope alone. He never returned...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_5">
		<text>Hmm, sad story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_6">
		<text>Listen ... Help me find my friend! Let's go to the factory together, together we can find him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_7">
		<text>No, it's too dangerous, I can't help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_8">
		<text>I'd love to help, but how are we going to get there? The plant is full of mutant zombies! They'll send us to hell!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_9">
		<text>I'm racking my brain on how to get there quietly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_10">
		<text>Quietly? In a crowd of zombies and snorks? Well, well, I think you should think further. But in this case. I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_start_11">
		<text>Quietly you say ... I have an idea! I'll go to Sakharov, he may be able to suggest something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_0">
		<text>Professor, is there a possibility to fool the zombies and mutants, so they don't attack people? I'm sure you have been asked this question before...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_1">
		<text>If you're wondering, this is a key point in ensuring the safety of our laboratory. Alas, detailed consideration has shown that: Mutants only attack objects whose aura lacks certain information. All the creatures have a "Learning Zone", so to speak. So the only way to avoid an attack - is to change the aura of the object. In a word, become a zombie. \nIncidentally, in the process of studying the impact of psi-emissions on living organisms, we have developed a serum in our laboratory that, when ingested by a human, creates an experimental zombie. It solved the problem of a shortage of biological material - you know, the mere trapping of mutants did not meet the needs of laboratory to the full. This serum increases the body's sensitivity to a range of psycho-waves, inducing a state of "light" zombification of the subject. It is noteworthy that the effect of the serum is only temporary and does not result in death of the animal. However, human trials have not yet been done, of course. Thus, the answer to your question: Theoretically it's possible, but it can have quite dangerous consequences for humans. Why are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_2">
		<text>Another stalker and I need to become zombies, it's very important. Help, please, Professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_3">
		<text>A strange request... I should dissuade you from this idea... But I'm afraid if I don't help you, then you are likely to succumb to radiation and become a zombie. This wouldn't end well... Okay, I will prepare the desired serum for you. But for that, I need a sample of water from the lake at Yantar: I've run out of suitable samples, and this eliminates the need for replenishment - our research has moved to a new level.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_4">
		<text>What kind of water is it? And where can I get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_5">
		<text>This water contains unusual neurotoxins formed during prolonged exposure to radiation. In any case, you shouldn't drink it, as it causes reactions that increase the susceptibility to the influence of psi. Not to mention the inevitable content of various impurities, including poisons. Bring it to me, and I will prepare a serum for you, the use of which will cause you to go into state similar to that of a zombie, but only temporarily. You can get the water from a small swamp not far from here, near the crashed helicopter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_6">
		<text>I'll get you the water.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_7">
		<text>Wait, don't rush. I'll give you a flask for the water. Be careful, that swamp is not safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_give_kilba_to_sahar_0">
		<text>I got the water. Here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_give_kilba_to_sahar_1">
		<text>So, let me have a look ... Yes, that's what I need, the water is perfect for the preparation of the serum.\nNow I'll mix all the necessary ingredients and the serum will be ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_give_kilba_to_sahar_2">
		<text>[Wait]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_give_kilba_to_sahar_3">
		<text>The serum is ready. Once you take the drug, you may become ill. It's not dangerous and will change within a minute. When the serum wears off, zombies will attack. Be careful not to miss the moment of the serum's expiration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_give_kilba_to_sahar_4">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_letsgo_0">
		<text>Well, were you successful?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_letsgo_1">
		<text>Shall we get on with it? Let's drink the serum! I'll be right behind you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_letsgo_2">
		<text>All right, all right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_0">
		<text>Listen, I seem to have found a way to get into the factory!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_1">
		<text>How?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_2">
		<text>Sakharov produced a serum which will turn us into temporary zombies. While we're in this state, zombies and snorks will leave us alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_3">
		<text>Dumb idea, but damn it, let's try. There doesn't seem to be any other way. You have the first drink and I'll have the remainder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_4">
		<text>All right, now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_5">
		<text>I think... we have... a chance. We can go... to the factory... to look for Figa...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_6">
		<text>Come on... hurry!..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_7">
		<text>Ha ha ha!... Ah Ha Ha Ha!..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_8">
		<text>Figa!.. Can you talk?... Do you know... Chuck?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_9">
		<text>Chuck!... Brother!... Good to see him... Hmm...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_10">
		<text>The Secret... Of Yantar... Tell me?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_11">
		<text>Yes... Cache... Territory... Bar, where the fuzz... fuzz burns... painfully... Big safe...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_12">
		<text>Hold on... let me... help you... get out... we have... to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_13">
		<text>I'm dying...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_14">
		<text>Strelok... thank you... You go... I'll stay!.. I need... to bury Figa... while I'm still... a zombie...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_15">
		<text>Don't stay... here for too long... you'll die...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_0">
		<text>Hi! What are you doing here? Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_dead_stalker_start_dialog_1_second_1_1">
		<text>Clearly, you have troubled look. Do you want to ask something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_1">
		<text>I'm - Dead Stalker. I'm known by this nickname because I look like a corpse, having spent so much time in the dungeons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2">
		<text>How did you get there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_3">
		<text>Long story, are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_4">
		<text>Yes, I found some documents... Project "C-Consciousness", heard anything about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_5">
		<text>Found? Really ... Let me guess, Sample "O-21"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_6">
		<text>How do you know about that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_7">
		<text>I was part of those awful experiments. During the experiment, our minds were merged, completely losing our individual will... And believe me, I was not happy with all this. We experienced strange pressure on our minds, sometime later. Almost all the test subjects became thoroughly addicted with the obsession - to create an ideal world, becoming Gods in it. It seemed the only way they could achieve this - was to give up their identities, and merge into a single super being. This idea to us was intentionally introduced to us, it seems tried to make our brains something like a very powerful computer, having turned us into an impersonal appendage. It was terrifying, I struggled and resisted. But what could I change? I had barely enough strength to struggle to cling on to the fleeting remnants of myself... I resisted as well as I could - but my head went to pieces at the same time: I have seen such horrific hallucinations that I've screamed in terror and wanted to die. My mind saw fragments of the future - I saw the Zone, long before it appeared. But the heartless scientists, who only  saw us as lab rats, decided that my psyche was not strong enough to  withstand the experiment, transferred me here - to the X-18.\n
		So I came here, and kept my mind. I don't know what happened to the rest. And yet, this group of scientists had created a sample of "O-21" that you found...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_8">
		<text>An atrocity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_9">
		<text>Oh, do not say ... But "O-21" is a beautiful trap, which has some kind of donor relationship with the C-Consciousness. With it you think clearer and have better ideas, but it can drive you crazy, infecting your brain with notions about the "ideal world." But the longer you interact with it, the worse you will be... I sometimes call myself, "Seeing Stone" because of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_10">
		<text>What should we do with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_11">
		<text>Well, we should - destroy it. It's too dangerous. But that is not so simple. The sample material is only halfway complete, and trying to destroy it, won't work. However, there is a place where it can be destroyed. I have no idea where it is, and certainly can't imagine what it's called. But I can clearly see its outlines: somewhere in the rocky terrain is an anomaly, like a small pool. It seems there was an evacuation attempt nearby, but apparently it was unsuccessful ... I see a half-destroyed bus, abandoned vehicles and construction equipment. This anomaly - was one of the first in the area and is very strong. It is able to consume "O-21", destroying it without a trace. Although, you know, you can make a choice. Some have sold the soul of this sample.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_12">
		<text>I'll find this place and destroy the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_13">
		<text>Well, good luck, Stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2_0">
		<text>Well, it's over. I destroyed Sample "O-21".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2_1">
		<text>Destroyed? Really. This is great news. I didn't even believe that you would succeed. Lucky you.\nBy the way, I forgot to tell you. Those records that you found in Professor Thompson's  cache are very important to the scientists. I advise you to give these records to Sakharov. Maybe the scientists can decipher some very important data from the records. And you can get a good reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2_2">
		<text>No, I better hold on to these notes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2_3">
		<text>Well, I'll take these notes to Sakharov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2_4">
		<text>Well, as you wish. In your place, I would take these notes to the scientists immediately.\nThank you once again for destroying Sample "O-21". I'm very grateful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_dstalker_2_5">
		<text>Have a good trip. \nThank you once again for destroying Sample "O-21". I'm very grateful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_bring_zapisi_complete_0">
		<text>I brought you some of professor Thompson's notes. Perhaps they will be useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_bring_zapisi_complete_1">
		<text>Let me see... Hmm... These records reveal a lot of detail about what happened in the X-16 lab here at Yantar. I'll study them. Thank you very much, Strelok. Take this device as a reward for the information, it will useful to you in the Zone. It detects all forms of life. If you need additional life-form signatures for it, I always have the firmware in stock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_letter_title">
		<text>Wisher: Find the missing piece of code.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_letter_find_letter">
		<text>Find the missing piece of code.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_letter_article_descr">
		<text>Wisher said that the missing part of the code can be found in the house where I originally found Minor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_get_pda_monolit">
		<text>"Monolith"'s PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_password">
		<text>Password for the Radar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_password_article_descr">
		<text>Password to deactivate the bomb in the control room at the Radar - 14539782568.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_12_1_2_1">
		<text>Is it suitable?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_12_1_2">
		<text>Hurry up, so I don't die instantly, the City is full of zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_12_1_1">
		<text>Yes, just right!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_12_1_1_2">
		<text>Well, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_12_1">
		<text>Well, I'll see what I have so I could give you a weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_0">
		<text>Uh, thank you for saving me. I thought I'd be stuck here forever. We need to get out of here before the "Monolith" spot us. Are you coming?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_12_1_2_1_1">
		<text>Damn, look again, maybe you have something more decent?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_1">
		<text>I rescued you for a reason. I was told that you know the second part of the code from the briefcase.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_3">
		<text>Well, stalker, thank you for saving me. Write down the second part of the code, it sounds like this: "2568".\nNow listen carefully. You already know that if you turn off the switch, the trap is triggered. The first part of the password you have, the second I gave you. Before turning off the main switch don't forget to enter the password into the computer, located in front of the circuit breaker.\nGoodbye, and good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_6">
		<text>Excellent, thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_2">
		<text>Ah, so you're the one! Yes, I know the second part of the code. But first, let's get far away from this place, I need to get to go to the Military Warehouses, and then I'll tell you the second part of the password. Just give me a weapon, I've been without one for a long time, and I have no ammunition left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_not_complete">
		<text>Yes? Is there something you wanted to say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_4">
		<text>Yeah, thank you and good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="x10_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_5">
		<text>Hey!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Yeah, it's a little problem. Okay, wait, don't despair. Maybe I'll think of something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_1_1_1_1">
		<text>They call me Minor. This building is a spatial trap. It's impossible to get out of here, I'm worn out trying. Every time I try, I get thrown back. I've been sitting here for more than a day. Damn it, I came looking for artifacts, and like an idiot, got stuck here. It looks like we're stuck here together now. Do you have any food? We could last a little longer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>How come you're here? Who are you, and what's going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_talk_with_svyaznoy_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Oh, Hey! You shouldn't have come here, buddy. You won't get out of here now. Now there're two of us, I'm not so afraid to die.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="search_code2_meet_with_svyaznoi_text">
		<text>Plans have changed, the agent wasn't there, he didn't arrive at the appointed time. His last communique came from the Dead City. This is a dangerous place, I have a suspicion that something is wrong here. It is in our best interest to rescue the agent. Beware of the "Monolith", their spies operate throughout the City.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_spawn_letter_in_treasure_text">
		<text>Perfect! Well, just great! You didn't save Minor, damn it, it's necessary to improvise. Well, what happened, happened. If you need the missing portion of the code - look in the house where Minor was supposed to be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_scoryi_0">
		<text>Listen, man, the medkit won't help, I will die anyway, but promise me that you'll perform my last request! I beg you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_scoryi_1">
		<text>Of course I will! Ask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_scoryi_2">
		<text>Man, I'm sorry, but I'm too busy, I can't help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_scoryi_3">
		<text>Thank you. I believed that there were good people in this world. So, we, that is, Bulrush and I, were returning from a raid. The amount of loot was - absurd. Earlier I had a bad premonition... Then it happened. We were on our way to Sidorovich, we only had a little way to go when Bulrush shot me in the back. I lost consciousness, and he thought I was done for, so he took the loot and disappeared. I pulled myself together, sent a SOS signal SOS, and to my relief, you arrived. Listen, find this reptile and take my share away from him. No need to kill him, just take my share and send it to my wife. My daughter is sick. She needs surgery. Because of Bulrush, this would be my last raid. The money is just enough. I beg you, for God's sake, send the money to my wife. Here's my PDA, it has the address where you can send money ... Do it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_scoryi_4">
		<text>Hey, hey, stalker, hold on... Now I'll give you something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_01">
		<text>Oh, Marked One, finally you came. I've been waiting for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_0">
		<text>You said you had a small job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_1">
		<text>Yes it's a breeze. A lone stalker wound up here... a very suspicious person, with a no less suspicious appearance. We saw him at the farm in the Dark: sitting Valley, frowning as if contemplating something, and went to the factory three timed that day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_2">
		<text>So, what's so strange about that? Can't a stalker go to the factory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_3">
		<text>It's not that. There, at the factory in the Dark Valley, we spotted some movement - maybe mercenaries or monolith had settled there. We couldn't get a better look at what he was up to - he moved across enemy territory, then disappeared. But that's not all. The same stalker was seen repeatedly under the bridge at the military checkpoint. There he talked with Kuznetsov about something. \n... In general, dark doings, Marked One. I don't like it. After the military raid on the bandit's base in the Dark Valley everything settled down, and the military became more active there - Kuznetsov has already sent soldiers to the base three times that was unscheduled. Here and there groups of soldiers intersect. Helicopters are circling like they're looking for something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_4">
		<text>So-oo. As soon as I leave you alone, you start to brew up something. Let me guess: this job is tied up with what you're brewing? Is it not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_5">
		<text>No, not at all! I told you it was easy - Just follow the stalker as he goes back and forth. See what he does at the factory. If the soldiers under the bridge are not angry with you, then try to talk with Kuznetsov, he can tell you interesting things. Tell me the results. The size of your reward depends on the results. In any case, Anyway I won't offend, you know me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esckvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_6">
		<text>I know I know. Well, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_0">
		<text>Look, Sidorovich, did a certain Bulrush come here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_1">
		<text>Why? You know, I never give out customer's names. Well, almost never.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_2">
		<text>That's right, almost. I need this man, Sidorovich. He shot his partner so he could steal their loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_3">
		<text>Where did you get this information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_4">
		<text>His partner, that Bulrush mortally wounded, the poor man stayed alive long enough to tell me. He was saving the money for his daughter's operation. His last raid was indeed his last. I promised to fulfil his last request - to get his share of the money from Bulrush, and send it to his widow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_5">
		<text>Well, yes, of course! If you want, I can tell you a dozen similar stories. They will bring a tear to your eyes - even hardened criminals have cried... This is not your first day in the Zone, Marked One! I am amazed how you believe in such nonsense?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_6">
		<text>Here, look - The stalkers PDA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_7">
		<text>... Hmm ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_8">
		<text>Convinced?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_9">
		<text>Okay. Let us assume that I believe you. But all the same, if you don't perform a task I gave you, I won't tell. The information can be payment for your labour. Or pay the money. One thousand two hundred. Ha-ha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_10">
		<text>Well, you toad, Sidorovich!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_11">
		<text>But, but ... You do it, so don't get cocky. And yet, how could it be otherwise? In my profession, it happens all the time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_0">
		<text>How business?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_1">
		<text>I'm not accountable to you. Do you want to pay for passage? Then pay. So come on, hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_2">
		<text>Oh ... And I've got some vodka. Let's drink to the valiant military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_3">
		<text>Vodka, you say? Well, so should have said so sooner. We certainly could use a drink. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_4">
		<text>Here it is, major. So what can you tell me? How's things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_5">
		<text>Worse than ever. The administration has started something, and there making us all nervous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_6">
		<text>What are they doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_7">
		<text>I can't tell you. All I can say, is that things will start to heat up very soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_8">
		<text>You really won't tell me? Is it not a Military secret?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_9">
		<text>All the same, I still can't say. I didn't tell you anything. What I blurted out, was superfluous!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_10">
		<text>Okay, okay, don't get angry. And how are things with the stalkers? They bother you, I suppose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_11">
		<text>And how. There's a loner who comes here, begging rounds. Many come begging. Here I am, at the same time, a soldier with a requisition for more ammo. The main warehouse keeps asking us why we require so many supplies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_12">
		<text>You be careful, or they will close you down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_13">
		<text>I have the same feeling.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_about_sitnik_kuzn_14">
		<text>Well, good luck to you. I've got to run.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_0">
		<text>Come, let's talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_1">
		<text>Where's my gear? Who put me here? What's going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_2">
		<text>Don't panic. I'll tell you everything. So, in case you haven't noticed, there are a lot of strange things happening in the district. There is a reason for this - the military are planning a special major operation. Frankly, I don't know what they intend to bring into the Zone, but it has the "Monolith" running scared. In general, they see this as a direct threat to the Zone and to their own very existence. Therefore the "Monolith" are planning a counter operation whose main objective  is not to allow the device to pass into the Zone. The mercenaries pursue a somewhat different cause - they don't care about the Zone, they just want to steal the device - apparently to fill somebody's order. Thus, the interests of two powerful groups are met, and, most importantly, they don't contradict, but complement each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_3">
		<text>Now I know, however. Let's deal with this. We'll have to think - what to do about it. Come on. How do you know all this? How did you get involved, and why did you go to military under the bridge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_4">
		<text>I got involved in the most direct way. I was hired for a lot of money to play the role of "negotiator", so to speak. There is this one guy, with the military under the bridge. Alexander Ovechkin - he's in good standing with Kuznetsov. Whether monolith or mercenary, this clown couldn't tell them apart, but he managed to recruit them  I don't know how, but for a "mole", he's doing well. I had come for cartridges. Kuznetsov sent someone to the base and while I waited for the order, Ovechkin was supposedly talking peacefully with me on the sidelines. In fact, he gave me all the necessary information. Sometimes Kuznetsov sent Ovechkin to the base. That's when I got to know the latest facts "first hand." Getting cartridges was a needed distraction for him to get information. Well that, and to a lesser extent, to strengthen the combat potential of mercenary and monolith troops..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_5">
		<text>I had fun with you. Now for the big question. Why the hell are you telling me all this? What's the catch? I'm about to be executed, and you have decided to tell me the truth before this monumentous event?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_6">
		<text>No catch. Think of it like this  I woke up with a conscience. Yes, don't laugh. You see, once upon a time I defended people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_7">
		<text>Where you a cop?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_8">
		<text>Sort of. I have not worked in my profession for many years, I turned a blind eye to all that was happening around me. But now - it's over. I don't do this anymore. There's too much turmoil now to ignore. After all, if the "Monolith" are frightened of that damn thing the military has dragged in the Zone,  it's possible to assume that it's some sort of weapon. And a powerful weapon at that. If this military weapon fell into the hands of the mercenaries or anyone else, it could cause a lot of problems. This cannot be allowed to happen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_9">
		<text>Listen, do you really believe that ... How many of them? Twenty, thirty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_10">
		<text>Thirty. A total of thirty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_11">
		<text>Well... Do you believe, that thirty people can cause enough damage to the entire military expedition? Surely the soldiers will have helicopter gun-ships and BTRs to protect them... And their number of personnel ... is not small.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_12">
		<text>If only it were so simple. The "Monolith"s are cunning pricks, they've dug up some psi-unit from an unknown underground laboratory. I don't know in what condition it was, or whether they had to fix it, but it works. And it works only on mutants. the "Monolith" say that all they need. Mutants have always been abundant in the Dark Valley and the Garbage. Install the unit in the right place, they can provoke a so-called "rutting season". Have you ever seen it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_13">
		<text>I heard of it, but never seen it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_14">
		<text>Well, I have. I can assure you, the "Monolith" will have a certain advantage. All that will remain of the expedition will be a few body parts. This is very dangerous shit, that the mercenaries have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_15">
		<text>What do you suggest? Once you have freed me, you have a plan, I hope?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_16">
		<text>No, no plan as such. But there is a goal that must be achieved - we must disrupt the plans of the mercenaries and monolith.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_17">
		<text>Commendable. First. I need my gear returned. Secondly - it is necessary to warn the military. I doubt that the two of us can overcome thirty well-trained fighters alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_18">
		<text>At the factory, they're not up to strength. There's just some top-brass and a dozen fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_19">
		<text>Whatever. All the same, it's an unnecessary risks. We need to find a simpler way. But it's necessary that military believe us. Any idea where we can get evidence that they are preparing an ambush?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_20">
		<text>The chief of the mercenaries has a laptop. Surely there is enough stored entertaining information. You'll find all your gear in Borov's box.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_21">
		<text>Clear. I need to get my belongings before we enter the factory. You distract the main mercenary, and I will try to grab the laptop from his desk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_22">
		<text>Move. There's a dead bandit up ahead, take his suit and then you can go for your things. Then we'll move to the factory. I will say that you are my assistant, because that amount of ammo is heavy to lug around by yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_23">
		<text>Okay!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_23___2">
		<text>So, we're almost there. Follow me and stay close. I'll take you into the mercenaries main office, well, you know what to do - you pinch the laptop and then we get the hell out of there. Then we'll tell the military everything. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_0">
		<text>It's urgent we notify military command that the convoy with the cargo will be attacked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_1">
		<text>Are you crazy? Who would believe me? And why should I believe you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_2">
		<text>Here's the laptop of the advance party commander of mercenaries and monoliths. It contains more evidence than you think.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_3">
		<text>Um ... Jeez!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_4">
		<text>Report it! What are you waiting for? Your "secret operation" will most invariably end in failure, and that damn thing you're transporting, will fall into the hands of the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_5">
		<text>Damn, damn, damn! I'll try to contact them on the radio, you go ahead and meet them, then reconnoitre the road.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_dlg_6">
		<text>Well, here we go again. Run.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_0">
		<text>Don't kill me, Marked One. I didn't do anything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_1">
		<text>Not guilty? Didn't you kill Swift? Am I right? Why did you do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_2">
		<text>I was overcome by greed. I don't know what came over me. Well, don't kill me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_3">
		<text>Did you know that his daughter was ill, and Swift was saving the money for her? Did you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_4">
		<text>No, of course not... If I had, I never would have touched him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_5">
		<text>Yeah, however you did ... Talk! Where are the goods?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_6">
		<text>Mercy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_7">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_8">
		<text>Okay, I tell you! I hid the loot in (several options). I'll give you everything! Spare my life! Are you going to kill me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_9">
		<text>I'm still thinking. Tell me why you killed the soldier?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_10">
		<text>They said, I was to wait in the attic of the grain elevator and if I saw this soldier on the road  they thrust a photo under  my nose  I was to shoot him. Most likely you won't be needed, we are using you as insurance. They gave me a thousand rubles. They said if I sat in ambush, they would double it. And if shot the soldier, then four. I agreed, of course. So what? Spare me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_11">
		<text>No, scum, you cannot live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sitnik_12">
		<text>All right, live. But mind you, if I ever hear about you doing that shit again, don't hope for mercy! Take this medkit and fuck off out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_send_money_to_wife_0">
		<text>Barkeep, I have a simple job for you. I need to send some money to this address.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_send_money_to_wife_1">
		<text>No problem, I can send it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_send_money_to_wife_2">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_end_0">
		<text>I'm on the job. About shadowing the stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_end_1">
		<text>Speak come on, don't wait. Did you manage to find out anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_end_2">
		<text>That stalker, I was following, is helping the mercenaries with something. The military has a big operation going on - they are bringing into the Zone that the "Monolith" didn't like. They and the mercenaries want to intercept the soldiers importing the object.\nDuring the shadowing, I was spotted and captured, but this mysterious stalker saved me. He helped me prevent the mercenary's ambush. I stole their laptop and showed it to the military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_end_3">
		<text>Marked One, you have a talent for getting involved in problems. Well, for your troubles, you get a really notable loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_end_4">
		<text>loot loot, what about Bulrush? You promised to help me, you bald bastard!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_end_5">
		<text>You've become arrogant, Marked One. He left here all emboldened and went to some deserted basement in an abandoned factory, you see. All right... I heard that the fellow you're looking for was hanging around here, he'd returned from raid and was boasting about his loot. He soon managed to relax - got drunk, poked his nose where it didn't belong, then came across a patrol of soldiers. So, if you want to find out, if or where he can be found, go to the checkpoint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_talk_0">
		<text>Take me to the compound where Mole and the diggers are camped - It'll be safe there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_talk_1">
		<text>Okay, I'll help you, let's get out of here before the special forces arrive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_talk_2">
		<text>You know, I didn't come here to save you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_going_to_rescue_point">
		<text>Break through. We'll break through - together. Everything will be fine. Only let's go. Yes, we'll get there. I know it. Come on, what are you waiting for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_talk_spasen_0">
		<text>Thank you, stalker, I'll never forget what you have done! Listen, I have nothing with me, but Barkeep will pay you with interest, I promise. He owes me a lot. Okay, then I'll head off to Duty. I hope we meet again someday.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_talk_spasen_1">
		<text>Well, good luck to you, Tramp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_talk_hello">
		<text>Marked One, hello!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_10">
		<text>Good morning! I am -  the commander of the rescue unit, ordered to pick up and evacuate the Stalker prisoner going by the name of Signalman. If the operational report from headquarters is to be believed, you are the person who volunteered to rescue the prisoner. Am I right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_11">
		<text>Yes, I am the stalker, about whom you speak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_12">
		<text>That's good. However, where is the prisoner?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_13">
		<text>I'll get him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_14">
		<text>We can't stay here for long. So I advise you to hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_15">
		<text>Yes yes, I know that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_20">
		<text>Well Marked One, where's the promised Signalman?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_21">
		<text>Soon, a little patience.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_32">
		<text>I see you brought the prisoner. That's good. Finally, we can escort him to our base.\nYou're free, your help is no longer needed here. Your reward can be obtained from Barkeep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_33">
		<text>Well, I'm glad to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_50">
		<text>Stalker, I've already told you that your help is not needed. You're free to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_51">
		<text>Got it, I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_60">
		<text>Hello, stalker! Command left us here to protect this area from mutant scum and insolent bandits. However, we will shoot ordinary extremists with great pleasure. So, don't play pranks here, understood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_guard_commander_dialog_4b0">
		<text>Oh, Marked One, why didn't you save Signalman? He was a good man known by all stalkers, he kept the network up and running...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Healing -->
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_title">
		<text>Healing: Talk with Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_speak_with_saharov">
		<text>Talk to Sakharov about the disease</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_article_descr">
		<text>Sidorovich managed to get sick. Unfortunately it's quite bad: he has high temperatures, gut-wrenching lung coughs and other "joys" of life. It seems strange, as he doesn't leave the bunker - well, only very seldom when absolutely necessary. Maybe, he has no immunity to germs? But that's okay, we'll find out afterwards, but for now I'll go to Sakharov - maybe he can suggest something sensible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_preobr_title">
		<text>Healing: Find professor Preobrazhensky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_preobr">
		<text>Find Preobrazhensky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_preobr_article_descr">
		<text>After the conversation with Sakharov it became clear that he knows very little about the disease, however, he advised to find his colleagues - Professor Preobrazhensky. He threw the coordinates onto my PDA - all that remains, is to find a scientist.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_0">
		<text>What's happened to Sidorovich? The door is locked, and someone inside is coughing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_1">
		<text>Sidorovich got sick. Very sick. I don't even know if he'll make it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_2">
		<text>What kind of sickness? What are his symptoms?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_3">
		<text>He says he has a headache, his body aches, has a temperature over forty and is coughing up blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_4">
		<text>It doesn't look good... You look after him, while I go to Yantar and speak with the scientists. Maybe Sakharov can advise what to do...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_5">
		<text>So be it, I'll nurse that old bastard. But he's still a jerk!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_6">
		<text>Come on, good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_7">
		<text>Of course Sidorovich can sometimes be a redneck when it comes to money, but he's a good man. He helps novices, and, by the way, he helped you too. Have you forgotten?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_8">
		<text>I would have survived without his help. He only helped me because I performed a few tasks for him. Okay, I'll go now, and share the good news with others.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_about_sidor_info_9">
		<text>Even so ... You're right. He did help me ... So now, I'll help him. You stay here and take care of him while I go to Yantar and speak with the scientists. Maybe Sakharov will come up with something...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_0">
		<text>We need your expert help. Do you know anything about diseases?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_1">
		<text>What sort of diseases are you interested in? If they are common ones, I can help. If it's any specific disease caused by the Zone, it's unlikely. My colleague, professor Preobrazhensky is engaged in studying viruses from the Zone, in more detail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_2">
		<text>I'll tell you the symptoms, and you tell me, if this disease is common or "specific".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_3">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_4">
		<text>Headaches, body aches, temperature over forty and coughing up blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_5">
		<text>My colleague recently studied something like this. If you want, I'll give you his coordinates, - he's now engaged in field studies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_6">
		<text>Yes, of course. The person is at deaths door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_7">
		<text>So, give me your PDA... Everything is ready, I've noted his location on your map. If I'm not mistaken, my colleague was accompanied by two volunteer stalkers.\nWell, good luck. Have a nice search!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_saharov_8">
		<text>Thank you, Professor!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_0">
		<text>Are you one of them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_1">
		<text>No, I'm on my own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2">
		<text>How did you find me? Confess! I know you're one of them! Release me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_3">
		<text>Calm down. I'm not one of them, whoever they were. I just found you - I heard some shooting and decided to see what was happening. You see, my friend, I really need your help. Were you the one responsible for studying viruses in Sakharov's laboratory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_4">
		<text>Yes I was.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_5">
		<text>I have an important question for you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_6">
		<text>So. Hold on with your questions. Did Sakharov send you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_7">
		<text>To some extent. I need an expert on viruses. The professor said that you are doing research into this, and gave me the coordinates of your camp. By the way, here's your PDA. I found it near... Heh, your now "former" camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_8">
		<text>Thank you very much. It contains very important scientific data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_9">
		<text>So, will you answer my questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_10">
		<text>Take me to the Dark Valley - to the entrance from the Darkscape, then I will help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_11">
		<text>All right. Come on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_0">
		<text>Are you ready to help me now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_1">
		<text>Sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_2">
		<text>An indispensable and very influential person has just got sick. His symptoms include: severe headaches, aching body, temperature above forty and coughing up blood. Sakharov said that you recently come across something similar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_3">
		<text>The Professor is right. About a month ago two diggers, came to the laboratory and brought us a gas cylinder. There were biological hazard warning signs on it. The stalkers were confused. We purchased the gas cylinder, and I began to study its contents. As it turned out, there was a virus inside. It's called... I won't give you its long scientific name. For my own reference, I baptized it "boar flu", "avian fever", "bloodsuckers itch" - or something like that. The structure of the virus clearly indicates that its origin is artificial. To find a vaccine under normal circumstances, I think would take a decade, but fortunately, there is one in the Zone now. 
At about that time, I had studied a very curious and extremely rare plant: Ranunculus insolita. What do you think? Even a small amount of its juice is enough to completely destroy the cells of the virus! A "vaccine" for humans has already passed tests. A week after the diggers left the lab, a stalker showed up. He said that he breathed in some muck in one of the laboratories and had those same symptoms that you have listed. Blood tests showed that the number of units of the virus, read off the scale. Three injections killed the virus, and in a day the stalker was completely cured.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_4">
		<text>Do you have this plant juice?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_5">
		<text>Not anymore. It's quite impossible to keep - it's perishable. But I do know where to find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_6">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_7">
		<text>If I understand correctly, it grows near water. The very first time I found it, was in the swamps near the Army Warehouses. There was some crazy sitting there and screaming all the time, he even tried to shoot me.\nBut that's irrelevant. Bring me three stalks, and I will make a vaccine. But remember, it will only help if it's less than three days since he caught the infection. After that, the process of destruction of the body is likely to be irreversible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_2_8">
		<text>Wait, I'll be right back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_3_0">
		<text>Here, three stalk as you requested. Prepare the medication.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_3_1">
		<text>Meanwhile,  why not talk with Sakharov, maybe he has some work for you... Recently, the snorks in the swamp have become very active.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_4_0">
		<text>Is it ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_4_1">
		<text>Yes, everything is ready. Administer it intramuscularly three times, at five hour intervals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_4_2">
		<text>Thank you, doctor!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_4_3">
		<text>It's a pleasure. I owe you my life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_ecolog_4_4">
		<text>Well, it was no big deal... Okay, I got to run. Goodbye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_0">
		<text>Well, how are you? Feeling better?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_1">
		<text>Much. My nose is still runny, but it doesn't matter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_2">
		<text>That's good, you really had us worried... But I wonder, how did you pick up such a nasty virus?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_3">
		<text>The fact of the matter is that I didn't pick it up, it was given to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_4">
		<text>How so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_5">
		<text>Some kind of stalker wearing a brown cloak came here, and said, well, he was delivering a gift someone had sent me, and puts a box on the counter. I asked, how much is this going to cost me? And he says: nothing at all. A man, who wishes to remain anonymous, presents you with a gift completely free, you have nothing to pay. I thanked him and he left. Well, out of interest I opened the cover of the box and something inside hissed, then the cellar filled with gas. I didn't have time to realise what was happening. I think he played me for a sucker. That evening I was laid up with fever and was shaking with an intolerable cough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_6">
		<text>So, one of your competitors sent you the virus?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_7">
		<text>Seems so...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_8">
		<text>Do you remember any distinguishing features? Or a name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_9">
		<text>Nothing special, he just looked like any other stalker. He was dressed in a brown cloak.  I don't remember his name. But I do remember that it began with a "B" and it reminded me of something like mushrooms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_10">
		<text>This is going badly for Sidorovich. But I'll still try to find the villains. In the meantime, I'll tell the guard not to let strangers in. Certainly they won't rest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_11">
		<text>Wait a minute. You've saved my life. I will never forget this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_sidor_12">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_info_a_killer_0">
		<text>Did two diggers bring you a gas cylinder about a month ago?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_info_a_killer_1">
		<text>Yes, they did.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_info_a_killer_2">
		<text>Do you don't know where those stalkers went then? Or, at least, where they found the gas cylinder?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_info_a_killer_3">
		<text>Where they found it - I don't know, they didn't say, but they were going to go to the X-16 laboratory. However, if they really went there, then most likely, there remained.I have no confidence in their training... Unlike yours, Marked One. Do you want to help science once again? I need monster tissue samples for experiments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_info_a_killer_4">
		<text>Sorry, Professor, I don't have time. I need to check out the X-16...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_0">
		<text>Bulrush? Why did you poison Sidorovich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_1">
		<text>He was poisoned? I only gave him a gift!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_2">
		<text>Don't play me for a fool! In the box that you gave him, was a spray with a deadly virus!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_3">
		<text>The stalker named Snake asked me to deliver a gift to Sidorovich. He said I would be well paid. He didn't disappoint me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_4">
		<text>Okay, I'll believe you. But first tell me where I can find this Snake?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_5">
		<text>The last time I saw him was in the building at the gas station, in the Dark Valley. Perhaps, you know the place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_6">
		<text>I know it. Here's a medkit, and don't pass any more suspicious types of gifts!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_7">
		<text>Sure, sure. If I had known, I never would have!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_sitnik_8">
		<text>See ya.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_0">
		<text>Are you Snake?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_1">
		<text>Well, I am. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_2">
		<text>Why would you want to poison Sidorovich?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_3">
		<text>What do you mean, "wanted"? I did poison him. I'm not trying to hide it. First, he's getting long in the tooth. Second, I found a worthy replacement.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_4">
		<text>Are you out of your mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_5">
		<text>What could I... the customer is waiting at the Cordon. By the way, could you can tell him I said Sidorovich is finished? I can't be bothered going myself. Not for free, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_6">
		<text>No, Snake. Sidorovich survived. I found medicine for him. But a cure for a bullet in the head, has not been found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_7">
		<text>Come on. I'm going there anyway.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_8">
		<text>Great. Well then, his name is Crafty. I have a message for him. Tell him this: "the bastard is dead". Can you remember that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_9">
		<text>Of course. "The bastard is dead". It's simple.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_search_talk_with_uzh_10">
		<text>Here's a thousand up front, when you get back, you'll get even more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_hitryi_0">
		<text>Hi, Crafty. I have a message for you from Snake. "The bastard is dead!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_hitryi_1">
		<text>Well, everything went smoothly. I can now safely take the place of that bastard. He-he ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_with_hitryi_2">
		<text>Yeah, you will take his place. Sidorovich survived, I found medicine for him. But you won't live, you louse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_bring_lekar_1">
		<text>This is a cure for Sidorovich. The scientists made it. It should help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_talk_bring_lekar_2">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One. If it helps, I don't even know how to thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_start_kvests_barman_0">
		<text>Barkeep, do you have any personal errands for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_start_kvests_barman_1">
		<text>Of course, Marked One, I always have assignments. Dangerous, but well paid. Here, you choose which one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_start_kvest_friend_of_barman_0">
		<text>Barkeep's friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_start_kvest_friend_of_barman_1">
		<text>I have a friend, he is somewhere in the Dark Valley with his group. They're monitoring the bandits and sending back information. But the last couple of days, my friend suddenly stopped communicating, even though his PDA is transmitting. Marked One, go there, and find out what happened. I'll give you the coordinates of his last location. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_friend_of_barman_shvid_pda">
		<text>Shvidi's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_friend_of_barman_shvid_pda_descr">
		<text>Record 1:\nYesterday we saw three bandits capture a Duty member. Those freaks!\nRecord 2:\nThe bandits are obviously becoming impudent! According to our data, they've already captured several Duty members.\nRecord 3:\nToday was lucky - we found three chunk of meat artifacts.\nRecord 4:\nWe crossed paths with Freedom, but we managed to repulse them.\nRecord 5:\nOur group was captured by Freedom, they  took away our weapons. They want to take us to a small tower next to the trailer and force us to get the artifacts. They don't want to climb up there themselves - there is strong radiation. We are trying...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sms_barmens_friend1">
		<text>Stalker! Help - we have been captured. We're being held in a trailer, but there is a window! Quietly and carefully come to the window so we can talk...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_sms_barmens_friend2">
		<text>Marked One, well done! You found my friend. Try to rescue him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_0">
		<text>Duty's deal with the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_1">
		<text>In general, here's the story. A week ago, Duty clashed with the mercenaries. They usually like to remain neutral, but this time something happened. During the shoot-out, a detachment of Duty was defeated and the squad commander was taken prisoner. Duty then contacted the mercenaries and demanded the return of the captured commander. The mercenaries agreed, but only for a very large ransom. They had no choice, the commander was an experienced man and Duty couldn't afford to lose him - so an exchange was planned. You need to keep an eye on what's happening and, if things don't go according to plan - you never know what could happen - support Duty with cover fire. Begin by talking with the ensign, he will tell you what to do next. How about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_start_0">
		<text>Prisoner at the military base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_start_1">
		<text>A very dangerous situation has developed, Marked One. The military captured one of our experienced stalkers, our messenger. The problem is that he participated in the creation of the stalker communication network, and he knows all the data encryption codes for the stalker PDAs. He is a good fellow, strong and silent, but it won't be long before he cracks. The military are going to get him out of the Zone and send him to specialised interrogators, they are sure to find methods to squeeze out every drop of information from him.  All this is very bad, Marked One. If this information reaches the mainland, it will become a disaster for us. It won't be possible to go fishing for artifacts in the Zone for a long time. I'm afraid we have few choices - it's necessary to save the guy, and quickly. Or, if you really have no other choice - kill the guy. As reported by the scouts, he is now in the main building being interrogated; they occasionally catch glimpses of him through the windows. Will you take it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_start_2">
		<text>That's good. Go to the "Agroprom" Research Institute. I'll get back to you, if the situation changes.</text>
		<!-- So here's the SVD. Choose a comfortable position and take the shot. Don't forget - you won't get a second attempt, so be careful. -->
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_save_title">
		<text>Resolve the situation with the prisoner at the Agroprom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_save_info_descr">
		<text>The military at the Agroprom have captured a stalker who has some very important information. If this information reaches the mainland, it would have disastrous consequences for everyone in the Zone, except the military. It's necessary to rescue or liquidate the captive in the shortest possible time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_save_go_to_agroprom">
		<text>Reach the Agroprom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_save_save_captive">
		<text>Save or eliminate the prisoner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_save_return_to_barman">
		<text>Back to Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_military_plennik">
		<text>Signalman</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_go_to_rescue_point_title">
		<text>Save the captive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_go_to_rescue_point_info_descr">
		<text>It's necessary to escort Signalman to the factory where diggers were based - there, he will be safe. Well, at least military if don't guess he's there and send special troops by helicopter to the Garbage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_go_to_rescue_point_save_captive">
		<text>Take the prisoner to a safe location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_rescue_point">
		<text>Safe place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_dolg_commander">
		<text>The commander of the rescue team</text>
	</string>
	<string id="captive_on_agr_mill_base_go_to_rescue_point_speak_with_dolg_commander">
		<text>Talk to the detachment commander</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar__kvest_friend_of_barman_complete_0">
		<text>Hi, Barkeep. I have completed this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar__kvest_friend_of_barman_complete_1">
		<text>Hi, Barkeep. I have completed this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar__kvest_friend_of_barman_fail">
		<text>Hi, Barkeep. I refuse to carry out this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_complete_0">
		<text>Duty's deal with the mercenaries. I have completed this mission. The mercenaries staged an attack, but I was able to rescue the captive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_fail">
		<text>Debt deal with the mercenaries. I refuse to carry out this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_completed">
		<text>That's well done, good work. I congratulate you on the success of the task and I'll give you a well-deserved reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_complete_0">
		<text>Prisoner at the military base. I have completed this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_complete_dead">
		<text>Well. Too bad, of course, that you couldn't save Signalman. He was a good man, dammit. It's a real shame. Mmm, look, we'll have to replace him... Okay, may he rest in peace. Take the reward and go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_complete_alive">
		<text>Well, Marked One! Thank you so much for saving Signalman. Without him, our stalker network - would be useless. Wow, it's scary to imagine what would have happened if his data fell into the hands of the military. So, here's your reward - you deserve it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_plennik_on_base_mils_fail">
		<text>Prisoner at the military base. I refuse to carry out this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_start_kvests_max_0">
		<text>Max, do you have any personal errands for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_start_kvests_max_1">
		<text>No problem. Here's what I can offer you:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_help_freedomer_on_radar_start_0">
		<text>Help Freedom at the radar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_help_freedomer_on_radar_start_1">
		<text>We've had an experienced fighter who decided to show his bravery by going to the Red Forest at the Radar to search the downed helicopter. We tried to stop him, but he was determined, and at night left for the Radar. They say there is something useful there. We are definitely interested in this helicopter, but we don't want to risk the life of one of our experienced guides. He's been gone two days, and I am very concerned. Marked One, take a trip out to the helicopter, and check it out... Is our hero alive, or does he need to be buried? If he's alive, bring him back - I hope he hasn't become a zombie. In the last couple of days, the radiation from the Brain Scorcher has weakened, but it won't last long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_help_freedomer_on_radar_complete_0">
		<text>Help Freedom at the radar. I have completed this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_help_freedomer_on_radar_fail_1">
		<text>Help Freedom at the radar. I refuse to carry out this mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_help_freedomer_on_radar_completed">
		<text>Thank you Stalker, for rescuing him. Without you he would have died.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_0">
		<text>Hi, Grandpa. What are you doing here? Why so sad?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_1">
		<text>Hello Stalker. Yeah... I don't know what to do... Ah, if it wasn't for my poor health and old bones, I would go to Pripyat - I want to find my daughter. And then there's the military! The are unhelpful - they won't give me a pass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_2">
		<text>And what happened to your daughter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_1">
		<text>I used to live in Pripyat with my only daughter, Tanya. She was 10 years old and in third grade at school. I worked in the turbine halls of the third and fourth units at Chernobyl. I'm a turbine specialist... All was well, and we lived happily. And then the accident happened at Chernobyl. I was  unlucky, I was on the night shift - and close to the fourth reactor. Our shift remained on site during the tests because our replacements hadn't arrived. Everything was going fine and all the tests were completed, except for the last one. At that moment, there were two powerful shock waves, the second was much stronger than the first one. Dust rose up around the control room, and then everything went quiet, well, at first, it was not clear what happened. I was probably only about thirty metres from the reactor. I ran into the room - the Block Control room is located between the turbine hall and the reactor room, and saw this: the lights were out, short circuit flashes were coming from the on-site feed pumps followed by steam and a strong burning smell.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_2">
		<text>Holy cow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_3">
		<text>I ran to the fourth reactor control room, the room was a mess, Tregub, the shift supervisor, ran to manually open the valves of the reactor cooling system, deciding it was urgent to apply water to the reactor, so I tagged along, to help. We rushed out into the corridor, where the annex was located. We ran up the stairs. There were blue fumes hanging in the air, strange... we didn't pay much attention to it, because we didn't yet understood how serious this was... after inhaling these fumes , as we reached the 27th step, we could feel a strong metal taste in our mouths. But not below that. It happened suddenly. Tregub ran ahead, he knew this place like the back of his hand. There was a wooden door. He grabbed for it - apparently it was swollen - and wouldn't give! We wanted to enter, but couldn't - and it was impossible to stay there. We went back to try to get into the turbine hall. We opened the door and saw the hall was piled high with debris, and the roof was gone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_4">
		<text>Yeah, that's a picture.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_5">
		<text>The Turbine Hall roof had collapsed - as if hit by something ... I could see the stars in the sky through the hole, under my feet were pieces of the roof, and black bitumen, so... so dusty. I thought - wow ... what's all this dust? Is this - bitumen coating dried up by the sun? It's not usually dusty. Or insulation so dry that it turned to dust? Only then I realized. It was graphite. From the reactor. Then I spun round - opened all the valves, then rushed outside to see what had happened, well because, from in here you couldn't tell. Outside, everything was covered with graphite. And over the fourth reactor, was a luminescence. It was bright blue. In general, I inhaled a very decent dose. Well, it became clear that everything was very bad. I called Tanya that afternoon, I told her to close all the windows of the house and not to leave for any reason. In the evening of that day I became ill, my mind was swimming and I was taken away by ambulance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_6">
		<text>You don't mess with radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_3_7">
		<text>Immediately the next day I was transferred with the others to the City Clinical Hospital 6 in Moscow, by then I almost couldn't see straight. It saved me as a result. While I was recovering, my daughter was home alone, and now, I cannot return home. I was in a coma for almost four days. I asked about her when I awoke, it was said the entire city was evacuated, but I never found my daughter after I recovered. I searched and rummaged all papers - she didn't get out of the city with the rest, she was never evacuated. She's probably frightened... And hiding, that's why she was never found. I've been looking for her since and I won't stop until I die. I came to the Zone to find her... or, at least, her remains. Or maybe she's still alive, and I will be lucky enough to see her again! It will remove a burden from the soul of an old man...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_4">
		<text>Hmm, well, a sad story. Accept my condolences.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_5">
		<text>Look, stalker, will you help me in my search?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_6">
		<text>No, Grandpa, don't be angry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_7">
		<text>I will help. Tell me, where do I look? Just approximately?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_8">
		<text>It's a pity, a real pity. Well, okay then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_9">
		<text>I'll write you the address of the apartment where I lived with my daughter. I think there should still be some traces of her left. Go, see what's there. If you find anything - bring it to me. Well, you'll help, huh? I probably won't be able to get there anyway. Only don't get angry with me son, I can't offer you a reward, I have nothing except old rifles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_10">
		<text>No, Pripyat - is a very dangerous place, and I want to live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_11">
		<text>Well, I'll try to find something. Don't leave camp and don't get involved, I'll be back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_0">
		<text>Hi, Grandpa! It's about your daughter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_1">
		<text>Did you find out anything? Did you go to Pripyat? Did you find something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_2">
		<text>No, I haven't been there yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_3">
		<text>Yes, I went to Pripyat and was in your apartment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_4">
		<text>Well, what did you see? Come on, speak up, don't keep me in suspense.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_5">
		<text>The room was empty, I found nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_6">
		<text>Your daughter kept a diary in the notebook, it seems they took her out after all, only not with the main group, but separately, a week later. She received a decent dose of radiation. She could still be alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_7">
		<text>It's a pity... I was hoping that there was something there. Okay, thank you stalker, you helped all you could. I'll have to keep scouring the archives.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_8">
		<text>Oh-oh ... if this is so, my Tanya was most likely taken to the military hospital and then probably also sent to the City Clinical Hospital 6 in Moscow, not to the same wards where we adults were brought, but somewhere in the nursery. But that was then... It's necessary to go to Moscow, to search the archives of the children's hospitals. At least I have some hope now, maybe I'll even see her again in my old age. Thank you, stalker. You helped me a lot, you've removed a burden from my mind. If she's still alive, she'd be forty now.  I was a fool, I spent almost thirty years trying to turn up documents about the evacuation,  going to cities where people were taken, and find out whether Tanya was there. I poked around in despair...\nWell, it's time for me to leave. I found out everything I could... Thank you once again stalker, for respecting an old man's wishes, you have no idea how important this was to me... Stay safe in the Zone, son.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_complete_9">
		<text>Goodbye, Grandpa, I was glad to help you. You'll see, you'll meet up with her, something tells me that she is still alive. Look, take the doll with you, don't lose it. Just don't show anyone. It lay in the zone for a long time, it seems to me it could be useful to you in your quest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blessing_of_old_man_tip">
		<text>The Zone is favourable to those who selflessly do good deeds.\nNow you can sleep in the rain and without protection.\nThe Zone will safeguard you from cold and danger as you sleep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_start_0">
		<text>Comrade General, have you never tried to negotiate with Freedom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_start_1">
		<text>Yes, we've already tried. But unfortunately, the meeting with Lukash frustrated me at times for various reasons. When the emission began, one of theirs seized one of our fighters, then the opposite happened, and one thing lead to another. In general, an agreement  was never reached. Why do you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_start_2">
		<text>I can help you arrange another meeting with the leader of the Freedom. If you can negotiate with each other, then it will be easier for all of us to live...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_start_3">
		<text>Well, life is certainly easy, in addition to our encounters, we have plenty of other misfortunes. The monsters, those lousy fucking monolith fanatics, emissions and God knows what else the Zone can throw at us. I need to have a long talk with Lukash! Well, Strelok, try to arrange a meeting. But only on neutral territory. For example, the abandoned farm at the Army Warehouses. I'll take care of the protection, and you work as the peace envoy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_start_4">
		<text>Well, then I'm gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_start_5">
		<text>Oh, no reason, just asking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_talk_with_lukash_0">
		<text>I want to arrange a meeting between you and Voronin. What do you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_talk_with_lukash_1">
		<text>Ummm... Marked One, I don't know what to say. I would have shot you for your silly joke, but you look painfully serious. Are you kidding me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_talk_with_lukash_2">
		<text>By no means, I don't kid. Agree? I talked with Duty - they don't mind, they wanted to talk with you for a long time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_talk_with_lukash_3">
		<text>Well, actually, yes, then I agree. To be at war on two fronts - is not good business. The fanatics constantly break through the Northern checkpoint, our people have already put down fuck knows how many, but they keep coming. Thank you for organizing the meeting, although unexpectedly. Take something from me in gratitude. Only look - it seems you're honest, but if it's a trap - the revenge will be terrible, believe me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_talk_with_lukash_4">
		<text>Don't worry, I'm honest. The meeting will be at the abandoned farm, not far from here - on neutral territory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_take_reward_of_dolg_0">
		<text>All's well, Lukash agreed to the meeting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_take_reward_of_dolg_1">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One, for organizing the meeting. Here, take this small reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_talk_with_freedomer_0">
		<text>Phew, at least it's safe on the rocks. Stalker, I'm lucky that you were here. Listen, I'm low on cartridges and I still need to get out of here. Can you help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_talk_with_freedomer_1">
		<text>I will. I came for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_talk_with_freedomer_2">
		<text>You were probably sent by Lukash, right? Just wait a moment, I'll go and remove the recorder from the helicopter. It will only take a minute, then we can go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_talk_with_freedomer_3">
		<text>Uh-huh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_talk_with_freedomer_4">
		<text>Well, did you get the recorder? Then let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_talk_with_freedomer_5">
		<text>Got it. We can go now. Take me to the transition to the Army Warehouses, I can manage on my own after that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_0s">
		<text>Stalker, this is our territory, leave quickly!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_0">
		<text>Freedom? Here? What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_1">
		<text>We are no longer members of Freedom. We recently left the group. We kept the Freedom body armour because that's all we had.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_2">
		<text>Well, I'll go then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_3">
		<text>Why are you keeping those stalkers in the car? Who are they?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_4">
		<text>Yes, they wandered near here, well, we met and talked with them. It turned out they were working for Barkeep - leaking information to him about what is happening. Well, we tied them and -  tried to shake out some information about Duty. And at the same time, since they're our prisoners, we'll force them to get to us artifacts from that low tower over there. There should be some Mama's Beads there. It's as radioactive as like hell, but they have nothing to lose. If you try to interfere - you will be shot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_5">
		<text>I never thought that Freedom could be so cruel. Can you let them go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_6">
		<text>I told you, we're not Freedom any more. Whether or not we release them - is our business, okay? And anyway, why am I talking to you? Get the hell out of here before I put a hole in your head!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_7">
		<text>What if you let me go up there, bring you the artifact, and you let them go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_8">
		<text>Why would you do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_9">
		<text>What can I say, I have business with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_10">
		<text>Well, no problem. For now, the bullet will have to wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_11">
		<text>I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_0">
		<text>Did you bring the artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_1">
		<text>Not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_2">
		<text>Yes, here it is, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_3">
		<text>Yeah, I'll take it.\nThat's all, you can go now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_4">
		<text>Um, but what about our bargain?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_5">
		<text>What bargain? What are you talking about? I don't know anything about it. Get out of here while you can before you get a bullet to the head. I repeat - you're free to go. Hurry, while you're still in one piece.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_art_6">
		<text>Well okay, okay...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_goodbay_1">
		<text>Stalker, piss off. We won't tolerate having you here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_zahvatchik_friend_barman_goodbay_2">
		<text>I'm going, going, going ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_0">
		<text>Hey stalker, come here. Hush-up, speak softly, so as we don't alert them. Hey, help us out, we're in deep shit. These crazy Freedom renegades won't let us live. They have planted explosives in the car, so we don't try to escape. Damn, we don't know what to do. Help us out stalker, and we will return the favour. Do something, please, we want to stay alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_1">
		<text>Well, I'll try to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_2">
		<text>Phew, thank you! So, can you get me a firearm and necessary ammunition for it? If we break out, it will be easier to do with a weapon. What about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_give_first_slot_weapon">
		<text>[Take the weapon from the first slot]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_give_second_slot_weapon">
		<text>[Tahe the weapon from the second slot]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_search_in_inventory">
		<text>Wait, have a look at what I can give you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_waiting_for_weapon">
		<text>Have you decided what weapon to give me? If yes, then let's do it quickly - every second counts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_give_nothing">
		<text>Sorry, but I can't give you anything - I need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_waiting">
		<text>Well, I'm waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_21">
		<text>Well, how soon before you begin the assault?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_22">
		<text>I'm on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_thank_for_weapon">
		<text>Okay, when you distract them, we'll begin our escape. I'll help you with cover fire, so don't worry. Phew, we'll get through this...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_no_weapon">
		<text>It's a pity that you have no weapons. Well, as soon as you distract the renegades, we will start to run. I hope that everything works out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_actor_goodbye">
		<text>God help us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_again_0">
		<text>We'll break out when you start firing. Thanks again for having responded! Don't wait for us, go, quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_save_0">
		<text>Well, it seems we beat them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_save_1">
		<text>It's my pleasure. Always happy to help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_save_2">
		<text>Thank you, stalker, you helped us a lot. Now I'm nothing you can repay, but the bartender you for saving me roll away the good reward. Well, I can get to the Bar on my own.\nThanks again for saving me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_talk_with_shvid_hello">
		<text>Hi, Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_friend_of_barman_completed">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One, for saving my friend. I really thought it was curtains for him. Take this well earned reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_talk_with_prapor_0">
		<text>I came from Barkeep about the deal with the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_talk_with_prapor_1">
		<text>Yes, Barkeep warned me. In general: Go to the meeting with the squad, I threw the coordinates on your PDA. You have to play the role of a sniper and help if they come fire. The main thing - try to protect the captured commander. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gar_talk_with_prapor_2">
		<text>Yes, I understood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_comp_bunker">
		<text>Enable</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_volk_fuel_1">
		<text>Gasoline? Well, you can try and search the old warehouses... or ask the military. But remember, the warehouses were plundered10 years ago and trying to get something from the military - is like asking a zombie for a cigarette. Although, if you want, I can help you out - I know where you can find a canister. I'm willing to share the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_volk_fuel_2">
		<text>The gasoline can be found near the old grain elevator, there is an old warehouse there or whatever it was. Look around in the corner of the building near a pile of wooden boxes. That's where a stalker hid a can of gasoline. In fact, the Zone claimed this stalker, so you can safely take it.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Teleport art -->
	<string id="teleport_trap_find_art_title">
		<text>Find the unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<!-- The text of the article should be should be moved -->
	<string id="teleport_trap_find_art_article_descr">
		<text>Sakharov asked me to go to the Darkscape and try to get an unusual artifact that was found there not so long ago. True, it's a long way to go, and who knows what's waiting for me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_find_art_go_to_place">
		<text>Find and try to pick up the artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_find_art_tell_to_saharov">
		<text>Go and talk with Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_title">
		<text>Examine the unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_article_descr">
		<text>A strange artifact has appeared in the Darkscape, which runs from the pursuer. I need to catch it and examine it with the Special artifacts Analyser.  According to Sakharov, the artifact is located south of the mountain range, in the woods west of the mill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_recearching">
		<text>Examine the artifact with the SAA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_article_descr">
		<text>Sakharov gave me a bag with unknown alloy inside, which theoretically could stifle the properties of the artifact. It's better not to handle it at all. It is necessary to put the case on the ground and drive the artifact into it. Well, try to...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_title">
		<text>Get the unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_catching">
		<text>Catch the artifact with "Prudenko's isolator" case</text>
	</string>
	<!-- deserter -->
	<string id="agr_deserter_text_spot">
		<text>Defector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_quest_title">
		<text>Help the deserter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_quest_find_outfit">
		<text>Find deserter some clothing</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_report_read_text">
		<text>Find a report about the transition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_make_dezerter_companion">
		<text>Return to the deserter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_quest_go_to_sidorivich">
		<text>Reach Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_quest_talk_with_dezeter">
		<text>Talk to the deserter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_dezerter_quest_article_descr">
		<text>The deserter, the poor fellow asked me to take him to the Cordon and put in a word for him with Sidorovich. But above all, in order not to attract too much attention, he needs a change of clothing. A plain Stalker jacket or suit will do. Also it's necessary to remember to pick up the documents that will help you find the transition between the Agroprom and the Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bp_mily_otschet_name">
		<text>Reconnaissance report</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bp_mily_otschet_article_descr">
		<text>Commander\nSpecial Security Battalion\nZone Perimeter\nAbout the isthmus Osadchenko A.G.\n \nCommander of the 2nd Company\nS/isthmus Kahn V.I.\n \nREPORT\n \nI want bring to your attention that in the course of verification of the information obtained by our aerial reconnaissance, the presence of a terrestrial passage south-east from the "Agroprom" complex to the area near the destroyed railway bridge, has been established.
		The preliminary measurements which are carried out by the investigation group, revealed a number of zones with raised (higher than average for this territory) background radiation levels. They have also explored and mapped 5 locations of abnormal activity,  and located 48 separate abnormal formations. Only 3 monster related incidences occurred during the operation suggesting there is low mutant activity in the area.
		We discovered that the entire length allows the smooth movement of wheeled and tracked vehicles and can be used to transfer our forces from Checkpoint 4 at Perimeter without involving aviation.
		At the moment, the protection of the area immediately adjacent to the passage area is entrusted to a squad commanded by Major Kuznetsov, located under the railway bridge.\n \nThe Commander of the 2nd Company\nS/isthmus Kahn V.I.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Psycho -->
	<string id="military_psycho_quest_title">
		<text>Help Psycho</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_quest_article_decr">
		<text>It is necessary to take Psycho to Sakharov. The guy is clearly on the verge of a nervous breakdown, and needs help from the outside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_quest_go_to_saharov">
		<text>Talk to Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_quest_talk_with_psycho">
		<text>Tell psycho about the decision</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psycho_military_note_name">
		<text>Strange note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psycho_military_note_desc">
		<text>It's unclear who wrote the note. But it is worth reading it all the same.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psycho_military_note_article_descr">
		<text>Marked One, hello! Don't worry about me! And thanks for taking me where you did. You must excuse me for what happened. It makes no sense to explain to you where I am - you wouldn't believe me anyway ... But know this - that terrible silence isn't present there. And it's delicious!\nI would like to thank you. My flash drive, I think you have already attached it somewhere, but it's okay. Along with the note I gave you an artifact. Its properties don't  increase your speed, strength or endurance. Not at all! It just protects you when you fall asleep in an unprotected place. I call it "Morpheus". I think you'll like it.\nWell, it's time for me to go. I hope someday I'll see you again! Oh yes, Ghost and Fang pass on their greetings. They are waiting for you on this side, but very specifically asked you not to rush...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Dead stalker -->
	<string id="question_of_immortality_fisrt_part_title">
		<text>The question of immortality - Part 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_fisrt_part_find_muten">
		<text>Find the "Cobblestone"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_fisrt_part_find_firefly">
		<text>Find the "Firefly"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_fisrt_part_find_chameleon">
		<text>Find the "Chameleon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_fisrt_part_speak_with_dead_stalker">
		<text>Bring the artifacts to the customer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_fisrt_part_article_descr">
		<text>A strange creature in the X-18 lab, called the Dead Stalker asked me to bring him three unusual artifacts: a "Cobblestone", a "Firefly" and a "Chameleon". There's no point in asking other stalkers, the description given by the Dead Stalker will help with the search.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_second_part_title">
		<text>The question of immortality - Part 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_second_part_find_black_soul">
		<text>Place the artifacts in this anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_second_part_speak_with_dead_stalker">
		<text>Take the transmutation to the Dead Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="question_of_immortality_second_part_article_descr">
		<text>The Dead Stalker asked me to perform the final part of his request: place the collected artifacts in the "Fruit Punch" anomaly on the first level of the X-18 lab and bring him the resulting transmuted artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_stalker_little_pseudogigant_title">
		<text>Little Giant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_stalker_little_pseudogigant_kill_monster">
		<text>Drive the pseudogiant into the anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_stalker_little_pseudogigant_speak_with_dead_stalker">
		<text>Report your success</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dead_stalker_little_pseudogigant_article_descr">
		<text>The young and noisy pseudogiant disturbs the failed controller... Who would have thought!\nThe Dead Stalker asked me to destroy the animal so it doesn't bother him, but there's a catch: the mutant swallowed a variety of artifacts that has reinforced his already strong natural defences. The only way to destroy the beast - is to drive it into a sufficiently powerful and tenacious anomaly that could deal with it the first time. It would be best to use artifact "Goldfish".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_search_guitar_info_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich asked him to find his guitar that a few newcomers lost somewhere in the camp.\nWe need to find it and return it to its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_hear_what_orlov_said_info_desc">
		<text>I need to find out what Orlov has to say</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_zaz_article_desc">
		<text>Drive the Zaporozhets close to Kuznetsov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_info_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich said a small transaction is to take place with the military under the bridge. It's necessary to bring them a bag of artifacts in exchange for a box of weapons and to give it to the village senior.\nThe weapon crate is very heavy, so you'll need a car. It was arranged that you use the Zaporozhets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_fuel_desc">
		<text>You'll need to find some gasoline to refuel it. Without a car, you won't be able to bring the box of weapons to the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_info_desc">
		<text>A group of soldiers have arrived at the Cordon and are at the gully with the anomaly. Sidorovich asked to me to find out the purpose of their stay there, but warned against an open confrontation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_2_info_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich, after learning why the military are at the anomaly, asked me to swipe the artifact from under their noses and bring it to him. I can't do it openly, maybe I can resort to cunning?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_3_info_desc">
		<text>The military refused to divulge the purpose of their appearance at the anomalous gully. Their commander agreed to lift the veil of secrecy in exchange for three loaves of bread, two sticks of sausage and a bottle of vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_info_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich has learnt from his sources that some shameless mercenaries came to the Cordon from the Garbage, he asked me to find out what they are looking for.\nTo do this, he gave me a directional microphone  with which you can overhear a conversation over a radius of 100-200 meters. I need to get close to the mercenaries and turn it on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_2_info_desc">
		<text>Having learned about the planned explosion in the newcomer's village, Sidorovich ordered me to urgently find and defuse the bomb, promising good pay. To avoid repeated attempts, it is necessary to destroy the mercenaries who planted the bomb.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_3_info_desc">
		<text>After the neutralization of the bomb, Sidorovich offered an additional reward for the heads of the mercenaries who planted it.\nI can go to the Garbage and destroy them, or take the main reward from Sidorovich. To hell with these mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_friend_of_barman_info_desc">
		<text>Barkeep told me about a friend, who, with his group, is monitoring the situation in the Dark Valley and sending information back to him.\nAfter his last unsuccessful attempt to contact his companion, Barkeep became agitated and has asked for help to learn the reason for the silence.\n He has given me the coordinates of the PDA's last signal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_friend_of_barman_2_info_desc">
		<text>Evidently, the stalker dropped his PDA and therefore didn't answer. Barkeep asked to try to find his friend, using the notes in his PDA as a guide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_talk_with_prapor_info_desc">
		<text>Barkeep said that mercenaries and Duty crossed paths by chance at the Army Warehouses recently. During the skirmish, the mercenaries destroyed the squad and the shell-shocked commander was captured, apparently they're planning to interrogate him. Duty wants the return of their commander and have contacted the mercenaries and agreed to a ransom.\nBartender has asked me to cover Duty in the event of a shoot-out; the prisoner must stay alive. First you need to talk to the ensign at the checkpoint and get further instructions from him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_slezhka_info_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to take a position and watch the meeting between the mercenaries and Duty. In the event of a shootout, the main task - is to prevent the death of the prisoner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_info_desc">
		<text>The old man at the Cordon said he lost his daughter during in the process of evacuation, after the first explosion at Chernobyl. Since then, he hasn't been able to find any information on whether she left the city...\nMany years later, he decided to return to Pripyat, to find any trace of his daughter. However, he could go no further than the Garbage - Duty would not allow it... The old man asked me to find the apartment in Pripyat, where he once lived with his daughter. I may be able to find clues to his daughter's whereabouts there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_info_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to arrange a meeting between Duty and Freedom. Voronin is in favour of it, but Lukash is not. I must meet him and convince him of the need for the meeting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_info_desc">
		<text>One of the young Freedom members decided to prove his bravery, by going alone to the downed helicopter in the forest at the Radar. Freedom is interested in what's there, but don't want to risk the life of another one of their own to find him.\nI must go to the downed helicopter, try to find this "hero" and help him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_info_desc">
		<text>One novice (near the fire at a house, near the Camp) got into a bad situation: He promised Fanatic he would get a "Night Star" artifact... But the bandits stole it, and now Fanatic will not let the poor fellow in the camp.\nI need to help the beginner - I'll go to the bandits and try to negotiate the return of the artifact with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_chek_info_desc">
		<text>At the grain elevator, near the bridge, stalkers noticed someone smoking in the attic. Sidorovich is wondering who is this mystery guest and what's he doing there.\nI need to go there and check.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_show_wpn_info_desc">
		<text>I found this damaged rifle at the grain elevator, where a mysterious stranger tried to stage an ambush. I have to show it to Sidorovich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_show_wpn_to_barman_info_desc">
		<text>The weapon I found, bears Barkeep's logo. It seems that Barkeep hired a hitman to kill me.\nI need to meet with Barkeep and find out what caused this friction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_kill_sniper_info_desc">
		<text>It turned out, Barkeep didn't want me killed. The sniper had me confused with his target.\nBartender fumed: he needs a certain stalker to kick the bucket. This hit was set up by the mercenaries; that loner probably seriously crossed their path.\nBartender ordered TNT cartridges from the mainland - to eliminate the killer who took the shot. Everything would have turned out, but the sniper confused his target.\nJust in case, Barkeep hired a second assassin - he's waiting for the victim at the Cordon's transition to the Garbage. My goal - is to eliminate the assassin after he makes the hit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_know_zombied_info_desc">
		<text>A Stalker named Chuck told me this story: his friend Figa, supposedly unveiled the secret of Yantar, he went there and disappeared. Chuck asked me to help him find Figa, who apparently fell victim to psi radiation. We need to find a way to get into the factory without a fight. Perhaps Sakharov can suggest something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_take_water_info_desc">
		<text>Sakharov spoke about the process of becoming a temporary zombie using some serum. It requires a certain water for its preparation. I can get it from a small marsh located next to the fallen helicopter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_talk_with_chuk_info_desc">
		<text>I need to go to the factory with Chuck and help him find Figa.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_search_figa_info_desc">
		<text>Sakharov gave me serum that turns you into a zombie temporarily. We need to drink it, then Chuck and I can go to the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_search_treasure_figa_info_desc">
		<text>Figa managed to utter indistinctly: Ter... Bar where anomaly... Large safe..."\nI need to find the hiding place, Figa spoke about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_on_taina_info_desc">
		<text>Judging by the note from Figa's hiding place, something appears at the factory at 21:00 and disappears exactly at 22:00. I need to find out what it is. The specific coordinates are not mentioned in the note.\nThe note referred to "the bus on the road leading to the factory gate". Most likely, there is something there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_on_taina_2_info_desc">
		<text>Based on the entries in Professor Thompson's diary, experiments were conducted on people in the X18 lab. Perhaps I'll find the compound or something connected with it. I'll need to go back to the X18 lab. Perhaps there is a clue in there somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_on_taina_3_info_desc">
		<text>This sample O-21 - is a terrible thing. It really should be destroyed; the dead stalker said that it should be immersed in something like the anomalous pool close to buses and construction equipment, near where the unsuccessful evacuation took place. I think I remember some place like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_help_to_chuk_on_taina_4_info_desc">
		<text>These records can be very useful to science. I should give them to Professor Sakharov, maybe they will be of some use to him, and, I may get something in return.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_search_case_info_desc">
		<text>An unknown person sent a strange message to my PDA: "I know Barkeep asked you to turn off the Brain Scorcher and you have a configured psi helmet, making you the only normal person able to get to the circuit breaker. In your place, if you value your life, I wouldn't hurry to fulfil Barkeep's request. I assure you, even if you disable the installation and get to the Chernobyl NPP, you won't find the answers you're looking for, but quite the opposite - it will only increase the number of questions. Well, if you don't want to deviate from your intended path - go to where you took measurements with Sakharov's assistant. At the entrance to the factory, on the right, there is a machine shop. There you will find a case containing something vital for you."\nSigned: A well-wisher.\nI need to decide: whether to look for the case the message refers to, or simply ignore the message and go further.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_search_case_tip">
		<text>I know Barkeep asked you to turn off the Brain Scorcher and you have a configured psi helmet, making you the only normal person able to get to the circuit breaker. In your place, if you value your life, I wouldn't hurry to fulfill Barkeep's request. I assure you, even if you disable the installation and get to the Chernobyl NPP, you won't find the answers you're looking for, but quite the opposite - it will only increase the number of questions. Well, if you don't want to deviate from your intended path - go to where you took measurements with Sakharov's assistant. At the entrance to the factory, on the right, there is a machine shop. There you will find a case containing something vital for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_kvest_search_case_code_info_desc">
		<text>Found an old case with a coded lock. I must find the code for the lock and open it.\nThe note that was lying next to the case, said that the code can be found in Strelok's cache.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_search_code_2_info_desc">
		<text>A note found in Strelok's stash instructed me to meet a messenger in the farm near the Army Warehouses to obtain the second part of the password.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_kvest_dobrozhelatel_plen_info_desc">
		<text>The messenger wasn't there. The unknown stalker sent a message saying he was most likely stuck somewhere in the Dead City. It's necessary to find the messenger and get the second part of the password from him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_him_info_desc">
		<text>A message arrived on my PDA:\n"" Brothers stalkers, help me out, I got into trouble! Help! I am close to the transition to the Garbage, near a broken truck."\nI need to help the stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_search_sitnik_info_desc">
		<text>I need to find Bulrush, who killed Swift and stole his loot. I must ask the people at the Cordon about him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_sidor_info_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich called me for a talk. He has a task for me. I need to talk to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_shpion_stalker_info_desc">
		<text>Sidorovich told me about a suspicious stalker in the Dark Valley, who visits the factory three times a day. I need to follow this stalker and find out what's there. But most importantly, I need to keep my distance so as not to spook him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_shpion_stalker_wait_info_desc">
		<text>It's impossible to watch this stalker any further. I'll wait at the entrance to the factory. I may be able to overhear something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_talk_with_orlov_info_desc">
		<text>An unknown stalker has let me out of the cell. I need to talk to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_tyrit_notebook_info_desc">
		<text>The mercenaries want to intercept the object which the military are bringing into the Zone. It's necessary to warn the military, but for that I need evidence - the mercenary commander's laptop is certain to contain important information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_info_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to notify Kuznetsov about the events.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_2_info_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to inform the military about what is happening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_mils_info_3_info_desc">
		<text>Kuznetsov asked me to drive a loaded "Gaz" back to the military checkpoint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_millitary_need_help_info_desc">
		<text>It's urgent to destroy the mercenaries who attacked the military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_send_money_info_desc">
		<text>I found the money Swift wanted to send to his wife. I should send it to the addressee.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_to_scoryi_say_all_to_sidor_info_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to report to Sidorovich about what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_af_uley_desc">
		<text>I need to go to the Dark Valley and find a unique artifact, called a "Beehive". It's necessary to be very careful, and be dressed in a protective suit with air recirculation. Since Zany didn't give precise details of the location of the cache, I will have to search the entire swamp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="check_robber_places_desc">
		<text>Weasel:\n"On Wednesday I found an unfamiliar artifact here. It's a cool piece - similar to a beehive! I concealed it in one of our four caches, here in the swamp, but forgot which one. I need to check them all, but something is making me sick..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="return_our_items_desc">
		<text>A member of "Duty" took my equipment, as well as the flash drive with information about the Klondike artifacts. I need to talk with General Voronin about the return of my property.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_artifact_task_desc">
		<text>The merchant asked to bring him a "Blood Stone" artifact, not the normal one with the same name, but a special one - it's radioactive and has much better healing properties. I should search in the anomalous gully.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_help_wounded111_desc">
		<text>State of emergency - a group of rookie slackers decided to fire at a helicopter and all of them were lost in the process. Well, maybe not all, it's necessary to go and check.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_trader_job_desc">
		<text>In exchange for help, Sidorovich wants me to get a case from the military base at the Agroprom. I ought to try to get it and not die at the same time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tolik_vodka_article_desc">
		<text>Tolik asked me to bring him some vodka. For this, he will give me the location of a cache containing a customized AS Val.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_cheb_desc">
		<text>Vasya Schukin gave me a tip about a strange artifact, in the tunnel with the derailed wagons. I ought to see what it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_goto_af_mincer_meat_desc">
		<text>In order to help the seriously wounded stranger from the farm, Healer has asked me to bring him a "chunk of meat" artifact. I heard that this artifact was seen near the grain elevator.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_first_shron_desc">
		<text>Before he died, the stranger asked me to find a cache with something, he said, was very valuable. Judging by the description, the cache is in a wooden box in the service block of the abandoned grain elevator.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_dnevnik_1_desc">
		<text>Diary of the experienced. Recording 1.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_dnevnik_2_desc">
		<text>Diary of a seasoned stalker. Record 2.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_dnevnik_3_desc">
		<text>Diary of a seasoned stalker. Recording 3.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_dnevnik_4_desc">
		<text>Diary of a seasoned stalker. Record 4.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_dnevnik_5_desc">
		<text>Diary of a seasoned stalker. Entry 5.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_dnevnik_6_desc">
		<text>Diary of a seasoned stalker. Record 6.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_planshet_zapiska_desc">
		<text>Note from Owl</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_1_desc">
		<text>Veteran planned to meet up with a Digger about some transaction. Apparently, this Digger has his flash drive. I need to meet him and pick up Veteran's drive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_2_desc">
		<text>Owl sent One-eyed to Petrenko at the Bar to buy some equipment from him. I need to find One-eyed. Perhaps the colonel could help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_3_desc">
		<text> Radioman went to the scientists at Yantar to buy detectors and other devices necessary for the campaign. I need to find out his whereabouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_4_desc">
		<text>Chatterbox went to the Darkscape for a meeting with group of Hunters. He heard they had a map showing how to bypass the Brain Scorcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_5_desc">
		<text>Owl, the leader of stalkers, should be at the Army Warehouses. Maybe he went to the Freedom base. I need to find out where he is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_find_flover_desc">
		<text>The cunning Healer took the content of the Veteran's cache. However, he is willing to trade it for a "Stone Flower" artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_seif_task_desc">
		<text>The digger who has the flash card with Veteran's information, has set a condition: it's necessary to crack the old safe first - then he will share the information with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_1_name">
		<text>Hint 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_2_name">
		<text>Hint 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_3_name">
		<text>Hint 3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_4_name">
		<text>Hint 4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_5_name">
		<text>Hint 5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_6_name">
		<text>Hint 6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_7_name">
		<text>Hint 7</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_8_name">
		<text>Hint 8</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_9_name">
		<text>Hint 9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_10_name">
		<text>Hint 10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_11_name">
		<text>Hint 11</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_12_name">
		<text>Hint 12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_13_name">
		<text>Hint 13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_14_name">
		<text>Hint 14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_15_name">
		<text>Hint 15</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_16_name">
		<text>Hint 16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_17_name">
		<text>Hint 17</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_18_name">
		<text>Hint 18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_19_name">
		<text>Hint 19</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_20_name">
		<text>Hint 20</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_1_desc">
		<text>Sawmill, next to a pile of logs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_2_desc">
		<text>Sawmill, in the shop with the saw bench</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_3_desc">
		<text>Hill top, under an evergreen bush</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_4_desc">
		<text>Concrete parapet, near an old barn close to the transition to the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_5_desc">
		<text>The huge pile of boulders, fifty metres from the transition to the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_6_desc">
		<text>On the roof of the filled-up tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_7_desc">
		<text>At the abandoned gas station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_8_desc">
		<text>On the destroyed bridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_9_desc">
		<text>In the windbreak near the bridge over the overgrown river</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_10_desc">
		<text>A cosy place at an abandoned farm in the north, where I used to live</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_11_desc">
		<text>In the metal scaffolding near the filled-up tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_12_desc">
		<text>As you go south from the broken bridge, on the right side of the road there will be a turn in the forest. Turn to the right there and after a hundred steps look behind the rocks to the right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_13_desc">
		<text>A hundred metres past the Poisonous Pool heading towards the Cordon, look to the left. There you will see a large fallen tree under the cliff. Look under it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_14_desc">
		<text>Leave my house and go straight to the north-west into a thick forest. As you reach the cliffs, look closely - you will see three large stones and a red spruce tree. Look between the stones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_15_desc">
		<text>Somewhere here, near this shack, I hid something valuable, but I forgot where. Damn sclerosis!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_16_desc">
		<text>To the east of the sawmill, under a bush on the hill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_17_desc">
		<text>Travel fifty metres from the train bridge towards the farm. Then look to the right: there will be many rocks and stones on that side. Choose the two biggest, standing side by side. Somewhere behind them lies the loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_18_desc">
		<text>Not very far of the little norhtern farm, on the right hand side, you'll see a bunch of boulders. The cache is behind them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_19_desc">
		<text>There is an old toilet near the sawmill. Look somewhere near it... Just don't walk in any shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="otgadka_20_desc">
		<text>In the rocks near the fork in the road, there's a rusty Lada there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_talk_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to get the information from the captured bandit, who is being held by the Hunters. Apparently, he knows something important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_talk_desc">
		<text>I need to talk with the leader of the Kulgavy gang, who are entrenched at the sawmill. He may agree to let the Hunters leave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_1_desc">
		<text>I have to release Flea the bandit from captivity. To do this, I have to destroy all the Hunters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_2_desc">
		<text>If I convince the Hunters not to attack first and drop their weapons - they will be easily taken captive by bandits. I need to talk with Yuri about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenniy_talk_desc">
		<text>If I come to an agreement with Yuri to spare Flea's life, the bandit will give me the location of the cache. He'll also provided information, which can be used to influence the bandits and get them to leave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_info_desc">
		<text>Somewhere here, near the sawmill. It was at night and I hit my head, so I forgot the exact place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_artnabor_task_desc">
		<text>Before Flea the bandit will reveal the important information he was carrying to his ringleader, you need to get him three artifacts, a "Mica", "Flash" and "Soul".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_with_hunter_desc">
		<text>Based on the data, Chatterbox was able to leave the Sawmill before the bandit attack. After that he went to the Hunters, it's worth looking for him there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_desc">
		<text>Musician is frightened by what is happening in the old house. According to rumours, a murder was once committed there and the victim's spirit cannot rest. Perhaps it makes sense to search the house itself and the whole yard and immediate surroundings, to find evidence of what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_arthunter_desc">
		<text>I need to meet with a newcomer named Vaska Podaypatron, who's at the Garbage. I will be able to get Veteran's flash drive with part of the Klondike artifacts information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_bar_scientist_desc">
		<text>I need to find medical help for the stalkers with an unknown disease. It's Professor Gorbovsky, but the mercenaries have kidnapped him for ransom. It's necessary to release the scientist if he's alive, if not, then to find his medical preparation and deliver it to Assistant Malyshev at the Bar. Then he can try to cure the patients himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="capture_the_officer_desc">
		<text>Denard, the leader of a group of foreign mercenaries has information on the whereabouts of Dr.Gorbovsky, but he wants help in the capture of a military officer. This officer, a Colonel, will soon be driving through the Darkscape with a group of soldiers. I must help Denard stop the car and take the Colonel prisoner. The officer must not be harmed, because the mercenaries were contracted for a large sum for his capture.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_izgoy_company_desc">
		<text>I received a strange message on my PDA at the Bar:it was from someone who is not allowed into the territory, asking for help. It's necessary to take a walk to the outskirts and check who's there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_merc_planshet_info_desc">
		<text>The target should appear soon, the explosives are ready. The main thing - is to take him alive and not let him slip past, I don't care about the rest - reliable sources reported that only three soldiers are in the car with the Colonel. The main thing - is to stop the car, and the rest - is a cinch...\n Nobody wants to pay for old scientist - that's too bad. What to do about it, I don't know. We'll probably have to get rid of him, but we don't want to dirty our hands - so we'll just feed the bespectacled scientist to the local fauna. I ordered that the scientist be taken and left on the outskirts of the Bar, somewhere near the bloodsucker's nest or dog's den.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_info_desc_name">
		<text>A tip-off from Flea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dar_merc_planshet_info_desc_name">
		<text>Mercenary's tablet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_bratstvo_9_desc">
		<text>A dying stalker at the abandoned gas station asked me to give his brothers his location so they can come to his aid. Look for his companions in a bunker under the cliff to the north of the forester's hut. The code for the bunker door - is 1983.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bratstvo_agent_1_sleep_desc">
		<text>This artifact, which I put in the safe, formed some kind of anomaly, and it won't let me out! If you hang it on your belt, the anomaly disappears. I only need to remember the combination of the safe... Damn!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bratstvo_agent_1_sleep_desc_desc_name">
		<text>Zheka's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_desc">
		<text>The head of the "Cleaners" asked me to escort their injured comrade, a security guard, to the doctor in the bunker, so that he could help him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_alltask_desc">
		<text>A stalker by the name of Kolya went to the Zone and has disappeared. It's necessary to find him and notify his friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_desc">
		<text>Why not try to deceive the bandits at the ATP and get them to release the prisoner without firing a shot? Yes, it's a risky option, you can fall directly into the clutches of the thugs, but why not try? All you need is to wear a brown gangster's cloak, black is not suitable as it attracts the authorities, forge a "transfer note" from some well-known bandit leader and give it to the local chief.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_krovosos_quest_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to obtain a unique live bloodsucker. To do this, I need to shoot it with a special tranquillizer dart using a special pistol, which the doctor gave me. Under no circumstances am I to shoot the mutant with a conventional weapon - it may interfere with the scientific research. In addition, I must act quickly, otherwise the bloodsucker could wake up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_pseudodog_quest_desc">
		<text>It's necessary to obtain a unique live pseudo-dog. To do this, I need to shoot it with a special tranquillizer dart using a special pistol, which the doctor gave me. Under no circumstances am I to shoot the mutant with a conventional weapon - it may interfere with the scientific research. In addition, I must act quickly, otherwise the pseudo-dog. could wake up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_desc">
		<text>Yuri the Digger bought a modified gun on the black market. After Bruise, a local craftsman serviced the weapon, it lost its abilities. I need to find this "master gunsmith" and force him to repair the machine gun, and then return it to its owner. Bruise can be found at the Bar, in a room next to the entrance to the Arena.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="diggers_pda_info_desc">
		<text>Incredibly, after decades, this thing continues to hum, as if in perfect working order! It seems that it's a perpetual motion machine, but it barely hums. Now, if I give it extra power, then the fan in the duct that is connected to it, can blow a great deal more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="diggers_pda_info_desc_desc_name">
		<text>Yuri the Digger's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_desc">
		<text>Jowly, the ringleader of the bandits from the Old Cordon, learned that a secret courier  went from the Bar through the Garbage and the Cordon at certain times with a large loot. This loot - is Barkeep's proceeds from a month's trade in artifacts and the bandits want to intercept it. It's necessary to track down the courier and kill him, take the loot and hand it over to the gangster's common fund - I will earn authority and the respect of the bandits, and also I will have the opportunity to get on their base and to trade there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_samogon_quest_desc">
		<text>Zakharych, the forester asked me to look in the Dead City for some moonshine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arthunter_task_desc">
		<text>I must get a unique artifact from the spatial anomaly that won't let me approach. Intuition suggests that I should look for a solution to this problem somewhere nearby.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mikluha_band_desc">
		<text>Mikluha, the Freedom guide went to the Radar, taking several of his comrades with him. I must find him, dead or alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="look_on_door_desc">
		<text>I need to examine the suspicious door in the tunnel at the Radar. Mikluha said it wasn't locked, but it doesn't open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_find_scientists_desc">
		<text>A group of scientists and the military to protect them, mysteriously disappeared while doing studies at Yantar. With them was a man I need to talk to - a stalker named Radio-operator. It's necessary to survey the scene and find out what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_find_diplomat_desc">
		<text>To pick up the trail of the missing group, I need to find the diplomatic case of the Guard commander, in it, there's a key which will give me access to valuable information stored in his personal box.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="get_afscanner_desc">
		<text>One of the members found from the missing group at the signals location, keeps talking about some "Wonderland" and "prototype"... something is fishy here. It's necessary to ask someone who was involved in the expedition: the private soldier who survived.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_sold_final_task_desc">
		<text>After the private clarified the situation, I need to do the following to help out the missing people: Find the special prototype upgrade for the "Search" detector, and then use it to get three different artifacts from the "Dark Zones" and then install them in a backup generator at the anomaly at Yantar. Then it will be necessary to trigger the pulse for its operation and wait for the outcome.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_af_uley_text_task">
		<text>Find the "Beehive" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_af_uley_text_task_hint">
		<text>Artifact caches</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_af_uley_2_text_task">
		<text>Deliver the artifact to Dr.Gorbovsky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_af_uley_text_2_task_hint">
		<text>Gorbovsky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="check_robber_places_text_task">
		<text>Get the "Beehive" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="check_robber_places_2_text_task">
		<text>Inspect all Rogue's caches in the swamp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="check_robber_places_3_text_task">
		<text>Pick up the "Beehive" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="seif2_task_text_task">
		<text>Open Petrenko's safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="seif2_task_text_task2">
		<text>Open the safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="seif2_task_text_task3">
		<text>Report to Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="seif2_task_text_task2_hint">
		<text>Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="seif2_task_text_task1_hint">
		<text>Petrenko's safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_candle_task_text_task">
		<text>Hidden properties</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_candle_task_text_task2">
		<text>Talk to Tykar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_candle_task_text_task3">
		<text>Study the properties of the "candle" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_candle_task_text_task_hint">
		<text>Stalker Tykar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_with_hunter_text_task">
		<text>Talk to Zakharych</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_with_hunter2_text_task">
		<text>Zakharych</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_with_hunter3_text_task">
		<text>Learn about Chatterbox from Zakharych</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar_talk_text_task">
		<text>Reach an agreement with the gang leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar2_talk_text_task">
		<text>Reach an agreement with the gang leader about the release of the Searchers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar3_talk_text_task">
		<text>Professor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_glavar4_talk_text_task">
		<text>Report to Yuri</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_1_text_task">
		<text>Release the captured bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_1_text2_task">
		<text>Destroy the Searchers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_1_text3_task">
		<text>Report to Professor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_2_text_task">
		<text>Ensure a peaceful solution to the conflict</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_2_text2_task">
		<text>Convince Yuri to believe the bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_2_text3_task">
		<text>Yuri</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_task_2_text4_task">
		<text>Talk to the gang leader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenniy_talk_text_task">
		<text>Ferret out the information from the prisoner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenniy_talk2_text_task">
		<text>Talk to Yuri about Flea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenniy_talk3_text_task">
		<text>Get the coordinates of the cache with the valuable information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenniy_talk4_text_task">
		<text>Find the information in the cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenniy_talk5_text_task">
		<text>Force the bandits to leave</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bloha_mark_text_task">
		<text>Flea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_artnabor_task_text_task">
		<text>Get a set of artifacts for Flea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_artnabor_task2_text_task">
		<text>Find the "Soul", "Mica" and "Flash"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_artnabor_task3_text_task">
		<text>Give the artifacts to Flea</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_kulg_band_text_task">
		<text>Destroy all the bandits at the sawmill</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_kulg_band2_text_task">
		<text>Destroy the Kulgavy bandit's gang</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_kulg_band3_text_task">
		<text>Talk to Yuri</text>
	</string>
	<string id="capture_the_officer_text_task">
		<text>Capture the officer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="capture_the_officer2_text_task">
		<text>Stop the car with explosives</text>
	</string>
	<string id="capture_the_officer3_text_task">
		<text>Colonel's car</text>
	</string>
	<string id="capture_the_officer4_text_task">
		<text>Kill the guards and wait for the Colonel get out of the car</text>
	</string>
	<string id="capture_the_officer5_text_task">
		<text>Grab the Colonel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_dar_btr_text_task">
		<text>Destroy the BTR escort</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_dar_btr2_text_task">
		<text>BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="read_book_4_text_task">
		<text>Read Zakharych's book</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_darkstalk_text_task">
		<text>Meet the Black Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_darkstalk2_text_task">
		<text>Someone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_light_task_text_task">
		<text>Get the "Light" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_light_task2_text_task">
		<text>Proceed with Dick to "anomalous hearth"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_light_task3_text_task">
		<text>Protect Dick's dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_light_task4_text_task">
		<text>Dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_light_task5_text_task">
		<text>Wait until Dick gets the artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_light_task6_text_task">
		<text>Get the "Light" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapravka_port_task_text_task">
		<text>Get out of the trap</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapravka_port_task2_text_task">
		<text>Find a way to get out of the room</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_bratstvo_9_text_task">
		<text>Find the secret bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_bratstvo_9_text2_task">
		<text>Find the secret bunker in the Darkscape</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_bratstvo_9_text3_task">
		<text>Tell the bunker inhabitants about their dying companion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_bratstvo_9_text4_task">
		<text>Brotherhood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text_task">
		<text>Help the "Cleaners"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text2_task">
		<text>Talk to Korneev</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text3_task">
		<text>Korneev</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text4_task">
		<text>Accompany the "Cleaners" on the road</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text5_task">
		<text>Bring the victim to the bunker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text6_task">
		<text>Talk to the leader of the "Cleaners"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_ds_agent_text7_task">
		<text>The leader of the "Cleaners"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_greeting_text_task">
		<text>A strange object</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_greeting_text2_task">
		<text>Inspect the Cheburashka figurine in your backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_greeting_text3_task">
		<text>Determine the source of the signal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_alltask_text_task">
		<text>Find the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_alltask_text2_task">
		<text>Find a stalker named Tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cheb_alltask_text3_task">
		<text>Find the right person in the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_samogon_quest_text_task">
		<text>Moonshine and the knowledge of the universe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_samogon_quest_text2_task">
		<text>Find information about the Bootleggers in the Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_samogon_quest_text3_task">
		<text>Find the moonshine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_samogon_quest_text4_task">
		<text>Bring the device to Zakharych</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_samogon_quest_text5_task">
		<text>Get information about the explosion in the sky over the Darkscape</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_fraer_text_task">
		<text>Kill Friar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_fraer_text2_task">
		<text>Friar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_fraer_text3_task">
		<text>Back to Borov for your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_fraer_text4_task">
		<text>Borov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cherep_treasure_text_task">
		<text>Find Skull's SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cherep_treasure_text2_task">
		<text>Skull's SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_pula_text_task">
		<text>Kill Bullet, the Duty member</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_pula_text2_task">
		<text>Bullet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_document_text_task">
		<text>Bring Barkeep's documents to Borov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_document_text2_task">
		<text>Find the documents in Barkeep's guarded room</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_document_text3_task">
		<text>Bring Barkeep's stolen documents to Borov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_document_text4_task">
		<text>Plichko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_artifact_task_text_task">
		<text>Bring a radioactive "Blood Stone" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_artifact_task_text2_task">
		<text>Find the artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_artifact_task_text3_task">
		<text>Find the artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_help_wounded_ogse_text_task">
		<text>Find survivors after the helicopter attack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_rma_dinamit_to_volk_text_task">
		<text>Get Wolf the dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_rma_dinamit_to_volk_text2_task">
		<text>Find the Dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_rma_dinamit_to_volk_text3_task">
		<text>Bring the dynamite to Wolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_goto_af_mincer_meat_text_task">
		<text>Find the artifact for the wounded stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_goto_af_mincer_meat_text2_task">
		<text>Give the artifact to Healer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_goto_af_mincer_meat_text3_task">
		<text>Healer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_first_shron_text_task">
		<text>Find Veteran's cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_first_shron_text2_task">
		<text>Find the cache of a stranger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_first_shron_text3_task">
		<text>Find Veteran's cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_first_shron_text4_task">
		<text>The area of the cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_first_shron_text5_task">
		<text>Get information from the caches</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_1_text_task">
		<text>Get the first part of the map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_1_text2_task">
		<text>Meet Digger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_1_text3_task">
		<text>Digger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_1_text4_task">
		<text>Get stick 1.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_2_text_task">
		<text>Get the second part of the map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_2_text2_task">
		<text>Talk to Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_2_text3_task">
		<text>Petrenko</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_2_text4_task">
		<text>Find a stalker named One-eyed at the Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_2_text5_task">
		<text>Get stick 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_3_text_task">
		<text>Get the third part of the map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_3_text2_task">
		<text>Find a stalker named Radioman at Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_3_text3_task">
		<text>Scientific Base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_3_text4_task">
		<text>Get stick 3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_4_text_task">
		<text>Get the fourth part of the map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_4_text2_task">
		<text>Meet with the Searchers in the Darkscape</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_4_text3_task">
		<text>Artifact Searcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_4_text4_task">
		<text>Get information about a stalker named Chatterbox</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_4_text5_task">
		<text>Find stick 4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_5_text_task">
		<text>Get the fifth part of the map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_5_text2_task">
		<text>Find Owl</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_flash_5_text3_task">
		<text>Get stick 5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_find_flover_text_task">
		<text>Find the "Stone Flower" artifact for Healer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_find_flover_text2_task">
		<text>Find the Stone Flower artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_find_flover_text3_task">
		<text>Give the artifact to Healer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="lekar_find_flover_text4_task">
		<text>Healer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_seif_task_text_task">
		<text>Open the old safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_seif_task_text2_task">
		<text>Open the old safe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_seif_task_text3_task">
		<text>Give the contents to Digger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_seif_task_text4_task">
		<text>Digger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text_task">
		<text>Mystery of the old house</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text2_task">
		<text>Find the remains of the slain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text3_task">
		<text>First part</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text4_task">
		<text>The second part</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text5_task">
		<text>Third</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text6_task">
		<text>The fourth part</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text7_task">
		<text>Talk with Musician</text>
	</string>
	<string id="secret_villager_task_text8_task">
		<text>Musician</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_arthunter_text_task">
		<text>Meet Vaska Podaypatron</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_arthunter_text2_task">
		<text>Vaska must be around here somewhere</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_arthunter_text3_task">
		<text>Get stick 1 from him</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brother_trap_task_text_task">
		<text>Help your fellow rookies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brother_trap_task_text2_task">
		<text>Accompany the rookies to the specified location</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brother_trap_task_text3_task">
		<text>Vaska Schukin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="brother_trap_task_text4_task">
		<text>Cover the brothers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="defend_bro2_text_task">
		<text>Protect the youngest of the brothers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="defend_bro2_text2_task">
		<text>Escort the rookie to the hut</text>
	</string>
	<string id="defend_bro2_text3_task">
		<text>Peter Schukin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="defend_bro2_text4_task">
		<text>Protect the rookie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tunnel_task_text_task">
		<text>Inspect the tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tunnel_task_text2_task">
		<text>Inspect the railway tunnel at the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tunnel_task_text3_task">
		<text>Abandoned tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_text_task">
		<text>Peacefully free the captive at the ATP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_text2_task">
		<text>Dress in a bandit cloak</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_text3_task">
		<text>Give the ringleader a "transfer note" from Borov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_text4_task">
		<text>Ringleader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_text5_task">
		<text>Escort the captive to the rookie village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_band_cheat_text6_task">
		<text>Nimble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_krovosos_quest_text_task">
		<text>Catch a unique bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_krovosos_quest_text2_task">
		<text>Tranquillize the bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_krovosos_quest_text3_task">
		<text>Unique bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_krovosos_quest_text4_task">
		<text>Bring the live mutant to Dr.Marsh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_krovosos_quest_text5_task">
		<text>Doctor's house</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_pseudodog_quest_text_task">
		<text>Catch a unique pseudo dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_pseudodog_quest_text2_task">
		<text>Tranquillize the pseudo dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_pseudodog_quest_text3_task">
		<text>Unique pseudo dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_pseudodog_quest_text4_task">
		<text>Bring the live mutant to Dr.Marsh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="unic_pseudodog_quest_text5_task">
		<text>Doctor's house</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text_task">
		<text>Digger's weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text2_task">
		<text>Get Digger's weapon repaired</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text3_task">
		<text>Give Bruise Digger's gun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text4_task">
		<text>Bruise</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text5_task">
		<text>Wait until the repairs are finished</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text6_task">
		<text>Return the gun to its owner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="digger_weapon_quest_text7_task">
		<text>Yuri the Digger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text_task">
		<text>Work for Jowly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text2_task">
		<text>Hunt down Barkeep's courier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text3_task">
		<text>Courier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text4_task">
		<text>Kill the courier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text5_task">
		<text>Collect the loot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text6_task">
		<text>Deliver loot to the ATP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_lider_work1_text7_task">
		<text>Vehicle station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arthunter_task_text_task">
		<text>A strange anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arthunter_task_text2_task">
		<text>Get the "bubble" artifact out of the spatial anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mikluha_band_text_task">
		<text>Prisoners at the Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mikluha_band_text2_task">
		<text>Find the Freedom squad at the Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mikluha_band_text3_task">
		<text>The likely location of the unit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mikluha_band_text4_task">
		<text>Find out what happened</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_mikluha_band_text5_task">
		<text>Report to Lukash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_1_text_task">
		<text>Protect the Guides Camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_1_text2_task">
		<text>Repel the wave of mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_1_text3_task">
		<text>Destroy the boars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_1_text4_task">
		<text>Talk to Mikluha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_1_text5_task">
		<text>Mikluha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="look_on_door_text_task">
		<text>Inspect the door in the tunnel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_2_text_task">
		<text>Repel the second wave of mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_2_text2_task">
		<text>Destroy the snorks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_2_text3_task">
		<text>Talk to Mikluha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_3_text_task">
		<text>Destroy the third wave of mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_3_text2_task">
		<text>Destroy chimeras and the pseudo giant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mobs_attack_3_text3_task">
		<text>Talk to Mikluha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="superkontroller_kill_text_task">
		<text>Destroy the super-controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="superkontroller_kill_text2_task">
		<text>Destroy the super-controller before he turns the stalkers into zombies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_with_guider_text_task">
		<text>Bring the guide Ghost's "AS val"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_with_guider_text2_task">
		<text>Find Ghost's "AS val"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text_task">
		<text>The deal with the military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text2_task">
		<text>Make a deal with the military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text3_task">
		<text>Get a bag of artifacts from Wolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text4_task">
		<text>Fill the vehicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text5_task">
		<text>Deliver the box with artifacts to the military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text6_task">
		<text>Kuznetsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text7_task">
		<text>Bring a box of weapons to the rookie camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text8_task">
		<text>Report the implementation to Wolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_text9_task">
		<text>Collect your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_sdelka_with_mils_zaz_text_task">
		<text>Drive the vehicle closer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text_task">
		<text>Rescue the captive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text2_task">
		<text>Talk to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text3_task">
		<text>Meet with the commander of the Special Squad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text4_task">
		<text>Destroy the military at a checkpoint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text5_task">
		<text>Eliminate the military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text6_task">
		<text>Find information about the captive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text7_task">
		<text>Find the captive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text8_task">
		<text>Escort the prisoner to the rookie village</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_plennik_of_blockpost_text9_task">
		<text>Talk to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_text_task">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_2_text_task">
		<text>The Military at the anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_2_text2_task">
		<text>Bring the strange object to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_2_text3_task">
		<text>Take the strange object in the anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_2_text4_task">
		<text>Anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_know_do_mils_near_anomaly_3_text_task">
		<text>Bring food and vodka to the soldiers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text_task">
		<text>Mercenaries at the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text2_task">
		<text>Back to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text3_task">
		<text>Get imperceptibly closer to the mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text4_task">
		<text>Mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text5_task">
		<text>Turn on the microphone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text6_task">
		<text>Wait until the conversation is recorded</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_text7_task">
		<text>Back to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_2_text_task">
		<text>Protect the camp from the explosion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_2_text2_task">
		<text>Defuse the bomb</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_2_text3_task">
		<text>Find bomb planted in the camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_2_text4_task">
		<text>Rookies camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_killers_mined_lager_3_text_task">
		<text>Kill the mercenaries who planted the bomb</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_talk_with_prapor_text_task">
		<text>Duty's deal with the mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_talk_with_prapor_text2_task">
		<text>Talk to Prapor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_talk_with_prapor_text3_task">
		<text>Warrant officer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_slezhka_text_task">
		<text>Report to Barkeep about what took place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_slezhka_text2_task">
		<text>Meet with a detachment of Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_slezhka_text3_task">
		<text>Take a point for observation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_slezhka_text4_task">
		<text>Protect the Duty prisoner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_sdelka_dolg_and_killers_talk_with_prapor_2_text_task">
		<text>Report to the ensign about what took place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_text_task">
		<text>Old Man's Daughter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_text2_task">
		<text>Talk to the old man</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_text3_task">
		<text>Old timer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_text4_task">
		<text>Find the apartment, where the old man lived</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pri_kvest_search_doch_of_starik_text5_task">
		<text>Search the apartment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_text_task">
		<text>Meeting between Duty and Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_text2_task">
		<text>Talk with Voronin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_text3_task">
		<text>Voronin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_text4_task">
		<text>Convince Lukash to begin negotiations with Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kvest_make_meet_dolg_freedom_text5_task">
		<text>Lukash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_text_task">
		<text>Rescue the Freedom members</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_text2_task">
		<text>Talk to Max</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_text3_task">
		<text>Find the Freedom soldier, who had gone to the helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_kvest_spasti_freedomer_on_radar_text4_task">
		<text>Max</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_text_task">
		<text>Help Grouse</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_text2_task">
		<text>Bring Grouse the artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_text3_task">
		<text>Grouse</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_help_teterev_text4_task">
		<text>Take the bandit's artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text_task">
		<text>Guest at the elevator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text2_task">
		<text>Check the guest's "motives"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text3_task">
		<text>Show the weapon you found to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text4_task">
		<text>Quiz Barkeep about the weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text5_task">
		<text>Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text6_task">
		<text>Report on the success to Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_qest_on_elevator_text7_task">
		<text>Eliminate the assassin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Talk with Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text2_task">
		<text>Learn from Sakharov, how to deceive the mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text3_task">
		<text>Professor Sakharov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text4_task">
		<text>Learn from Sakharov, how to deceive the mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text5_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Become a zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text6_task">
		<text>Bring Sakharov a flask with water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text7_task">
		<text>Collect some swamp water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text8_task">
		<text>Bring Sakharov a flask with the water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text9_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Talk to Chuck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text10_task">
		<text>Talk to Chuck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text11_task">
		<text>Chuck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text12_task">
		<text>Become a zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text13_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Find Figa</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text14_task">
		<text>Find Figa - Chuck's friend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text15_task">
		<text>Enter the "Yantar" factory with Chuck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text16_task">
		<text>Find Figa - Chuck's friend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text17_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Search Figa's cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text18_task">
		<text>Search Figa's cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text19_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Find the O-21 sample</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text20_task">
		<text>Find the O-21 sample</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text21_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Uncover the secret</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text22_task">
		<text>Unlock the secrets of Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text23_task">
		<text>Yantar's secret: Destroy the O-21 sample</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text24_task">
		<text>Talk to the Dead Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text25_task">
		<text>Destroy the O-21 sample</text>
	</string>
	<string id="scary_mistery_of_the_yantar_text26_task">
		<text>Bring Sakharov Prof. Thompson's records</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text_task">
		<text>Well-wisher: Take the case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text2_task">
		<text>Take the case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text3_task">
		<text>Well-wisher: Briefcase code</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text4_task">
		<text>Open the briefcase</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text5_task">
		<text>Find the code for the briefcase</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text6_task">
		<text>Well-wisher: The second part of the code</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text7_task">
		<text>Meet with the messenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text8_task">
		<text>Well-wisher: Save the messenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text9_task">
		<text>Get the password from the messenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text10_task">
		<text>Messenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text11_task">
		<text>Save Messenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text12_task">
		<text>Reach a safe place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_boomsurprise_defuse_text13_task">
		<text>Get the password from messenger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text_task">
		<text>Last request: Find Bulrush</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text2_task">
		<text>Find Bulrush</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text3_task">
		<text>Hunt down the stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text4_task">
		<text>Last request: Overhear the conversation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text5_task">
		<text>Overhear what Orlov says</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text6_task">
		<text>Orlov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text7_task">
		<text>Last request: Steal a mercenary's laptop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text8_task">
		<text>Steal a mercenary's laptop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text9_task">
		<text>Dressed as a bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text10_task">
		<text>Take your things</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text11_task">
		<text>Your belongings</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text12_task">
		<text>Steal a mercenary's laptop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text13_task">
		<text>Last request: Alert Kuznetsov about the sabotage attempt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text14_task">
		<text>Alert Kuznetsov about the sabotage attempt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text15_task">
		<text>Last request: Deal with the ambush</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text16_task">
		<text>Help the military with the destruction of the mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text17_task">
		<text>Mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text18_task">
		<text>Talk with Kuznetsov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text19_task">
		<text>Last request: Help the Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text20_task">
		<text>Drop the cargo off at the checkpoint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text21_task">
		<text>Checkpoint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text22_task">
		<text>Last request: Send the money to Swift's wife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text23_task">
		<text>Send the money to Swift's wife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text24_task">
		<text>Collect the loot from Bulrush's cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text25_task">
		<text>Last request: Report back to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="last_wish_quest_text26_task">
		<text>Report to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text_task">
		<text>Healing: Accompany Preobrazhensky to the evacuation point</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text2_task">
		<text>Accompany Preobrazhensky to the evacuation point</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text3_task">
		<text>Preobrazhensky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text4_task">
		<text>Healing: Find three plant stalks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text5_task">
		<text>Bring the stalks to Preobrazhensky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text6_task">
		<text>Find three stalk plants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text7_task">
		<text>Healing: Take the drug to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text8_task">
		<text>Take the drug to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text9_task">
		<text>Healing: Talk to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text10_task">
		<text>Healing: Ask the scientists about the Diggers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text11_task">
		<text>Ask the scientists about the Diggers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text12_task">
		<text>Healing: Find the Diggers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text13_task">
		<text>Find the Diggers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text14_task">
		<text>Healing: Find the bandit named Snake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text15_task">
		<text>Find the bandit named Snake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text16_task">
		<text>Healing: Find the customer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text17_task">
		<text>Find the customer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text18_task">
		<text>Healing: Kill Snake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text19_task">
		<text>Kill Snake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kvest_iscelenie_big_text20_task">
		<text>Healing: Talk to Sidorovich</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_find_gold_fish_start_text_task">
		<text>Bring Sakharov the "Goldfish" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_find_gold_fish_start_text2_task">
		<text>Find the "Goldfish" artifact. Perhaps zombie scientist Thompson owns a rare artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_find_gold_fish_start_text3_task">
		<text>Find the "Goldfish" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_find_gold_fish_start_text4_task">
		<text>Bring Sakharov the "Goldfish" artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text_task">
		<text>Dangerous science: Find the group</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text2_task">
		<text>Accompany the private to the scientist's camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text3_task">
		<text>Makeshift camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text4_task">
		<text>Inspect the temporary camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text5_task">
		<text>Talk to the private</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text6_task">
		<text>Private</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text7_task">
		<text>Find the cause of the group's disappearance</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text8_task">
		<text>Dangerous Science: Get a map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text9_task">
		<text>Find commander's personal diplomatic case and take the key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text10_task">
		<text>Search the area</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text11_task">
		<text>Open commander's box in the bunker with the key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text12_task">
		<text>Get the commander's map</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text13_task">
		<text>Show the map to the private</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text14_task">
		<text>Dangerous science: Inspect the signal source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text15_task">
		<text>Inspect the signal source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text16_task">
		<text>Location of the signal from the missing scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text17_task">
		<text>Dangerous Science: Get the information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text18_task">
		<text>Ask the private</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text19_task">
		<text>Dangerous Science: Final accord</text>
	</string>
	<!--	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text20_task">
		<text>  </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text21_task">
		<text>  </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text22_task">
		<text>     </text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text23_task">
		<text>    </text>
	</string> -->
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text24_task">
		<text>Find the "prototype"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text25_task">
		<text>Using the "Prototype" detector, collect three different artifacts from the "Dark Zones"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text26_task">
		<text>Place the artifacts in the backup generator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text27_task">
		<text>Provoke a discharge from the anomaly at Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dangerous_science_quest_text28_task">
		<text>Dark Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loschina_scientists_article_text_desc">
		<text>Get the scientist's records from the Darkscape</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_quest_text">
		<text>Get a BTR for protection of the Barrier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_quest_end_text">
		<text>Get your reward from Lukash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_keys_quest_text">
		<text>Find the electronic key for the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_keys_quest_2_text">
		<text>Get inside the BTR and inspect the damage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_keys_quest_1_text">
		<text>Find the key to the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_power_offline_quest_text">
		<text>Nothing works</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_get_accum_quest_text">
		<text>Get a new battery for the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_get_accum_quest_1_text">
		<text>Install a charged battery into the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_btr_hint">
		<text>Spare BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_get_accum_quest_2_text">
		<text>Find a battery at the Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_get_accum_quest_2_1_text">
		<text>Find three "Battery" artifacts to charge the battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_get_accum_quest_3_text">
		<text>Bring the battery to Screw for charging</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_get_accum_quest_4_text">
		<text>Pick up the charged battery from Screw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_computer_offline_quest_text">
		<text>The BTR computer is faulty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_computer_find_quest_text">
		<text>Get a new computer for the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_computer_find_quest_1_text">
		<text>Install the functional on-board computer into the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_computer_find_quest_2_text">
		<text>Get a new computer for the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_computer_find_quest_3_text">
		<text>Optional: Get a computer upgrade for the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_drive_quest_text">
		<text>Drive the BTR to the barrier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_drive_quest_1_text">
		<text>Talk to Cap about the transfer of the BTR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_drive_quest_2_text">
		<text>Deliver the BTR to the barrier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_get_btr_for_freedom_drive_quest_3_text">
		<text>The BTR has to survive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_bolt_task_text">
		<text>Find the anomalous bolts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_text">
		<text>Show found things to the scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_find_text">
		<text>Find the rest of the anomalous household items</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_end_text">
		<text>Bring all the found anomalous household items to the scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_help_krot_ammo_box_start_text">
		<text>Find out what help Mole needs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_help_krot_ammo_box_find_text">
		<text>Find Mole's lost boxes of ammunition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_help_krot_ammo_box_end_text">
		<text>Collect your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_help_krot_ammo_box_info_desc">
		<text>Mole asked me to find boxes of ammunition that stalkers from his group hid somewhere in the Garbage near the depot.\nThey left the boxes there, while they were running from a military detachment of Special Forces who were pursuing them. \nAccording to Dimon, one of the surviving stalkers, they were overtaken by an emission and were forced to take shelter in the underground tunnels.\nDimon also said that one or two stalkers ran towards the pile of garbage to the East of the depot</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

