<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="zombie_kak_dela">
		<text>Hello, how are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hochu_est">
		<text>How, how ... I just want to eat all the time! Do you have some food? No - it's a pity, I'll go look for some. A stalker might wander by...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pusto">
		<text>...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="benito">
		<text>Have you heard about Benito?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kto_etot">
		<text>No, who is he?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="odin_is_nas">
		<text>Yes, he's one of ours... He's friendly with the Doctor... He's run away again... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ne_slishal">
		<text>I didn't know that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tompsona_vidal">
		<text>Have you seen Thompson? I need to find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="za_zavodom">
		<text>Yes, he hides in the back streets behind the plant. It's strange.. He's not looking for food... He carries... all those... artifacts with him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ti_novenkii">
		<text>You look like a newcomer. Keep that in mind! If you want to stay alive, don't let Duty spot you, they don't like us very much... But, who does like us?.. Eh... </text>
	</string>
	<string id="kak_vi_jivete">
		<text>How do you survive down here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prokajennii">
		<text>We are like lepers. We have our own world. We are not wanted.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="privet">
		<text>Hello, colleague, heh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="obana">
		<text>Wow, Marked One is with us! Now we can move to the Bar! We will live longer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="necogda">
		<text>I have no time, I'm too busy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zrja">
		<text>No need, there's so much meat... There are only scientists here... and they sit in the bunker. Okay, I'm going - the guys have already assembled there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chto_novenk">
		<text>Well, what's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kontroller_poselilsja">
		<text>A controller had settled not far from here, he calls himself Chumak, he's very good at curing headaches and hangovers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="delaete">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="skuchno">
		<text>Well, it's boring here, at least until the dogs howl! Oh, wait, after the last release a whirligig anomaly appeared at the hangar, and yesterday, a couple of snorks tried to walk through it and were caught and torn up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mojno_vas">
		<text>Hey! Can you help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bbb">
		<text>Don't bother me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vi_tompson">
		<text>Are you Thompson?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="da_eto_ya">
		<text>Yes, I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="saharov_skazal">
		<text>Sakharov said...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ne_pugaj">
		<text>You don't scare me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="u_teba_est_artef">
		<text>Do you have any artifacts? Answer me, or I'll kill you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="est">
		<text>Yes, I have. But if you kill me, you'll get nothing. I can only sell them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_gold_fish">
		<text>Found... artifact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="usnete">
		<text>Excellent. Now fall asleep and wake up as a normal person.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="goodfine">
		<text>At... last...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pomogi">
		<text>Help... me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="viju">
		<text>I see, I see. In recent years, I have often seen these antics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chto_delat">
		<text>What... can... you do?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="est_sposob">
		<text>There is a way to help you. It can be done, but only if you provide a "Goldfish" artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gde_naiti">
		<text>Where... do I... find it?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tompson">
		<text>This artifact often appears after an emission. It's possible that my former colleague - Dr.Thompson, has such rare artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pochem">
		<text>Why... former?..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombi">
		<text>Here at Yantar, in the underground lab, Dr.Thompson was faced with a controller. The controller could not completely subdue him, and many of his brain functions stopped working. Now he's a zombie, but can still think and continues his research. He goes to the most dangerous places. He is likely to have a "Goldfish".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="popr">
		<text>Find... artifact... Yeah...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pomogi_opat">
		<text>Professor... help...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chto_opat">
		<text>Marked One, how did you manage? Did you remember - that to recover, you needed to get the "Goldfish" artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ya_pomnu">
		<text>I... remembered... Yeah...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vot_ona">
		<text>Here... it is...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nashel_vesh">
		<text>I've found a strange thing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="4to_imenno">
		<text>What is it, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="raspravilsa_s_zombi">
		<text>I dealt with a crowd of exploding zombies and found the remains of a hand among them. It glows, it's warm and apparently, it even protects against radiation...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neuzheli_ruka">
		<text>Marked One, did you find the hand of the legendary suicide zombie? If so, it will dramatically advance our research! We still don't have any evidence of the existence of this zombie. Ghost once told me that he met him, but I took it simply as a story. You should immediately give me the artifact for research!.. Don't worry about the price. If what you say is true, and my studies confirm this - believe me, you'll be adequately rewarded...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horosho">
		<text>OK I agree. Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="priberegu">
		<text>No, perhaps I'll keep it for myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="provedu_issledovanie">
		<text>Excellent, Marked One... Take a little walk, while I undertake a number of studies of this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="okay">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="podumai_horoshenko">
		<text>Marked One, think again. After all, I suggested a good reward. If you still decide to help science - come back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nu_kak_tam">
		<text>Well, how is the study of zombie's hand going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kak_raz_vovremja">
		<text>Marked One, you're just in time! I just finished my studies.\n \nIt's incredible! The unusual properties of the zombie's hand are directly related to the influence of the "Burner" anomaly. Like other artifacts from this anomaly, the hand is able to protect against radiation... But that's not all! It also possesses healing properties: It removes toxins from the body and promotes tissue regeneration. Apparently, the suicide zombie had an extremely accelerated metabolism. Perhaps this can explain their ability to explode. The structure of the tissue is so unstable that it fills with sulphur gas from  exposure to the heat of the burner anomaly, and in case of damage, they  just explode. But in its quiet state, it accelerates regeneration...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prodolzhai">
		<text>Interesting... Continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prodolzhaju">
		<text>Unlike other civilian zombies, these are ALIVE in the truest sense of the word. The special structure of their nerve cells suggests that these creatures can even control the speed of their metabolism. They have a kind of group intelligence - some sacrifice themselves for food for the others. This can explain their suicidal tendencies. They are just incredible creatures. Much information can be obtained if we could catch one of these suicide zombies alive! But I suspect that it's simply impossible, given their "explosive nature". Now I'll take the PDA with your research material, Marked One...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="a_gde_nagrada">
		<text>It's nice of course... Interesting information, and all that... But, I was expecting, so to speak, to receive more information from you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ah_da">
		<text>Oh yeah, I almost forgot about your reward - I so engrossed in my research... Science is now poorly funded, so I can't give you a lot of money. But I have a unique weapon - a modified SVU "Stormbreaker" sniper's rifle. Because of its ridiculous history - I got it for a box of vodka. With Duty, as always, there is a "leak" of new weapons. As a result, the rifle fell into the hands of a lone stalker. Not so long ago, he wandered here to us at Yantar. He was in a terrible state - hallucinating and behaving inappropriately. He kept saying that vodka prevented THEM from getting inside his head. Who was the "them" - I couldn't understand... Professor Kruglov had just finished distilling the alcohol... umm... Uh huh... Well, that stalker gave us everything he had, grabbed a box of vodka and left towards the Army Warehouses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zabavno">
		<text>Yeah, it's a funny story. And what's so special about this rifle?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="eta_vintovka">
		<text>Frankly, weapons are not included in the list of subjects, which I understand. If my memory doesn't fail me, the previous owner did mention, that this rifle has a lightened stock, an increased magazine capacity, high magnification sights and a built-in silencer. As a result, this allows for long distance shooting with minimal impact. According to him - it's the dream of any good shooter. Here, take it... and a couple of packs of cartridges for it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="spasibo">
		<text>Thank you. That sort of weapon can come in handy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_11_1_1_1">
		<text>Well Marked One, have you time to help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_11_1">
		<text>Sorry, I can't right now, maybe a little later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101">
		<text>Good to see you alive, Marked One! Did you find the laboratory in the Darkscape? What happened there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Well, I'll try to find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_1_1_1">
		<text>Then listen... this is not our only laboratory in the Zone, we have set up several in different places, close to the most interesting anomalies. Well, we have a measuring station in the area you know as the "Darkscape". My colleagues studied some of the primary anomalies that remained there after the first emission, when the Zone was first expanded. Some time ago, we lost all communications with that station and I am very worried about them. The area is difficult to access, you can only get there through the Dark Valley or the Garbage, and it's densely populated by bandits. I can't send a helicopter, the terrain is very rocky, with strong winds. Please go there and find out what happened. There's only one problem - I can't show you their exact location. Shortly before we lost communications, my colleagues said they found a perfectly safe place in Darkscape to use as research post, much better than where they were, and that they were beginning to move their equipment. Then there was a message that the transfer was complete and they're starting to power up the room, then the connection was lost. You have to find where they moved the post. One more thing - if something has happened to them, be sure to search the lab - there has to be their lab journal. Bring it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_1_1">
		<text>I'll try to help you any way I can.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Even if it's confidential, I can't refuse you the right to study it. Thank you for having brought it to me. And now tell me why Barkeep sent you to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Yes, here it is. It's fairly well preserved, I read a little on the way, I hope it's not confidential information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Oh my God. This is a terrible tragedy. I hope, they didn't suffer long. Controllers are extremely ruthless with their victims, they often eat them. Thank you, for ending their suffering. You visited the laboratory, did you manage to find the journal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1_1_1">
		<text>The laboratory was attacked by a controller, they probably moved into his den. All your colleagues were killed. They turned into zombies and I had to... well, you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1_1">
		<text>What happened there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_2_1">
		<text>I'll do everything in my power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_2">
		<text>Find it, Marked One. This data is very important to us, without it we can't continue our studies and get into the X-16 lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1">
		<text>Yes, I found it. Unfortunately I have some bad news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2_1-1">
		<text>Professor, I found the lab at the Darkscape. Unfortunately I have some bad news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2">
		<text>No, I haven't found them yet Professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2-1">
		<text>Professor, can you remind me why I need to look for the laboratory in the Darkscape?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_2-2">
		<text>This data is very important to us, without it we can't continue our studies and get into the X-16 lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101_1">
		<text>Thank you... uh-uh... marked one, right? You helped save my colleague Kruglov, and in gratitude, I would like to present you with one of our protective suits... A very handy thing, you know... You're a good fellow, a very capable stalker. Maybe you can do me one small favour, and I'll help you in response to your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1011">
		<text>I'm looking for the X-16 lab. Barkeep said that you know its whereabouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1012">
		<text>We've been interested in the X-16 lab for some time... Rather, the device inside, which generates emission that directly affects people's minds. I have to disappoint you: you can't enter without special psi-protection. The result is obviously tragic, even if you manage to avoid the hordes of zombies around the entrance to the lab, you risk turning into one of them. All this is very serious. However, in the journal that you brought from the Darkscape, I found a project for a device  which helps shield the emission, but for more accurate adjustment, it's necessary to conduct a number of additional measurements. If you help us with this, after some time we will probably be able to adjust the final prototype for field testing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1013">
		<text>Measurements?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1014">
		<text>If you accompany one of my staff he will take all the necessary measurements, I am prepared to build a prototype of a protective device, and give it to you. It will, most likely, allow you to get into the laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10141">
		<text>Okay, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101411">
		<text>Well, that's great! Talk to Kruglov and go. He's already equipped with all necessary gear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101412">
		<text>Good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10142">
		<text>Well, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101421">
		<text>Well, that's great! Talk with Semenov and head off. He already has all you need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101422">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10143">
		<text>No... I don't want to sign up for this right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101431">
		<text>It is a pity... I don't know when we'll be able to send an expedition for the measurements again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_11">
		<text>Yes? What are you interested in? Oh, hey, you're... uh-uh... Marked One, right? I've heard you are a very capable stalker. Maybe you can do me one small favour, and I'll help you in response to your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_111">
		<text>I'm looking for the X-16 lab. Barkeep said that you know its whereabouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12">
		<text>Thank you, Marked One, helping Kruglov escape. Take this protective suit as a reward for you help. I suspect you didn't just come for the reward, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121">
		<text>I'm looking for the X-16 lab. Barkeep said that you know its whereabouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1211">
		<text>We have been studying the emission coming from the X-16 lab, you won't be able to enter without special protection. We have developed an appropriate device, but we need to take a number of measurements so we can adjust it. If you can help us take these measurements, I will give you a customized prototype, which you can use to get into the lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12111">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121111">
		<text>Well, that's great, talk to Kruglov and go. He has everything you need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12112">
		<text>No, I don't agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121122">
		<text>It's a pity. Then I won't send anybody to take the measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21">
		<text>Yes? What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211">
		<text>Yes, we know about this lab, but its exact coordinates are not known. In addition, to try to get in there - is too dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111">
		<text>Continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21111">
		<text>We've been interested in the X-16 lab for some time... Rather, the device inside, which generates emission that directly affects people's minds. I have to disappoint you: you can't enter without special psi-protection. The result is obviously tragic, even if you manage to avoid the hordes of zombies around the entrance to the lab, you risk turning into one of them. All this is very serious. However, in the journal that you brought from the Darkscape, I found a project for a device  which helps shield the emission, but for more accurate adjustment, it's necessary to conduct a number of additional measurements. If you help us with this, after some time we will probably be able to adjust the final prototype for field testing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21112">
		<text>Okay, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211121">
		<text>Well, that's great! Talk to Kruglov and go. He has all the necessary gear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111211">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21113">
		<text>Okay, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211131">
		<text>Well, that's great! Talk with Semenov and head off. He already has all you need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211132">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211141">
		<text>Don't you understand? There's the emission. Nobody can get close to the place, they all turn into zombies. Without protection, it's a suicide mission, don't you see?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111411">
		<text>Hmm. It makes all the difference.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211142">
		<text>I don't care, just tell me what you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211143">
		<text>Well look, I've warned you. Vasilyev tried to deal with the problem in the lab. About a week ago, he, and a stalker named Ghost tried to get in. A few hours later the place shook and the emission abated, an hour after that, we received a signal from Vasilyev, the signal came from the marshes, but then disappeared. Apparently, it's possible that Vasilyev died... Try to find Vasilyev's corpse, he had accurate information about the laboratory: where it's located and how to get into it. Perhaps there's information on how to turn off the emission. It's likely the entry to the laboratory, is in the basement of one of the buildings at the factory site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211144">
		<text>That's great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21115">
		<text>No... I don't want to undertake it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211151">
		<text>It's a pity... I don't know when we will be able to send an expedition to take measurements again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_221">
		<text>Thank you... uh-uh... Marked One, right? You helped save my colleague Kruglov, and in gratitude, I would like to present you with one of our protective suits... A very handy thing, you know!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_231">
		<text>You did a great job, Marked One! Turning off the transmitter allows us to equip a new expedition and explore previously inaccessible areas. In the territory of the former Army Warehouses there is a transition to the Dead City, have you heard about this City?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2311">
		<text>Not sure whether I have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_241">
		<text>Yes, Marked One? What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31">
		<text>You did great job! If the measurements are correct, the prototype will provide maximum protection against emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311">
		<text>Glad to hear it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_3111">
		<text>Now your way to the lab is open... however, if the helmet loses power before the emission source is eliminated, you won't be able to go back in...\n \nWell, then, my friend. Our calculations helped to establish the approximate location of the transmitter, as well as the fact that it's located in an underground room. I marked it on your map. And further... I suggest you try our latest invention, the Bioradar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31111">
		<text>Exactly how do I get into the X-16 lab? Where is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311111">
		<text>Vasilyev tried to deal with that problem. About a week ago, he, and a stalker named Ghost tried to get in. A few hours later the place shook and the emission abated, an hour after that, we received a signal from Vasilyev, the signal came from the marshes, but then disappeared. Apparently, it's possible that Vasilyev died... Try to find Vasilyev's corpse, he had accurate information about the laboratory: where it's located and how to get into it. Perhaps there's information on how to turn off the emission.  I gave you all the known coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311112">
		<text>Hmm... Of course, it would be interesting to look at these documents. Do you think Vasilyev knew about these?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311113">
		<text>Maybe. You should start by finding Vasilyev's body - only in this case there is a chance to get accurate information on the whereabouts of the laboratory. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be in there somewhere. You know, I thought he knew much more about the X-16 lab than he said, and miraculously survived somehow... Although, of course, it's stupid to hope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311114">
		<text>Okay, I will try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41">
		<text>Why did he die? After all, you were supposed to protect him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411">
		<text>Kruglov was shot by zombies... I couldn't do anything. There were too many.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111">
		<text>Oh... well, how could this happen?... Shit, it all went awry... We'll have to call in additional staff... We have enough problems. Damn it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111">
		<text>Listen... Kruglov died, but I'm alive. Give me the prototype. I'll get into X-16 lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411111">
		<text>This is the prototype, but be careful: it's not configured properly. The device is faulty - it didn't protect our colleague. Although the device will weaken the emission it will not be able to provide maximum protection. You'll have to hurry on the way to the emitter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111111">
		<text>Exactly how do I get into the X-16 lab? Where is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111111">
		<text>Vasilyev tried to deal with the problem in the lab. About a week ago, he, and a stalker named Ghost tried to get in. A few hours later the place shook and the emission abated, an hour after that, we received a signal from Vasilyev, the signal came from the marshes, but then disappeared. Apparently, it's possible that Vasilyev died... Try to find Vasilyev's corpse, he had accurate information about the laboratory: where it's located and how to get into it. Perhaps there's information on how to turn off the emission.  I gave you all the known coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41112">
		<text>Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41113">
		<text>You should start by finding Vasilyev's body - only in this case there is a chance to get accurate information on the whereabouts of the laboratory. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be in there somewhere. You know, I thought he knew much more about the X-16 lab than he said, and miraculously survived somehow... Although, of course, it's stupid to hope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41114">
		<text>Ok, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51">
		<text>Why is he dead? After all, you were supposed to protect him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511">
		<text>Kruglov was shot by zombies... I couldn't do anything. There were too many.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_5111">
		<text>Oh... well, how could this happen?... Shit, it all went awry... We'll have to call in additional staff... We have enough problems. Damn it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51111">
		<text>Listen... Kruglov died, but I'm alive. Give me the prototype. I'll get into X-16 lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511111">
		<text>This is the prototype, but be careful: it's not configured properly. The device is faulty - it didn't protect our colleague. Although the device will weaken the emission it will not be able to provide maximum protection. You'll have to hurry on the way to the emitter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_5111111">
		<text>Exactly how do I get into the X-16 lab? Where is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511111111">
		<text>Vasilyev tried to deal with the problem in the lab. About a week ago, he, and a stalker named Ghost tried to get in. A few hours later the place shook and the emission abated, an hour after that, we received a signal from Vasilyev, the signal came from the marshes, but then disappeared. Apparently, it's possible that Vasilyev died... Try to find Vasilyev's corpse, he had accurate information about the laboratory: where it's located and how to get into it. Perhaps there's information on how to turn off the emission.  I gave you all the known coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51112">
		<text>Hmm... Of course, it would be interesting to look at these documents. Do you think Vasilyev knew about these?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51113">
		<text>Maybe. You should start by finding Vasilyev's body - only in this case there is a chance to get accurate information on the whereabouts of the laboratory. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be in there somewhere. You know, I thought he knew much more about the X-16 lab than he said, and miraculously survived somehow... Although, of course, it's stupid to hope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51114">
		<text>Okay, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_61">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_71">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81">
		<text>Too bad that Kruglov died... Alas, nothing can bring him back. First of all, I need measurement results. Did you bring them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81_1">
		<text>Too bad that Semenov died... Alas, nothing can bring him back. First of all, I need measurement results. Did you bring them?</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_811">
		<text>Yes, here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_8111">
		<text>Well, I'll set up the prototype. Wait for me here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81111">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_812">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_8121">
		<text>So get them quickly! Without them I cannot set up the prototype.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_91">
		<text>You did great! If the measurements are correct, the prototype will provide maximum protection against the emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_911">
		<text>Can you be more precise?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9111">
		<text>Marked One, you will be able to get into the lab now, but if you don't turn off the emitter, even with psi-protection, you won't last long there. We have calculated the approximate location of the emitter - it's located in an underground room. I marked it's position on your map. And further... I suggest you try our latest invention.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9112">
		<text>How do I get into the X-16 lab? Where exactly is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9113">
		<text>Vasilyev tried to deal with the problem in the lab. About a week ago, he, and a stalker named Ghost tried to get in. A few hours later the place shook and the emission abated, an hour after that, we received a signal from Vasilyev, the signal came from the marshes, but then disappeared. Apparently, it's possible that Vasilyev died... Try to find Vasilyev's corpse, he had accurate information about the laboratory: where it's located and how to get into it. Perhaps there's information on how to turn off the emission.  I gave you all the known coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9114">
		<text>Hmmm ... Of course it would be interesting to look at these documents. Do you think Vasilyev knew about these?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9115">
		<text>Maybe. You should start by finding Vasilyev's body - only in this case there is a chance to get accurate information on the whereabouts of the laboratory. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be in there somewhere. You know, I thought he knew much more about the X-16 lab than he said, and miraculously survived somehow... Although, of course, it's stupid to hope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9116">
		<text> Okay, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_101">
		<text>I don't have time...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111">
		<text>The professor asked me to accompany you to the measurement site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_1111">
		<text>That's it! We have to leave immediately. There's nothing left to do here, but go with you... I think we can handle it quickly. The main thing - is to keep away from the living dead. Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11111">
		<text>Ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111111">
		<text>You know what... it's probably better if you go first. You have more experience with zombies than I have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_1111111">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_21">
		<text>Wow! Marked One in person! You finally got here. Talk with Professor Sakharov, he wants to thank you for saving me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_31">
		<text>Later, later!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_41">
		<text>Welcome, Marked One! How are things progressing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_51">
		<text>Yes, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_511">
		<text>The professor asked me to accompany you to the measurement site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_512">
		<text>That's it! We have to leave immediately. There's nothing left to do here, but go with you... I think we can handle it quickly. The main thing - is to keep away from the living dead. Are you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_513">
		<text>Ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_514">
		<text>You know what... you should probably go first. The zombies are all stirred up, and you're more experienced than me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_515">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_61">
		<text>I'm sorry, I don't have time right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_71">
		<text>Hi, Marked One! How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_81">
		<text>Wait a bit... We need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_91">
		<text>Wait a minute! I'm still not finished with the measurements!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_11">
		<text>Yipe!.. Ouch... argh...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_111">
		<text>Still alive? Well, get up... Get up slowly. You'll be fine. It will soon pass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_21">
		<text>Hi, Marked One! How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_211">
		<text>Done! I'm chock-full of measurements, it's time to go back!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_31">
		<text>Hi, Marked One! How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Horror_time_ecolog_dialog -->
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_0">
		<text>Listen, Professor! I have a question!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_1">
		<text>Go ahead! I've been showed down with scientific work lately, but nevertheless, I still have time to talk to visitors. They don't come here often.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_2">
		<text>Could you, as a scientist, explain something to me... uh-uh... a certain phenomenon?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_3">
		<text>Well, young man, tell me, which one. The staff of this laboratory, and especially myself, are very interested in a variety of different phenomena, events... We wish to understand them from a scientific point of view. It's possible that I can help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_4">
		<text>Tell me, do you know anything about the Time of Terror?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_5">
		<text>Oh... Marked One, you touch on one of the most exciting and challenging aspects of my work! But I'll try to explain.\n \nYou see, periodically in the exclusion Zone, the so-called "conventional" emissions are accompanied by powerful psi radiation emissions, which make people hallucinate and delusional. This radiation is different from what we are studying here at Yantar. It's not as intense, but has the ability to travel considerable distances, almost without losing its properties. Unfortunately, the nature of propagation of the radiation is such that the precise location of its source can't be determined. I can only say that it's quite far from here.\n \nThat's all I know about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="horror_time_ecolog_story_6">
		<text>Thanks, Professor!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- yan_random_quest_first_talk -->
	<string id="yan_random_quest_0">
		<text>Professor, do you need any materials for your research?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_random_quest_1">
		<text>You know, perhaps, I do. I know perfectly well that the research centre, which is located outside the Perimeter and conducts extensive research in different areas, has exhausted its research materials. The centre is using all possible means to obtain objects from the anomalous Zone. Even asking our modest research lab for help. Let's do this: You come here from time to time, and I will tell you what is needed. When you have gathered these samples, simply return them at your first opportunity. Does this suit you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_random_quest_2">
		<text>Is it possible to get the required list remotely?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_random_quest_3">
		<text>Yes, of course. A list of required samples are sent to me after each emission, at the same time I will pass it on to you. Well, I'm glad that everything fell into place. I hope we have a long and productive relationship!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- yan_random_quest_give_item_list -->
	<string id="yan_random_quest_give_item_list">
		<text>Professor, is there a special order for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_random_quest_list_job">
		<text>At this point, the following artifacts and mutant parts are required:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_random_quest_seacrh_item">
		<text>Let me look what I have in stock from the list...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_random_quest_job_abandon">
		<text>Thank you, but these orders don't interest me.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- teleport_trap_dialogs -->
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello, Professor! Can you offer me an interesting task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_1">
		<text>My information channel has received information about a strange artifact, it's located South of the mountain range in the woods and West of the sawmill. Our staff tried to get it - but failed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_2">
		<text>Why is that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_3">
		<text>Mmm, how can I say it... In general, it is impossible to pick up the artifact - it runs away... Literally. Our people spent more than three days trying to capture it, but failed. As a result, I made the decision to involve stalkers in this work as soon as possible, only the ones that have proved they can cooperate with us, and won't steal the artifact. Maybe you can catch the artifact, Marked One? Please help me, I will be in your debt forever.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_31">
		<text>I'll gladly take this case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_311">
		<text>I knew I could rely on you. Now your job is to catch the artifact and simply scan it with a special device, which I'll give you. Just take the artifact in hand, if you can, and wait for about 10-15 seconds. I will tell you the results with pleasure - I know that it would interest you. Hopefully, you'll get the artifact. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_32">
		<text>No, not at this time, Professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_dialog_321">
		<text>It's a pity, I counted on you... Well, I'll no longer bother you on this task. I hope that we will be able to recruit other specialists...</text>
	</string>
	<!--
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_0">
		<text>Вообщем, не понятно с этим артефактом (рассказать о произошедшем)...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_1">
		<text>Интересненько... Как будто артефакт имеет зачатки примитивного разума. Да еще обладает телепортационными свойствами! О чем-то подобном рассказывали сталкеры-старожилы, но вот документальное подтверждение вижу и слышу впервые. Эх, дорого бы я отдал, чтобы получить его. Коллеги из Центра уж точно обрадуются этому. Ладно, если нельзя его транспортировать, то попробуем исследовать его в полевых условиях. Я вам выдам датчик, которым пользуются наши полевые сотрудники. А вы попробуете просканировать артефакт и поле, в котором он находится. Беретесь? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_11">
		<text>Конечно берусь - нужно идти до конца.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_111">
		<text>Вот и отлично! Жду вас с результатами. Да! Чтобы просканировать артефакт, необходимо просто взять его в руки, я вам сообщу, когда будет готов анализ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_12">
		<text>Нет, спасибо, чуть не чокнулся, когда выбирался из того места!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_research_art_121">
		<text>Жалко, что вы отказываетесь. Возможно, только вы бы и смогли получить положительный результат. Ну ладно, отрядим других сталкеров...</text>
	</string>
	-->
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_0">
		<text>I obtained the data, but this artifact nearly killed me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_1">
		<text>The data - that's excellent! But what exactly happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_2">
		<text>Well, I was really thrown all over the area - you weren't mistaken.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_3">
		<text>Well, are you alright? Hands and feet in place. Head too. I had no doubts that you could handle it. Maybe there's something else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_4">
		<text>An anomalous field formed around me - I barely got out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_5">
		<text>The field was a kind of protective reaction of the artifact towards you and your actions. Or maybe not against you, but the SAA. It will be necessary to reflect on this phenomenon after I analyse the results. You have the data, you said?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_6">
		<text>Yes, here it is, as you requested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_7">
		<text>So ... Let's see ... Hmm, there's an unusual shift in the delta wave. This is interesting!\n \nOf course, I could be mistaken, but a special alloy called "Prudenko's Isolate", named after the head of the research group, can be an effective countermeasure to this artifact. If this alloy meets all expectations, it will be possible to produce special containers for anomalous formations in the future. We've just produced a prototype of such a container for field testing. Hopefully, it will be able to contain all the negative effects of the artifact. \n \nWill you participate in the experiment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_71">
		<text>Yes, Professor, I'll bring the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_711">
		<text>Good! Here's the "Prudenko's Isolate"  alloy container. In order to capture an artifact, you just need to set the container on the ground and steer the artifact as closely as possible to it - the rest is automated. I'll take the SAA - it's no longer needed. I hope that everything goes without complications. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_72">
		<text>Sorry, but my life is as dear to me as memory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_catch_art_721">
		<text>It's bad when people stop one step away from victory. Thank you for the resultant data, but I can't give you a reward. The arrangement was for the delivery of an artifact, nothing less. I hope that in the future our cooperation will be more fruitful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_finish_0">
		<text>Phew, I brought the artifact. Once the artifact was captured, I was attacked by a chimera. Was the artifact responsible?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_finish_1">
		<text>Yeah, an interesting artifact. Evidently it didn't want be captured. Well, I hope there won't be any more incidents. Did anything strange happen on the road back?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_finish_2">
		<text>Well, it would periodically jump inside the box as if wanted to get out. Other than that, everything else was normal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_finish_3">
		<text>Well, okay. Today I will send this case to the Research Centre. Oh yeah, I almost forgot. For our valiant work, take this generous gift. I hope that it will compensate you for the hardship the artifact caused. In about two or three days, I'll be able to tell you what the Centre thinks about it. I think that you would be interested. Thank you very much for your help, Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_art_destiny_0">
		<text>Professor, hello! What are the results of the study of the artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="teleport_trap_art_destiny_1">
		<text>Hello, Marked One! I can't tell you, because of their absence. There was a strange incident. On the same day, I sent the case with the artifact by helicopter to the Centre. My parcel reached the destination without incident. But the next day when the scientists opened the briefcase to begin to study the artifact, it had... disappeared. Completely. They searched throughout the entire Centre for it - but it was not found. They even sent someone back to the place where you found it. It was not there. Even I, don't know what to do. If you find the artifact somewhere in the Zone, please let me know...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_talk_about_psycho_0">
		<text>I have a request of a personal nature, can you listen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_talk_about_psycho_1">
		<text>Yes, I will listen carefully.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_talk_about_psycho_2">
		<text>Will You help a poor fellow... (Psycho explains the situation)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_talk_about_psycho_3">
		<text>Mm, I don't know what to say. I agree, it's a sad and sorry tale. But alas, I can't help you. I'm not qualified. Judging from your description, the stalker's mind is damaged. Most likely, under the influence of the controller in the bloodsucker's village at the Army Warehouses. In general, Dr. Marsh could help me, so where is he now? We can't send him to the mainland - his brain has hardly suffered enough abnormal change which could be of interest to the scientists. Now, if he was an employee of our modest laboratory... But what is not, is not.\nBased on what you told me, the stalker won't last long,  I can assume that he is now experiencing acute depressive psychosis, and is suicidal. As an option, you should spend as much time as possible with him, and possibly the psychosis will pass by itself. Well, good luck to you, I'm sorry I can't help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_talk_about_psycho_4">
		<text>That's too bad. Okay, thanks for the help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_psycho_talk_about_psycho_5">
		<text>Such is life, you don't always get what you want. Believe me, I'm a veteran who has seen many things in life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Brother, are you following me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>I don't understand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>You're not. I just realised it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>What are you doing here? Are you part of the bunker protection?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>No, I'm from the expedition guard... Or rather, from the former guard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Were you attacked?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Worse... But it's not your problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Whatever you say. Listen, I'm looking for a stalker named Radioman. He came here about two weeks ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Yes, he came here. He was very "smart" and a real master with military equipment. You won't find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>What happened, did he meet his end?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>The scientists had organized an expedition to explore new anomalies. It was led by a post-graduate student named Perepelkin, and consisted of a security group of four people: The Captain and three soldiers of which I was one, and a freelance Stalker as an assistant. The research area is not far from the bunker on the approaches to the plant. In general, we arrived, spread some scientific gizmo's, then the graduate student began to explore... The day passed, all was quiet, we had stopped a couple of Snorks. The next morning, the trouble began.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>The commander sent me to a small road to scout the terrain. Perepelkin had just started his studies, all the equipment was prepared. While the others guarded him, I had to explore the area and scare off any zombies that I saw coming out of the plant. I was on patrol, when suddenly, something happened in the camp, and then I heard the screams... I rushed there, it took less than a minute, but saw nothing - the scientist, my commander and his comrades had disappeared! There was no blood, no spent cartridges - nothing! Then I went to pieces.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Strange.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>That's how it was: The men, were gone in a moment, the Zone had "swallowed them up"! I'd heard such stories from stalkers before.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>Radioman disappeared, too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>Yes, together with them. He helped the scientist with the equipment, he was always at his side.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_18">
		<text>Did you look for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_19">
		<text>I was there all day searching. On the whole, I searched both in the marshes and at the plant, as much as the radiation would allow. There was nothing and no one. Now I face a court martial and prison, because I'm under suspicion. I'm done for!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_20">
		<text>Let's look for them again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_21">
		<text>I told you, I've already searched for them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_22">
		<text>What have you got to lose? Maybe I'll find something you missed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_23">
		<text>Come on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_24">
		<text>Show me the place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_25">
		<text>We'll wait until the emission ends and then I'll show you this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog1_phrase_1">
		<text>It happened here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog1_phrase_2">
		<text>Yeah... That's the radio, near the container with instruments... Everything is still in place. Except the people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog1_phrase_3">
		<text>Let's examine everything once again. By the way, do you suspect that someone outside the Zone may be involved, someone more specific? Mercenaries, for example? Maybe they wanted the scientist or your commander.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog1_phrase_4">
		<text>Do you suggest we search for traces of a kidnapping? If it's true, then the kidnappers had the highest level of training, because everything happened so fast... I can't imagine that happening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog1_phrase_5">
		<text>It's better that we search again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog2_phrase_1">
		<text>Think so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog2_phrase_2">
		<text>I think I found something... A piece of paper with some writing. It got wet from the rain, almost everything is washed away, I'll try to decipher it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog2_phrase_3">
		<text>Maybe it's just rubbish?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog2_phrase_4">
		<text>No, wait... Give me time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog2_phrase_5">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_1">
		<text>Well, how did you go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_2">
		<text>I think I know what this is - a page from our commander's notebook. Those are the coordinates of a certain point. But how to find it - that's the question.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_3">
		<text>What's the problem?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_4">
		<text>The fact is, that these coordinates can only be shown on a special map, which our commander had.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_5">
		<text>Then the coordinates are useless to us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_6">
		<text>Not really. A copy of the map will be with his personal belongings, which are in a box in the bunker. We have to find it and locate the point, perhaps, there is something important there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_7">
		<text>Where are your commander's things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_8">
		<text>They are in his private box, which is located in the recreation room in the bunker. But it's locked, the commander always carried the key with him. It seems he had a spare key that he hid somewhere, not in the bunker but in the territory outside - he was worried that stalkers who came into the bunker to sell artifacts, would find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_9">
		<text>Any ideas where to find the spare key? The territory is large.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_10">
		<text>Honestly, I don't know where it is. You'll have to look. By the way, I do remember: talking among ourselves, I found out that the commander has a briefcase with personal documents and money, hidden near the bunker. It seems, he collected a sum of money from some "sinister" dealings for a comfortable life behind the perimeter - I don't know what they were, I didn't interfere with this business. If the key is hidden somewhere, it will most likely be in the briefcase.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lager_dialog3_phrase_11">
		<text>Well, I'll find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>What brought you to the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>There was a choice, either come here or go on trial... It was nothing serious, just simple hooliganism. My father's cousin rescued me, so to speak. It almost made no difference: here or two years behind bars, it's the same shit. I've been here a year already. Almost...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Well, yes, the lesser of two evils, as they say... Listen, what did the scientists investigate here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>There, you see, near the fence? A pillar of smoke and purple flashes? That's exactly what they were studying here on that fateful day. A new anomaly, the motherfucker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>What kind of anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>This thingamajig brother, is almost useless. First, it has no effect on humans or other animals. Secondly, it doesn't produce artifacts, so you won't be able to profit from it. Third, there are only a few of these thingamajigs in the Zone, you can count them on one hand. Four-eyes thought it was good fortune that one of them formed here, only a hundred metres from the base was, so he decided to investigate it. They have only one theory about this anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>What's that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>It seems that this is not an anomaly at all, but a kind of "worm hole" into another dimension. This scientist whom we protected, - this post-graduate student, Perepelkin - wanted to defend his thesis on this hogwash so he could obtain his Doctorate. So here you go. And now he has no thesis or Degree. Even the devil himself, doesn't know what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>I've seen the same anomaly in other places.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>I know, I've seen them too: one at the Garbage, another somewhere else, probably the Cordon... You know what I think: whether this devilry is connected with my group's disappearance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>You mean to say that this theory is confirmed by the scientists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>You know, the main purpose of the expedition was to conduct trials of new equipment on these anomalies. If there was something there to substantiate, then these devices would have provided some data... In short, I'm not good at this, I only got a "C" in physics. I'm just saying, what I heard from the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Were you familiar with Radioman?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_anomaly_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>No. He talked more with Perepelkin, than he did with us. He only spoke to us if he wanted a light, or help with a crate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I've brought something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>That was quick! What did you find? Was the map there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Then give it to me, I have to compare notes with the coordinates of this schematic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Here you go:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>So, what do we have here?... Yes, the numbers tally! It's somewhere here at Yantar. So, the commander of the group is alive and is trying to send us a signal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Where is the place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>One moment ... There. It seems to be somewhere around here... Stalker, follow me! I need to check the data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_map_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Lead on</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_sign_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>You see something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_sign_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Right about there, at the base of the pipes, between the marsh and the fence... Green smoke - our prearranged signal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_sign_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>You suggest I survey the area?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_sign_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Of course, do you just want to sit idly by? Let's do this: you search the gully, but be careful - it could be a trap! I'll cover you from up here on the hill. I have a sniper rifle - a SVD.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_sign_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>It sounds promising.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Help!... Mm-m...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>What's wrong?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>We are very weak... we have no food, very little water... Perepelkin asked me to... we can't go on any more!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Where's the scientist? Where's the group?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>They are in "Wonderland"... I was sent through by an increased pulse, now my brain is boiling... I'm screwed, Oh...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>What's "Wonderland"? What is this pulse?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>It's necessary to use a prototype... Find Radioman... He knows how to handle it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Prototype? What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Scanner... It's the only thing that can get us out... I've had it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_zombsold_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>Hold on, I have a med kit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Why did you shoot the survivor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>He turned into a zombie!.. Did he not? Is that so bad? What did he say to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>He said that the scientist and his companions are still alive, but are somewhere in the middle of nowhere. In a sort of "Wonderland"... It looks like he was delirious, the poor man had suffered brain damage. Something is wrong here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Yeah... And what else did he tell you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>That I should find a prototype and learn from Radioman how to use it. What kind of a prototype, and where the hell is Radioman - he didn't say, or rather, he didn't have time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>You say he mentioned a prototype... Did he say where to get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Do you know what it is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Um, no. Did he tell you where it was, or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>You say you don't know what he's talking about, but you want to know where it is. How is it so?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Perhaps this is something that will help us figure it out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>No buddy, there's something wrong here. Come on admit it, what do you know about the prototype?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>I know - nothing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_demask_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>You lie!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Wait, you bastard!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Please don't kill me! Only I know how to save the scientist and the soldiers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>I'm one of the guards...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>That "zombie" in the swamp was one of the missing men with the same name as yours. Did you shoot him intentionally?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>No, not really! Through the sights, I couldn't make out who it was. I only noticed that he moved and acted, like a zombie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>He managed to tell that the others are still alive, but time is short. I'll give you one last chance to tell everything that happened, otherwise I'll take you to Sakharov and tell him you're a suspect, he'll hand you over to the military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Okay, okay! But I have already told you everything as it happened... With a few exceptions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Go on!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>The fact is, I actually saw what happened to the group. I wasn't in patrol, but was together with everybody in the temporary camp. As I said, Perepelkin, the post-graduate student planned to study the new anomaly in detail and scored a scientific equipment container for the purpose. That morning, the most important part was planned - a pulsed scan. In the laboratory, a sophisticated generator has been assembled that emitted special kinds of impulses that had some impact on the anomaly. With this, Perepelkin intended to increase the anomaly's power, because according to his theory, the anomalies of this type are in "sleep" mode, that is, at minimum power. With the generator sending out special impulses it was possible for it to "awaken".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>Continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>As well as the others, I assisted the scientist, it was easy, simply press certain buttons at certain times on his orders, bring and carry away things, and so on. At first everything was fine, and even interesting - when the power to the anomaly was increased, something started to fly out making strange sounds. It turned out that this was the birth of the artifacts, and according to Perepelkin, such artifacts that even the scientists themselves had never seen. Then the trouble began: when generator power was increased to the maximum, there was a terrible roar. The anomaly turned black in its centre, there was a dark blue sphere the size of a ball, which slowly began to grow. Suddenly we felt the movement of air, which with every passing second was getting stronger and stronger, the anomaly pulling us inward. Leaves were sucked from the trees and the dry grass bent towards the centre of the anomaly. The wind increased to such an extent that it whistled in my ears, and then - the stream of air began to roar and it became difficult to stay on your feet. The scientist gave me the signal to turn off the generator, which I did, but the awakened anomaly continued to draw in all that was around. Initially, small items from our camp were drawn in: a bucket, a tent, deck chairs... Then it became difficult to stand upright. The first to go was Perepelkin, who was closest to the epicentre of the anomaly. When he reached the strange sphere, he suddenly disappeared. The commander shouted at us to retreat and tried to crawl away, but... In short, all of them were sucked in by an unknown force, and then they were gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>And you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>I managed to stay behind only because I managed to grab hold of a small tree that grew nearby. About three minutes later the anomaly finally discharged itself and died down... I immediately tried to contact them, but their radio was silent. I was going to report all this to the scientists in the bunker, but changed my mind: they wouldn't have believed me and would have held me responsible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>And you came up with the story that the group had disappeared for unknown reasons?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>... and waited for the arrival of the Military Accidents Investigator. He should be here in a couple of days.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>You said that you know how to help the missing? You're convinced that they survived and are still alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_18">
		<text>Yes, and here's why: I began to receive messages from them. Somehow they managed to throw out from where they are, a note or two  and different things... In short, I realized that they were still alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_19">
		<text>What is the "prototype"? Why is it necessary to find Radioman? And how to get people out of the anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_20">
		<text>"Prototype" - it's an upgrade for the scientific detector, a prototype of the pulse generator which "awakened" the anomaly. It creates a weak pulse, but when used as intended, it may be possible to reactivate the anomaly and pull people out of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_21">
		<text>But you said that the anomaly at it's peak power draws everything into itself, so then, how can we save them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_22">
		<text>In fact, there were two generators. The main generator would deliver strictly positive value pulses, while the backup would generate only negative ones. Therefore, it's possible to "awaken" the anomaly, or "Dark Zone" as Perepelkin called it, in the opposite direction. Then it won't draw everything in itself, on the contrary... Though, it's only a theory. But it's worth trying, don't you think?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_23">
		<text>Where is the "prototype"? And how do I contact Radioman?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_24">
		<text>Perepelkin was the designer of the "prototype" and as Radioman was his constant assistant, he would know how to operate it. Or know... If he is still alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_25">
		<text>Without Radioman, could we still master the instrument?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_26">
		<text>As a matter of fact, he participated in the initiative research of similar anomalies in other places in the Zone - he took the "Prototype" with him to scan a "Dark Zone" in Rostok. He hid it there somewhere, and then, as I said, he disappeared. So, if you want to get the "prototype", you have to find Radioman's cache in the Wild Territory. I have some thoughts on where it could be located.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_27">
		<text>That's good. How did they managed to throw out one of the soldiers "from there"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_28">
		<text>That I don't know. But, if you think logically, then: the main pulse generator was also sucked into the "Dark Zone", together with some auxiliary equipment and a storage battery. So they could try to start the return process "from there", although...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_29">
		<text>Although what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_30">
		<text>The fact that I haven't told you something: the main pulse generator is fuelled from the unique artifacts of these anomalies. The "Prototype" was constructed when a scientist came into possession of a hitherto unknown "afterlife"  artifact, as the stalkers call it. They differed from the others in that they consisted of materials unknown to science. They had many properties, but their main value consisted of the fact that with their help, it was possible to build a special kind of pulse generator...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_31">
		<text>...which was used by Perepelkin for his experiments. So, in order to fire up the second generator, these artifacts are also needed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_32">
		<text>Yes, the "prototype" was primarily created for the production of these artifacts. Its weak impulses provoke the "Dark Zone" to give birth to artifacts, that is, it's a tool for generating these working materials. The main unit was one of the two large generators which disappeared. Thank God that we still have the spare. It's something we can use to try to facilitate their return.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_33">
		<text>I'm a little confused... Can you explain the problem more clearly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_34">
		<text>First, we need to find the "prototype".\nSecondly - we need to scan the "Dark Zones" and extract the artifacts.\nThird - we need to place the artifacts in the spare generator and try to extract the scientist and soldiers.\n Is that clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_35">
		<text>Yes. But where is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_36">
		<text>Radioman was good at hiding his caches, but loved a good drink, after which he became over talkative... In short, I have a theory about that. But the Wild Territory is dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_37">
		<text>Let's go there together, you look for it, and I'll cover your lying ass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_38">
		<text>Don't go. I'm telling you - it's dangerous. I don't want to risk my ass. I heard what mercenaries do to stalkers - the instrument is not worth it. Go alone if you want. You're a strong guy, maybe you'll find something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_39">
		<text>Bloody coward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_40">
		<text>Maybe a coward, but I'm still alive. Here's the deal. Radioman concealed the prototype somewhere near the railway wagons. You need to search the area around them, the hiding place is somewhere near them. I outlined the approximate locations for you to search on the map in your PDA. Find the "Prototype" - scan the Dark Zones - when you've collected the artifacts - come back to me. I'll wait for you at the camp near the Dark Zone and prepare the generator.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_41">
		<text>How do you know that there is a cache?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_42">
		<text>Perepelkin overheard Radioman one night. So what? Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_say_true_dialog_phrase_43">
		<text>To hell with you, I'll look for the device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_suit_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I found the suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_suit_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Thank you. Now we go to the Rostok transition.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_suit_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Погнали к ТЗ -->
	<string id="yan_soldier_lets_go_final_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, now what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lets_go_final_dialog_1">
		<text>The generator is ready. Now, for the hardest part - get the guys out of the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lets_go_final_dialog_2">
		<text>The hardest part? That was getting these artifacts out of the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lets_go_final_dialog_3">
		<text>Okay, okay. Take the generator and go to the Dark Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_lets_go_final_dialog_4">
		<text>I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_place_generator_dialog_0">
		<text>Here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_place_generator_dialog_1">
		<text>That's the spot. Place the generator on the ground at the edge of the anomaly and turn it on. Be careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_place_generator_dialog_2">
		<text>I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_0">
		<text>What the fuck happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_1">
		<text>He he, it's all over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_2">
		<text>What did you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_3">
		<text>Destroyed the anomaly, of course. Now my "colleagues" will never get out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_4">
		<text>You sick freak! Why have you destroyed them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_5">
		<text>Perepelkin caught me stealing detectors from Sakharov's warehouse. He threatened to hand me over to Duty, if I didn't agree to help him conduct experiments on the Dark Zone. I knew I had to deal with that bastard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_6">
		<text>Wait, so you're...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_7">
		<text>Radioman, of course. You catch on quick! I agreed to go with them. Only, during the experiment, instead of gently applying the pulses to probe the anomaly, I overloaded it. Something happened that shouldn't have - they all got sucked into the anomaly. I just had to get the confiscated detectors and get out of Yantar. But I couldn't return to the bunker dressed as I was, no one would have believed me - it would've been clear who was responsible. So I got a similar suit that worn by the guards, and went to the bunker and informed them of the tragedy. These guys are constantly changing, nobody really remembers their faces, particularly those that don't remove their helmets. I hoped that before the next shift change, I could get back into the warehouse and then be on my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_8">
		<text>Would it not have been easier to buy the equipment instead?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_9">
		<text>Of course, it's easier - when you have money. I got cleaned out at the Bar. I had nowhere to go, Owl would have ripped off my skin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_10">
		<text>Why did you let me help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_11">
		<text>When you first stumbled in here, I thought you'd understand the hopelessness of the situation and fuck off. And then, when the real Epifantsev dropped out of the anomaly, I got scared. God forbid, if Perepelkin or the captain appeared next. Then I'm dead. I had to close the anomaly, come what may. Then you helped me. You even got the artifacts. Well, I configured the generator control button to short out the battery. Of course, quite by chance, he-he. Now, no generator, no anomaly - you beauty!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_12">
		<text>You bastard. Well, I don't care - I came here on business. I need the flash card.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_13">
		<text>Yeah fuck you, you're not getting it. Why should I give it to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_14">
		<text>Well, if you don't, I'll go to Sakharov and tell him everything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_15">
		<text>I need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_16">
		<text>So do I. Come on, hand it over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_17">
		<text>Freak.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_18">
		<text>Well, if you don't want to in an amicable way...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_19">
		<text>Well okay, okay, there's no need to get aggressive. Here you are. Say hello to Perepelkin for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_20">
		<text>What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_explain_dialog_21">
		<text>See you, motherfucker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_1">
		<text>Thank you very much! If not for you, we would never have got out of there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_2">
		<text>Taking Radioman on board was a bad idea.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, you're right. But he was the only one who knew anything about the Dark Zones! He came to us in the bunker, all excited about them. I was doing a thesis on the subject, and became interested in what he knew. I begged him to come with me on an expedition, that fortunately was only a short distance away, but he flatly refused. And then, as it turned out - I caught him as he rummaged through our warehouse. Well, I threatened to tell Professor Sakharov about what happened, if he wouldn't help me. You have to try to understand! Who knew that everything would turn out the way it did.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_4">
		<text>Probably, only a scientist would be able to understand such eagerness. Where did you go when you were sucked into the anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_5">
		<text>Hard to say. It looked similar to our world, but everything possessed very strange properties... As if each item - was an artifact. When samples made from various materials were subjected to abnormal influences here, we observed something similar. We never knew this. We can only acquire such knowledge by studying the Dark Zone! My thesis will cause a furore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_6">
		<text>I'm really glad you got out. There was certainly nothing to eat there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_7">
		<text>You're right, damn right! Once again, thank you for your help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_8">
		<text>Next time, don't mess with questionable people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_9">
		<text>I don't see Radioman among you, what happened to him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_perepelkin_dialog_10">
		<text>How could you? There he is. It was he who sent us here, the bastard. He came to us in the bunker, all excited about the Dark Zones. I was doing a thesis on the subject, and became interested in what he knew. I begged him to come with me on an expedition, that fortunately was only a short distance away, but he flatly refused. And then, as it turned out - I caught him as he rummaged through our warehouse. Well, I threatened to tell Professor Sakharov about what happened, if he wouldn't help me. You have to try to understand! You have to try to understand! Who knew that everything would turn out the way it did.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_1">
		<text>Apparently, we are indebted to you for our return from this hell hole!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_2">
		<text>Arrest your soldier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_3">
		<text>What soldier? This scum, is a stalker named Radioman. During the experiment, he tampered with something on the generator and we got dragged into the anomaly. No one had time to figure out what happened. We were trapped in some godforsaken place - the wood didn't burn, there was no water or even any living creatures. It's a miracle we got out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_4">
		<text>So, this is Radioman? He told me that his name was Epifantsev.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_5">
		<text>He lied, he was looking after his own ass. Had he returned to the camp alone, he would have been quickly put against the wall. Epifantsev was with us. When we found ourselves on the other side of the anomaly, there turned out to be a "portal", or something like that. I tried to throw some things through, like notes, in the hope that someone out there would find them and realise what was happening. Nothing came of it. Maybe someone did find them, but no one came to our aid. So we decided to send a human. Perepelkin, our scientist, collected the pulse generator from the trash that came through with us, and Epifantsev volunteered to be the guinea pig. Alas, that too, didn't work out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_6">
		<text>He came through, I saw him. But he really didn't have time to say much, Radioman shot him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_7">
		<text>That scum! He probably collected all my notes. Well now, he's really going to get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_8">
		<text>What will happen to him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_9">
		<text>He will be taken away to face a court-martial. This freak has already earned himself a trip to the gallows.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_10">
		<text>Probably, it serves him right. Look, you did happen to find a flash drive on him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_11">
		<text>Yes, I found one. Why, do you need it? Is it something important?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_12">
		<text>Not really, it just shows a cache with ammunition. It would have come in handy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_13">
		<text>Sorry, I'm seizing it. Thank you for freeing us. Well, if you need ammunition, take some grenades for your grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_14">
		<text>Thank you, they'll come in handy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_15">
		<text>Obviously he's Radioman.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_16">
		<text>Yeah, he's still a scumbag all the same. In was his fault we were sent God knows where.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_17">
		<text>By the way, he told me that his name was Epifantsev.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_18">
		<text>That scum! He probably collected all my notes. Well now, he's really going to get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_19">
		<text>Probably, it serves him right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_20">
		<text>Thank you for rescuing us. Well, if your problem is ammunition, take a couple of grenades for your grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_dz_captain_dialog_21">
		<text>See you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2311_1_1">
		<text>Thanks, I'll keep it in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2311_1">
		<text>It's "Town-32"', an old closed military town, named in the old Soviet tradition. It's like Pripyat, in the Ivankov district of the Kiev region of Ukraine. There was a major expedition of Western scientists there, who faced... let's say, some unforeseen circumstances. The expedition was almost completely destroyed, and from my information there weren't many survivors. Those that did, went crazy. Since then, stalkers call it the "Dead City". If you're going there to investigate it, take extreme precautions - in any case, don't go alone, don't sleep outside shelter in its territory and if you begin hallucinating - try to leave it as soon as possible. And yes, one other thing - as a sign of my appreciation for your help, I put aside something for you. If you're thinking of exploring the Dead City, or going to the Radar, this device will be helpful. It's an automatic "life-support system." Wear it on your belt, but don't forget to charge the cartridge with drugs first, they're included of course. The device will monitor your state of your health, and if you get a serious injury, an infection or an overdose of radiation, the device will automatically administer the appropriate drug. If you don't need some of these features, you can disable them on the front panel, where indicator strips show the drug capacities. Goodbye, Marked One, take care of yourself.\n\n(To use the Auto-doctor, place the device on your belt, then use the cartridge to charge it. Then enter into the interface of the device by clicking the right mouse button and select "Use". Turn on the unit with the "ON / OFF" button, also adjust the necessary features by buttons near the capacity indicator strips of the device. The "I" on the switch means on - and the "0" is off.)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_8">
		<text>Well, I got something a couple of times. Why do you ask??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_7">
		<text>Why is that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_6">
		<text>No, nothing special. Just everyday items. I need to check it out first, then I'll tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_5">
		<text>What did you see? Tell me, it may be important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_4">
		<text>Well it's clear, thank you. This makes me happy. I thought I was imagining things.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_3">
		<text>You know, Marked One, in principle, it's not possible. There are theories, because we can't have a lot of inconsistencies that otherwise could not be explained. There is one theory that the Zone has always been there, just hidden, as if asleep. While certain events, such as the Chernobyl disaster, did not wake it up, it just moved to an active state. There are reports that long before the disaster, abnormal events occurred sometimes, but they were largely attributed to witnesses suffering mental illness, self-hypnosis or hallucinations -  you know, the standard reasons. Now, all these events are lined up in a rather slender chain that leads us to the current state of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_2">
		<text>Well, you know, I sometimes still encounter such things in the Zone, it seems as if the Zone has not been here a dozen years, but much, much longer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2_1">
		<text>What?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_2">
		<text>I have a question about the age of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_17">
		<text>Damn. Why did I ask, now I can't sleep peacefully.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_16">
		<text>Well, this is a purely psychological thing - the Zone strongly influences your psyche, leaving a psychological mark on you, the longer you spend here, the less likely that you will want to return to the mainland. If you leave the Zone - the urge to return will be stronger. It may also have something to do with the desire of the Zone's reproduction. When you came back from a raid with a huge amount of loot - you want to leave the Zone, and then when you do - it draws you back. And so it becomes an infinite loop. The situation was saved only by traders - they cooperate closely with us, the artifacts in the most parts are packaged in safe containers and transported to research institutions around the world. But still, a decent number of artifacts are carried out in an uncontrolled manner. So, Marked One, Duty are not the uncouth fanatics, they first seemed to be. Their view of the Zone is very close to reality, that everything has the right to live. Well, back to your original question - it's for these reasons that the military behave so aggressively. They are instructed on the principle "what you don't know won't hurt you", and because of it they, and mostly in panic, are afraid of stalkers, excluding them by default from the infected dangerous and unknown diseases that perhaps exist in the Zone already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_15">
		<text>Stalker's syndrome?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_14">
		<text>Not all of them, just the better known ones. Yes, it's simplistic I know, but - they are the seeds of the Zone. And you take them out, unaccounted for and unchecked. No one can say, in whose hands they will finally fall. This is a peculiar method of reproduction, Marked One. To put it simply, the fact is, the Zone is using stalkers like you, as pollinators. You are spreading its seeds around the world, helping it to multiply. No one can guarantee that the removed artifact won't be activated by accident, outside the perimeter. If it's activated - I will create a piece of the Zone which will begin to generate its own artifacts. Those artifacts can also be activated,  to create pieces of the Zone, and so on. Such is the specific process of reproduction in which you play the role of pollinators. Generally, that's how it is. I only told you the most simple and obvious things, there are many other nuances. The Zone is evolving all the time, it's changing and no one can say what other surprises it will send out inside your body. There's only one stalker's syndrome, which is...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_13">
		<text>So you're saying, that the artifacts - are like... a seed?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_12">
		<text>Yes, you see, according to the latest theories, the problem is, that the Zone - is a kind of living creature. And every living creature has one basic instinct - to reproduce. Now, do you remember that artifacts can be activated in a special way, and become an anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_11">
		<text>What else? That we're removed from the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_10">
		<text>Well, because of this, burying stalkers in the Zone is impossible, because a week later, his grave would be overgrown with cheerful downy shoots. Because of this, stalkers, who are caught alive, are sent to quarantine and then are held to account that they are required to be cremated after death. But you guys pack into the Zone and run amok, and no one on the mainland knows where these spore carrying stalkers are, because they are not registered. There wouldn't be a problem with the Fuzz, if the stalkers behaved themselves...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_9">
		<text>The motherfuckers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_8">
		<text>Well, these spores burn armour, pierce the skin and enter the tissues. And there they form a solid shell - a cyst - and go dormant. Our immune system doesn't allow them to develop. But they don't need to, they're not parasites, they were introduced for a different purpose.  When the being contaminated with Fuzz spores dies, the spores are activated, dissolving their shell and grow into a full plant, simply by using the dead host's tissue as fertilizer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_7">
		<text>Yes, I noticed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_6">
		<text>Yes, you see, the Fuzz just burns. That's its method of propagation. When disturbed, it throws spores that produce a very strong organic acid, easily consuming steel and many other materials. It needs this interaction in order to get to a living body, which is protected by the steel. Did you notice - how the spores rapidly destroy armour, but almost doesn't harm living tissue, perhaps some decent bleeding, but nothing fatal, and after bandaging, it quickly heals?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_5">
		<text>I ask not because of something particularly good. Do you realize that you just started an argument?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_4">
		<text>Well, that's not quite true. Let me tell you a little bit more. Have you ever got something from under a "Burning Fuzz"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_3">
		<text>Well, I understand that, but you too, take artifacts out of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1_1">
		<text>Well, if you take into account that stalkers like you, who are not here legally, and are engaged in smuggling, then they have a very good reason. You see, what they broadcast over the loudspeakers at the checkpoint, about the poorly understood Zone, representing a great danger to human life and health - is the truth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="talk_about_zone_1_1">
		<text>You're working with the military, tell me, why are they so aggressive towards us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_1">
		<text>What are the zombie stalkers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_2">
		<text>Zombie Stalker - are essentially just ordinary people who have been exposed to psi radiation, with a very dim, but not completely destroyed rational behaviour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_3">
		<text>Are the sources of such radiation known?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_4">
		<text>But zombie stalkers can be found in many different places. Do they appear for other reasons, too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_5">
		<text>That's right. Stalkers can also turn into zombies, if they stay in some psychic anomaly for too long or fall under the influence of a controller.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_6">
		<text>How do you distinguish a man from a zombie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_7">
		<text>How do you effectively destroy a zombie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_8">
		<text>The most effective way to kill a zombie - is a few well placed shots to the head, because you can use more than one rifle magazine trying to shoot at the body and limbs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_9">
		<text>And what you can find on a zombie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_10">
		<text>As a rule, you can find some mouldy food,  a supply of cartridges and maybe a bandage on a dead zombie. Well, you shouldn't count on anything valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_11">
		<text>Thanks for the detailed information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_12">
		<text>Unlike the zombie stalkers who have their intelligence greatly atrophied, Snorks are deprived of all of it. They can be treated like animals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_13">
		<text>But they appear to have adapted to the good life in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_14">
		<text>Tell me more about these qualities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_15">
		<text>Clearly, they prefer ambush than long term pursuit. Are there any females among them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_16">
		<text>There are no female snorks in the herd - that allows us to hope for the total elimination of these creatures with proper cleansing of their habitats.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_17">
		<text>Where do they occur most often?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_18">
		<text>Do snorks fall under the influence of psi-control?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_19">
		<text>Yes, you know a lot of interesting things about snorks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_20">
		<text>Do you have explanations for these mysteries?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_21">
		<text>Soon we will unravel the mysteries of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_22">
		<text>What are snorks?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_23">
		<text>Apparently this is the swiftest being in the Zone. What tactics does it use?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_24">
		<text>What other behavioural patterns does it have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_25">
		<text>An ordinary chimera, for all its power - is nothing compared to the electric chimera. What can you tell me about them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_26">
		<text>What tactics should I use when dealing with them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_27">
		<text>What causes the chimeras electric charge?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_28">
		<text>Thanks for the detailed information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_29">
		<text>About the chimeras. I think - they were artificially created in a laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_30">
		<text>About the bloodsuckers. What are these things, and how do I deal with them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_31">
		<text>What do you do when you encounter a bloodsucker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_32">
		<text>And yet, stalkers manage to hunt bloodsuckers. Still, there is demand for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_33">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_34">
		<text>About the plague of rats - these carriers of aggressive flies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_35">
		<text>What are these flies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_36">
		<text>Can you tell me about the Zone mutants in more detail?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_37">
		<text>What exactly do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_garbage_about_life_1">
		<text>How's life brother stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_garbage_about_life_2">
		<text>Well, take care.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_garbage_about_life_3">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_garbage_about_life_4">
		<text>Do you collect artifacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="why_on_escape_1_1">
		<text>Thanks, I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="why_on_escape_1">
		<text>Hello, Marked One! I heard a lot about you. I've been engaged in the processing and accounting of artifacts received from traders and their registration and sending them to the Research Institute for the Chernobyl Anomalous Zone. By the way, if you have any artifacts - I'll give you a better price than what the usual traders give. Plus, I have some necessary consumables - ammunition, bandages and the like, if you need any, I sell them cheaply.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="why_on_escape_0">
		<text>Oh, hello! What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_40">
		<text>You're a scientist. Can you tell me something important and interesting about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_41">
		<text>What would you like to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_42">
		<text>About the hour of horror.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_43">
		<text>Are mobile anomalies also unstable?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_44">
		<text>From where do the phantoms come, in the hour of horror?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voprosy_o_zone_45">
		<text>Thank you for the interesting information.</text>
	</string>
	<!--Abnormal cookware-->
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Professor, please look, here's something I found...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_1">
		<text>Wow, how strange. What amazing distortion characteristics! Where did you get this, young man?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_2">
		<text>Yes, you know, I explored the Dead City. I was carefully searching the houses, you never know what could pop up, then I saw something - lying under some garbage, it wasn't an artifact... but it glowed! Maybe in fact, it too, is anomalous and useful? Do you want to see it, professor?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_3">
		<text>Well, of course! Listen, was there anything else similar nearby? If you go again - look carefully, perhaps it was not the only one formed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_4">
		<text>Well, of course! Listen, I see that it's not the only one! Bring them to me, I'll take take all! Listen, was there anything else similar nearby? If you go again - look carefully, perhaps it was not the only one formed...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_5">
		<text>Well, of course! Listen, I see that it's not the only one! Give them to me, I'll take them all! This effect is completely unknown to me, I need to notify the core research team! Here is your due reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_start_dialog_6">
		<text>Consider me, already gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_end_dialog_0">
		<text>Professor, look, I found other things!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anom_house_items_task_end_dialog_1">
		<text>Amazing! This effect is completely unknown to me, I need to notify the core research team! Here is your due reward.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Get to the cache -->
	<string id="ros_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>So, we are on the Wild Territory. I know something about Radioman's cache, I think we can find it. If we don't croak it here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>How do you know where it might be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>In the evening, of the first day of the studies, I was on guard duty at the camp. Perepelkin and Radioman sitting by the fire for a while and were quietly whispering. Well, I have a good ears and overheard something, although I gave no indication. Come on, Marked One, you go first and I'll follow. Keep your eyes open, this is a dangerous place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Come see what's what with mercenaries -->
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_first_dialog_1">
		<text>Look, there's a box around the corner from the unfinished building. There could be mercenaries there, it's best not to go past them. You go, and scout ahead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_first_dialog_2">
		<text>Why me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_first_dialog_3">
		<text>Because I know something about the cache, which we need. So it's necessary to protect my ass, right? By the way, you better check the upper floors at the construction site as well, there may be snipers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_first_dialog_4">
		<text>Snipers, wow. Well, I'll go and investigate.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Dismantling of mercenaries -->
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_1">
		<text>Well, what about the mercenaries?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_2">
		<text>The construction site is empty, not a soul. Let's move out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_3">
		<text>The construction site is occupied by mercenaries. What do we do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_4">
		<text>Personally, I'm going to - sit here. I'm not eager to get a bullet in the head. Or get captured them - that's even worse. I've heard what they do with stalkers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_5">
		<text>Now what? The cache? And people in the anomaly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_6">
		<text>Listen, if you want it - you go deal with them. You can go - but I'm not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_7">
		<text>Stay here, you bloody coward, I'll do it myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_8">
		<text>I haven't checked yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_9">
		<text>What are you waiting for? Hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_10">
		<text>There were mercenaries, but they're all gone. I dealt with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_11">
		<text>You're a real terminator. Well then, let's go. Follow me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_killers_12">
		<text>lead on.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- The search first cache -->
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_1">
		<text>Now listen carefully. The prototype is hidden near one of the wagons, standing on sidings. It think that under the rubble, at the entrance to the tunnel - is a good hiding place. You go and see if there's something, and I'll wait for you here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_2">
		<text>Of course, of course, you sit here and I'll go. That's nothing out of the ordinary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_search_1">
		<text>Well? Was there anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_search_2">
		<text>Well, I haven't looked yet. Easy for you to send me, but I need to look around, to check if it's safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_search_3">
		<text>Nothing, it's empty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_search_4">
		<text>God dammit. Well, let's go look some more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_first_spot_search_5">
		<text>Come on, let's get on with it.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- A search of the second cache -->
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_1">
		<text>Here's another place where Radioman could hide the prototype. Rummage under the platform, I'm sure, there is a cache somewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_2">
		<text>Look, maybe now, you should seek? I'll sit here and have a smoke.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_3">
		<text>Go on, I'll be here to cover you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_4">
		<text>Yeah, you'll have to cover...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_1">
		<text>Well, was there a cache?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_2">
		<text>Wait, I hear something, near the hiding place. I need to look.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_3">
		<text>Found it! There's even something that looks like instructions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_4">
		<text>Excellent! Now with the help of this device, you have to get three artifacts from the Dark Zone. When you get them, come to me, I'll wait for you at Sakharov's bunker. I'll try to get the second generator.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_5">
		<text>Where can I find these Dark Zones?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_6">
		<text>Radioman told us that he found them at the Cordon, the Garbage and here, at the Wild Territory. And Yantar, of course. Perepelkin said that they are almost everywhere - there could even be one in distant Pripyat. He game me a scientific explanation, but I didn't understand it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ros_soldier_search_dialog_second_spot_search_7">
		<text>Well, I'll have a look. See you!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Come arts -->
	<string id="yan_soldier_second_generator_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_second_generator_dialog_1">
		<text>Ah, Marked One! Did you search the Dark Zones? Did you collect the artifacts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_second_generator_dialog_2">
		<text>I'm in the process.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_second_generator_dialog_3">
		<text>Yes, I was able to get three of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_second_generator_dialog_4">
		<text>Excellent! Now I can fix the generator. Give me those artifacts, I'll equip the second generator. This may require some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yan_soldier_second_generator_dialog_5">
		<text>Here you are.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

