	<string id="yan_find_loschina_gosearch_task_desc">
		<text>Sakharov asked me to find a lost measurement team in the Darkscape, but first I need to get there and look around. That place, is very far away. It is advisable to take a companion along, it's not a place to venture alone. You need to inspect their last location - Sakharov said that before the loss of communication with the group, they were changing their position, to some well-protected hidden place. But where is it? I should ask one of the locals, maybe one of them would know. Then it is necessary to find the journal - at the measuring post, the scientists would have kept a journal, which describes all their experiments and measurements, and to bring it back to Sakharov - it contains very important information for him. Dammit, I have to walk through half Zone again, what punishment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_ghost_task">
		<text>Vasilyev:"... the coordinates to the entrance to the X-16 lab. The entrance is in the basement of the main building, the purpose of this building is unknown. Presumably - it's housing the underground emitters: the study of documentation from N *** disclosed the purpose of the project - a large-scale development of the mass psychotropic Effects on ...\n... We have all the necessary documents now, we know how to turn off the transmitter. I'll continue to descend into the lab with Ghost. The zombies seem to be coming out of everywhere ...\n... Everything is going to hell, Ghost is absolutely insane, talking nonsense  all the time. This place is highly radiated, I have to drop everything and go through the tunnels ...\n... I'm in the swamps, where's the bunker? Damn, damn, damn!!! I can't define where I am! Sakharov the coward, he doesn't answer!!! What's happening??? ... I'm surrounded by zombies, running out of ammo ... "</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_lab">
		<text>Sakharov: "All you have to do - is to find the corpse of Vasilyev and get precise information about the location of the laboratory. Then, having got into the lab, find Ghost. Ghost knew how to turn off the radiation and then how to get out."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_scientist">
		<text>Sakharov: "If you assist my staff member in taking measurements, I'll give a customized prototype helmet which will allow you to enter the lab."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_find_scientist_semenov">
		<text>Sakharov: "If you assist my staff member in taking measurements, I'll give a customized prototype helmet which will allow you to enter the lab."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_kill_brain">
		<text>Sakharov: "Good for you, Marked One, you got into the lab. It is essential for us to examine the installation, which is there. Try to turn it off so that we can investigate it.\n Look, Marked One, the prototype can only protect you from strong radiation for a short time. I provided for such a case. Therefore, when you get under the influence of strong radiation - a timer will start. When the time expires, the prototype will cease to protect you. Be careful and don't forget about the timer."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_kill_brain_2">
		<text>The unit has been disabled. All that is left now - is to get out alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_provodnik_task">
		<text>Ghost: "Guide, I'll send you someone, we have important information for the Doctor, facilitate him."\nConductor: "Good. Only Ghost, not like last time. Better still, you bring him; I haven't seen you for a long time and I want to talk with you. I look forward to seeing you as usual, at the camp near the bridge. Don't get lost, and look, there are army patrols, so don't get caught."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="descr_yan_scientist_return_task">
		<text>Sakharov: "What happened? Did he die? Take measurements and return immediately!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_find_ghost">
		<text>I'm in shock! The man in the photo on Ghost's PDA and the one tasked to kill Strelok, is one and the same person. I don't understand. There has to be some mistake. But who made it? There is no answer. From the records, I learned the name of Ghost's "mutual friend" and the fourth in Strelok's group - Doctor. He has long helped the group and served, apparently, the role of "chief of staff". You can find him through a stalker nicknamed Guide - who often visits the Cordon. He should be there provided he doesn't die by accident ... before you meet. On Ghost's corpse were also documents about the installation of the "psi-brain". The whole district was influenced by this shit - it zombified everyone within the area of its action. I learned that there is another installation in the X-10 lab, most likely, it's the brain scorcher. I also learned that these plants don't always operate at full power. There are times when they lower the radiation power for the units to cool.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_find_ghost_name">
		<text>Another mystery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_kill_brain">
		<text>After disabling this loathsome "brain in a bottle", I lost consciousness. Apparently I was affected by the tension of the past few days. While I was out, I had a dream...  It shows a grey-haired man with a huge dog around his feet looking at a photograph. The man looks into the distance, but around the swamp the landscape is nothing like what is depicted in the photo. In the fog you can barely see the retreating figure. The man mutters, as if talking to himself: "If this is so important, then why do I feel so plainly and did not explain what this place is and where did you get that picture" ... Then ... I see from a young guy smiling at the threshold of the hut, which announces cheerfully: "If you knew where I was able to visit and what I saw there!". He holds out some amazing contraption from which spreads lights on cabin. The dog starts to growl and retreats into a corner, and the grey-haired man muttered: "Did you ever finish the" ... Flash ... that's the same guy with a bloody face horribly disfigured that bursts in the door of the hut and on the verge of falling ... Behind the door, beat lightning, rain lashes ... flash ... The bed in the cabin - it is the same guy, but his face is all scarred and bandaged. Man unconscious and grey-haired man muttered: "Hold my son" ... In the corner of dumped things, and among them this strange picture ... flash ... Photo in the hands of the white-haired. A man with scars on his face going away. The grey-haired asks him: "Where are you going now?". It is a grim answer: "to the north". Flash ... and I woke up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_kill_brain_name">
		<text>The second dream.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_vasilyev_pda">
		<text>Well, I'm almost step away from one of Strelok's people. Ghost went with one of the scientists to the underground X-16 laboratory. One "but" - I will hardly find him live. The scientist returned from there but was lost on the way back to the camp. Sakharov gave me some device to protect me against this unknown radiation. I hope it will pay off. They want me to penetrate into the interior of the lab and disable source of radiation - then they will be able to study everything in the laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_vasilyev_pda_name">
		<text>One step away from Ghost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_ghost_info">
		<text>Record N257\n Guide, I'll send you someone, we have important information for the Doctor, facilitate him.\n "Good. Only Ghost, not like last time. Better still, you bring him; I haven't seen you for a long time and I want to talk with you. I look forward to seeing you as usual, at the camp near the bridge. Don't get lost, and look, there are army patrols, so don't get caught.".\n Record N384\n ... Vasiliev chickened out at the last minute and instead of disabling the lower panels, he just run away when the door opened. You should not have to rely on him, Strelok was right not trust this liar dog. My only chance - to get to the door before the controller...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_vasilyev_info">
		<text>... The coordinates to the entrance to the X-16 lab. The entrance is in the basement of the main building, the purpose of this building is unknown. Presumably - it's housing the underground emitters: the study of documentation from N *** disclosed the purpose of the project - a large-scale development of the mass psychotropic Effects on ...\n... We have all the necessary documents now, we know how to turn off the transmitter. I'll continue to descend into the lab with Ghost. The zombies seem to be coming out of everywhere ...\n... Everything is going to hell, Ghost is absolutely insane, talking nonsense  all the time. This place is highly radiated, I have to drop everything and go through the tunnels ...\n... I'm in the swamps, where's the bunker? Damn, damn, damn! I can't define where I am! Sakharov the coward, he doesn't answer! What's happening? ... I'm surrounded by zombies, running out of ammo...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loschina_scientists_info">
		<text>... Today we finally completed the transfer of equipment from the old camp to here. A wonderful place indeed - concrete walls, solid door, a very secretive location. But this invisible beam in the gap of the bridge, it's something. All day we joked on the topic of the adventures of Indiana Jones. The only thing is - that I don't feel too well this evening. Overtired, perhaps, my head aches a bit and I'm seeing double. A weakness of some sort. Vasya says you'll get accustomed to it and it will soon pass. Vasya is kind, he's lived here for a long time. He is our host and owner. My head hurts ... Vasya says the radio feedback is causing it. Vasya is right; it's necessary to turn off the radio.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="loschina_story_info">
		<text>The "Barrier" project. A short briefing. The demarcation boundary within which the manifestations of the facility occur has increased significantly, because of that we have been tasked to find ways to limit any further spread. The use of engineering units from the Ukrainian Armed Forces has been pre-approved to use heavy equipment and blasting to physical block the tunnels leading to the facility. It is necessary to observe extreme measures of precaution during the works, manifestations caused by the facility are extremely dangerous and create a very hostile environment. Plus, due to the current instability of the facility, manifestations often appear suddenly and in random locations with devastating effects. For various reasons during construction, we have already lost more than twenty civilian and military personnel; in particular the formation of one of the manifestations led to the loss of one of the buses carrying staff to their workplace. It is prescribed to use complete personal protective equipment kits at the site in the future, to carry out the work as quickly as possible and always keep transportation close by for emergency evacuation. Keep in mind that the situation is complicated by strong ground winds coming from the facility, which makes the use of helicopters for emergency evacuations difficult.</text>
	</string>	