<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_0">
		<text>Hey, Barkeep, do you have anything to drink?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_9">
		<text>It's on the house, thanks to Fair One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_10">
		<text>Barkeep, what's up there at the Mainland?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_11">
		<text>There's nothing good about that place. As ever.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_12">
		<text>Why do you say that? Didn't you have any luck there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_14">
		<text>Why don't you call the mainland and find out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_15">
		<text>I can make a call? To the mainland?! With pleasure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_16">
		<text>Climb on to the roof, jump across to the next one, from there take the stairs to the tower. Only don't break the bell!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_17">
		<text>Well... you amaze me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_18">
		<text>Okay, I'm only kidding. Help yourself to a beer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_0">
		<text>I see you have a deck of cards... Do you want to play for money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_1">
		<text>With pleasure! I'm bored here. We can play "21". Do you remember how to play or should I remind you the rules?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_2">
		<text>Remind me the rules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_3">
		<text>I know how to play.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_4">
		<text>The rules are simple. To win, you need to get 21 points. Points are calculated as follows: cards 2 to 10 - according to their face value, Jack - 2 points, Queen - 3 points, King - 4 points. Ace can have a higher value, in our case, an ace is 11 points.\nMaximum bet is 5000, minimum bet is 500. That's all, nothing complicated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_5">
		<text>Roger, let's play.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_6">
		<text>I changed my mind, I don't want to play.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_dialog_7">
		<text>Well, as you wish. Come back, when you feel like playing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_1_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm bored. Is there anything to have fun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_1_dialog_1">
		<text>We can play the "Find the ball" game. It's fun, but we play for money. If you forgot the rules - I can remind you. Interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_1_dialog_2">
		<text>I know how to play.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_1_dialog_3">
		<text>Tell me the rules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_1_dialog_4">
		<text>I don't want to play.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mini_games_1_dialog_5">
		<text>I'll put a ball under one of the three cups, then mix them to confuse you. Your task is to guess under which cup the ball is. Minimum bet is 500, maximum bet is 2000. Rules coulds't be simpler!\nWell, let's play then?</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Tip about the code X-18 -->
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_0">
		<text>Listen, I was given a task...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_1">
		<text>...and you're having some difficulties with it. That's why you came to me, didn't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_2">
		<text>Yes. I need the access codes to the X-18 lab. I can't find them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_3">
		<text>Well, actually, I could help you... For some adequate remuneration. Let's say, 50 thousand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_4">
		<text>It's expensive, but I have no choice. Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_5">
		<text>I don't have the money. I'll come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_6">
		<text>Excellent. Here's what I know about the X-18: Access to the laboratory is divided into two levels - one for junior and one for senior staff. The levels are separated by heavy coded doors, there are codes for each corresponding level. The code for the first level is - 1243. Code for the second level is - 9524. Remember it, as I won't repeat it a second time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_lab_hint_7">
		<text>Well, this is what I need. Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<!--Entry into Bandits by informant-->
	<string id="bar_informator_enter_bandit_1">
		<text>Help me to deal with the bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_enter_bandit_2">
		<text>And what affairs do you have with them? Do you have money?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_enter_bandit_3">
		<text>I have business with Borov. And yes, I have money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_enter_bandit_4">
		<text>Good. Pay me 30,000 roubles. I'll give you an introductory letter: I will say that you have important business with Borov. The bandits won't touch you for a day. But bear in mind that the neutrality term is limited. If you don't go, the bandits will no longer talk to you. And yes, as soon as your affairs in the Dark Valley are finalised - the neutrality will end.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_enter_bandit_5">
		<text>OK, I understand. Take the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_enter_bandit_6">
		<text>I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<!--Kitsenko talks about Duty-->
	<string id="about_dolg_0">
		<text>Tell me about your group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dolg_1">
		<text>Our group is called "Duty".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dolg_2">
		<text>Why such a name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dolg_3">
		<text>Why, you ask? Well, it's simple. If not us, then who? Our duty is to fight all the manifestations in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dolg_4">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dolg_5">
		<text>Many of our guys come into the Zone as ordinary stalkers wanting to cash in, but just seeing the local horror, they realized that something must be done to stop this. Now, they give up the good life, if only to keep the mutants out of their home towns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_dolg_6">
		<text>It's a pity really, that not all people think the same. And it sucks that we have to deal with a bunch of idiots, to prevent the spread of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_music_2">
		<text>Well, if I find any - I'll bring them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_music_1">
		<text>The radio receives too much strong interference due to the Zone. There is an old jukebox here, but it doesn't have any records. You walk around the Zone a lot; look around, see if you can find any music records. Bring them here and we'll gladly enjoy them together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_music_0">
		<text>Barkeep, why is it so quiet in the bar, why is there no music?</text>
	</string>
	<!--Restoring relations with Duty-->
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_1">
		<text>Could you help me to restore relations with Duty? I don't want to quarrel with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_2">
		<text>You shouldn't have picked a fight with them. So, now I have to sort out the nonsense you've caused. The cost will depend on how much damage you've caused. And compensation for my time, he he. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_3">
		<text>And what is the payment for your services?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_4">
		<text>Well. You didn't cause much harm, so you can get rid of the problem, if you pay 10,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_5">
		<text>Eh. You seriously annoyed them. Such a situation will not attract a small fee. I can sort out your problems for 30,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_6">
		<text>You really pissed them off. Dutiers are ready to destroy the Bar just to kill you. Solving your problem will be very difficult, but, if you pay 80,000 roubles, I can fix it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_7">
		<text>I agree to pay as much as you need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_dolg_8">
		<text>To hell with Duty! I'll cope with these nut bags somehow.</text>
	</string>
	<!--Restoring relations with Duty-->
	<!--Restoring relations with Freedom-->
	<string id="bar_informator_free_1">
		<text>Could you help me to restore relations with the Freedom? I'm tired of their persecution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_free_7_1">
		<text>Alas, at the moment, I can't help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_free_2">
		<text>I can assist you. You didn't cause much harm, so I can get rid of your problem, if you pay me 10,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_free_3">
		<text>Yes, you've left some considerable marks. For such a situation the fee is not small. I can settle your problems for 30,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_free_4">
		<text>You've really ruffled some feathers this time. Solving your problem will be very difficult, but it's possible, if you pay 80,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_free_5">
		<text>I'll pay whatever is necessary.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_informator_free_6">
		<text>To hell with the Freedom. They're not worth that kind of money.</text>
	</string>
	<!--Restoring relations with Freedom-->
	<!--The fee for the passage to the Garbage-->
	<string id="bribe_dolg_0">
		<text>Barkeep, I have business, you understand... Duty are quite insolent, they won't let me pass through to the Garbage. Can you help me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bribe_dolg_1">
		<text>It would be a sin not to help a good man. For a fee, of course. 40,000 roubles - and the gates will always be open for you. You will be able to pass like normal people, and not have to dodge radioactive piles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bribe_dolg_2">
		<text>Forty thousand? Damn it, that's too much. But all right, take it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bribe_dolg_4">
		<text>Alright then. Well, Dutiers won't simply open the door. You'll need to by-pass their post somehow, without letting them see you. Then you will have a free path. But, I will warn them about you in advance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bribe_dolg_3">
		<text>Why should I pay so much... I'll find a way to go around.</text>
	</string>
	<!--The fee for the passage to the Garbage-->
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_0">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_11">
		<text>So, your first fight? Your opponent is a piece of meat just like you. He's here because of debts and he only has two options: to come out and fight or to land himself in the nearest anomaly. He's going to fight like a cornered animal. Equipment for today... let me think... OK! Why don't you two use PMm's... Two clips each should be plenty. Either you kick his ass or we feed you to the dogs - not much of a choice. Go on now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_111">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_112">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_12">
		<text>Your last fight didn't mean shit. You're still the same piece of meat you were before and no self-respecting person will bet a single mag on you. If you want to earn some proper cash you're going to have to make a few more appearances in the arena. Your new opponent also got through the first round and his fight was a lot harder than yours. I don't like him, to be honest - he kills too quickly and the crowd doesn't like that. So, go and show us what you can do! The stakes will increase after this fight - all you've got to do is stay alive. Move it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_121">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_122">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_13">
		<text>Well, well... You're not as much of a pussy as you first seemed. Now it's time to test you out in a real fight. You're up against two guys. The first one's called Swede and I don't remember the second one's name. They were paired up intentionally as they hate each other's guts so don't worry about them working as a team - they're more likely to shoot each other. Today is rifle day so don't let them get too close or we'll have to pick you up piece by piece. The odds are 10:1 so if you win you'll make a fair amount. Off you go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_131">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_132">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_14">
		<text>Well, now I can safely say that you're a fighter, a real fighter. Now it's time for a team fight. You get to fight with two rookies - two brothers - on your side. They haven't fought yet but they're brothers, so I had to put them into a team fight. I wouldn't expect any real help from them if I were you. You're fighting an experienced team, they're contenders for the final this season. A dangerous lot. They use different weapons but one has an automatic shotgun - be very careful with him. Good luck, pal... you're gonna need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_141">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_142">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_15">
		<text>You've got a special fight today. Even the army has heard about you! Don't be surprised, they fight here too - there's even a general in the crowd. These guys are from the Spetsnaz or from OMON. They're well armed and their armour is good as you'd expect. Don't worry though, I'm not going to leave you out in the rain, either. You'll get a vest used by Freedom - it's light so it won't slow you down. Go on, show them that stalkers aren't whipping boys. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_151">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_152">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_16">
		<text>Time for you to show what you can do. Duty captured a group of bandits that had been causing problems for stalkers near Rostok. Duty took them at night so most of the bandits were taken alive. They were all going to be executed anyway so I convinced Duty to give them a chance. If any of them survive, they'll go in the can outside the Zone, which is better than dying here. They're not well-armed - just a few pistols and sawn-off's - but there're six of them so watch yourself. Go on now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_161">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_162">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_17">
		<text>Well, you're almost in the final. Now you'll be fighting a real stalker. He's alone but he's got an FN2000 and wears an exoskeleton. Catch one burst and you're toast. There will be a surprise that I can't tell you about too... Here's my advice: be prepared, it's going to be tough. The winner makes it through to the final. Fight to the death, go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_171">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_172">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_18">
		<text>Congratulations, you're in the final! One more to go and this one is to the death, every man for himself. There will be 4 other stalkers in the arena: all real pros in exoskeletons with G36s but it's a fair deal this time - you'll get exactly what they have. The only thing is, you don't get med kits or bandages in a fight to the death. Ready? Go prove you're the best, GO!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_181">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_job_182">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<!--ARENA_EXTENSION_MOD-->
	<string id="ARENA_MODE">
		<text>Congratulations, Marked One, you are now the champion! I haven't found a worthy contender yet to challenge your title, so... I suggest that you don't relax but continue to perform in the Arena. How about taking on a few mutants? We just got in a new batch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="continue">
		<text>Let's see...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="new_offer">
		<text>Choose the fight and we will begin.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_label">
		<text>Knackery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_info">
		<text>At last we have a supply of wild beasts, there are even some very rare specimens. Well, which will you try first?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_dog">
		<text>Dogs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_tushkan">
		<text>Rodents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_snork">
		<text>Snorks</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsuckers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_zombie">
		<text>Controller and zombies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_chimera">
		<text>Chimeras</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_burer">
		<text>Burers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fight_monsters_pseudogigant">
		<text>Pseudogiant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_11">
		<text>Fight with army soldiers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_12">
		<text>Fight with mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_13">
		<text>Fight with Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_14">
		<text>Fight with Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_11_1">
		<text>Well, tell me, how many of the soldier's livers do you want for your dog today?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_12_1">
		<text>Choose how much meat you want this time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_13_1">
		<text>Yes, they are fresh, very fresh ... How many pieces do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_14_1">
		<text>Duty. Today, they will do their duty and kick the bucket. How many of them will there be - you decide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_1on1">
		<text>One on one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_1on2">
		<text>Two against one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_1on3">
		<text>Three against one</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_massacre">
		<text>Bloodbath</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fight_make_stake">
		<text>Tote</text>
	</string>
	<string id="select_stakes">
		<text>Well then, Marked One, today we announced two exclusive bouts, namely the military against the mercenaries and Duty against Freedom. Each side will have six representatives, all of them are seasoned fighters and equipped accordingly. The winners will go into the finals, where they will compete for the title of the coolest group of the week with some privileges. For each of the parties, victory is essential, so they will fight like animals, so make the right choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="select_stakes_militaries">
		<text>I'll bet on the military.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="select_stakes_killers">
		<text>I'll bet on the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="select_stakes_freedom">
		<text>I'll bet on Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="select_stakes_duty">
		<text>I'll bet on Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stakes_final">
		<text>The final battle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_mil_vs_free">
		<text>Today in the finals are the military and Freedom. Well, you saw what they can do, so place your bets, gentlemen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_mil_vs_dolg">
		<text>Today in the finals are Duty and the military. Well, you saw what they can do, so place your bets, gentlemen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_free_vs_ki">
		<text>Today in the finals are Freedom and the mercenaries. Well, you saw what they can do, so place your bets, gentlemen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="final_ki_vs_dolg">
		<text>Today in the finals are Duty and the mercenaries. Well, you saw what they can do, so place your bets, gentlemen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="make_stake_militaries">
		<text>Well, on the military. How much did you want to bet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="make_stake_killers">
		<text>So, stake on the mercenaries. How much?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="make_stake_freedom">
		<text>How much do you want to put on Freedom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="make_stake_duty">
		<text>How many roubles will you stake on Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="10000p">
		<text>I'll stake 3,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="50000p">
		<text>I'll stake 8,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="100000p">
		<text>I'll stake 12,000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="back">
		<text>I'm not ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="empty">
		<text>I changed the mind, I will come after pay day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Exit">
		<text>I'm busy, I'll come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_11">
		<text>Yo! I've got a new fight for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_21">
		<text>Take a walk for an hour or two, the Arena isn't ready yet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_31">
		<text>You've become a master!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_41">
		<text>Here, take what you've earned.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_411">
		<text>Next please!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arena_completed">
		<text>The Arena is closed for maintenance. So take a little walk, until 22:00. I'll announce the opening on the general channel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arena_activated">
		<text>Excellent, Marked One. As you can see, the Arena is again ready for the walls to get sprinkled with fresh blood. Come on, hurry up and choose a fight! Today we have a very intense program, as always.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fuck_you">
		<text>See you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_man_start_51">
		<text>You are not experienced enough for this fight!</text>
	</string>
	<!--ARENA_EXTENSION_MOD-->	
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_0">
		<text>Here is the flash drive I got from professor Kruglov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_21">
		<text>Good job, I think, Duty will be grateful for this information. Here's a reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_ecolog_flash_done_31">
		<text>So. Information, you say? Directly from professor Kruglov, huh? Are you trying to mock me? "I, Professor Kruglov, in the name of science and humanity, have erased our research reports." - Is this the information you were supposed to bring? Yeah ... I think, Duty will be very "happy" when they find out about this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_0">
		<text>Mission accomplished. Here's Tyran's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_1">
		<text>Wow, Marked One. Great job! What can I say? You made me happy, man. I wasn't sure you'd manage, to be honest... But you're alive and they're not!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_2">
		<text>What about the reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_killer_ambush_3">
		<text>Here you go, as promised - your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_0">
		<text>Here is Lucky's PDA. I did what you asked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_1">
		<text>Nice, Marked One. Great job! What can I say? You made me happy, man. I wasn't sure you'd manage, to be honest... But you're alive and they're not!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_11">
		<text>What about the reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barman_veterans_finish_111">
		<text>You're a hero, man, a real hero. Here, this should make you happy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_0">
		<text>Are there any special missions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_111">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_21">
		<text>Get to the point. What should be done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_221">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2311">
		<text>I've got a serious mission. A group of veteran killers has shown up in the Wild Territory again. Some Duty people came to me and asked me to deal with these veterans. Duty has solid proof that they are responsible for the deaths of solo stalkers. The problem is that these veterans and Duty have some old agreement and Duty can't break it but these guys are really pushing it. Basically, Duty wants them taken out, nice and quiet. It isn't going be easy but the job pays well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_23111">
		<text>Any other additional conditions? It's strange that Duty sinks this low.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_231111">
		<text>Duty values its reputation. Therefore, they want it done covertly. You need to destroy their leader, named "Lucky" and bring his PDA as evidence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2311111">
		<text>I'll do it. I hope that I won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_23111111">
		<text>A good decision, there's nothing to regret.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2311112">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_23111121">
		<text>Well, as you wish... Just remember, this is a good opportunity to get appreciation from Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_24">
		<text>Get to the point. What should be done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_241">
		<text>Your mission is to kill Tyran, the leader of a group of mercenaries. His crew made it into the Wild Territory and set up a base at the construction site. Be careful, some of their fighters have set up ambushes on the way to the site. As soon as you bring me Tyran's PDA - you'll get your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2411">
		<text>I'll do it. I hope I won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_24111">
		<text>A good decision, there's nothing to regret.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2412">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_24121">
		<text>Well, as you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_251">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_261">
		<text>Your mission is to kill Tyran, the leader of a group of mercenaries. His crew made it into the Wild Territory and set up a base at the construction site. Be careful, some of their fighters have set up ambushes on the way to the site. As soon as you bring me Tyran's PDA - you'll get your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2611">
		<text>I'll do it. I hope I won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_26111">
		<text>A good decision, there's nothing to regret.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_2612">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_26121">
		<text>Well, as you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_266">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_271">
		<text>Don't hurry, Marked One. You haven't dealt with the veterans yet, and you're already keen to do something else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_311">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_321">
		<text>I've got a serious mission. A group of veteran killers has shown up in the Wild Territory again. Some Duty people came to me and asked me to deal with these veterans. Duty has solid proof that they are responsible for the deaths of solo stalkers. The problem is that these veterans and Duty have some old agreement and Duty can't break it but these guys are really pushing it. Basically, Duty wants them taken out, nice and quiet. It isn't going be easy but the job pays well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_3211">
		<text>Any additional conditions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_32111">
		<text>Duty values its reputation. Therefore, they want it done covertly. You need to destroy their leader, named "Lucky" and bring his PDA as evidence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_32112">
		<text>I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_321121">
		<text>A good decision, there's nothing to regret.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_32113">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_321131">
		<text>Well, as you wish... Just remember, this is a good opportunity to get appreciation from Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_32121">
		<text>default text</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_331">
		<text>Your mission is to kill Tyran, the leader of a group of mercenaries. His crew made it into the Wild Territory and set up a base at the construction site. Be careful, some of their fighters have set up ambushes on the way to the site. As soon as you bring me Tyran's PDA - you'll get your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_3312">
		<text>I'll do it..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_33121">
		<text>A good decision, there's nothing to regret.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_3313">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_33131">
		<text>Well, as you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_341">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_351">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_361">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_371">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_41">
		<text>Not yet, another time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_441">
		<text>I've got a job for a professional.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_442">
		<text>Get to the point. What should be done?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_443">
		<text>Your mission is to kill Tyran, the leader of a group of mercenaries. His crew made it into the Wild Territory and set up a base at the construction site. Be careful, some of their fighters have set up ambushes on the way to the site. As soon as you bring me Tyran's PDA - you'll get your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_4431">
		<text>Understood. I hope I won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_44311">
		<text>A good decision, there's nothing to regret.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_4432">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_44321">
		<text>Well, as you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_444">
		<text>No, I'm not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_52">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_531">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_541">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_62">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_jobs_72">
		<text>No, nothing today.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1111">
		<text>Well, shall we start? Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1131">
		<text>Hmm... What are you still doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_121">
		<text>Well, marked one, do you have the documents from the X-16?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1211">
		<text>Yes, here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1212">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_12121">
		<text>Get them, damn you. Here I am, busting my ass, bending over backwards for you, and you let me down. Get those damn documents! Without them, we won't make any progress!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_121211">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_131">
		<text>Well, Marked One, all that remains now, is to turn off the "Brain Scorcher" and open a passage to the North. Are you ready to go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1312">
		<text>I'm ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_13121">
		<text>Well then, Marked One, you have the prototype protective helmet to protect yourself from the Brain Scorcher. Here are the coordinates of the bunker. Don't forget that the prototype can't protect you indefinitely from the radiation. You should get into the bunker under the antennas, and disable the Scorcher as quickly as possible. I don't know what will happen next, but I feel that it's worth it! I know one thing for sure - the road to the centre of the Zone will be open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1313">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1314">
		<text>All you have to do is to get to the bunker under the antennas and disable them. All clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1315">
		<text>Clear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1316">
		<text>Yes, there's another thing! The leader of Duty, I marked him on the map, needs a volunteer to perform some task at a the Army Warehouses. If you're interested, you can go and see him. I'll arrange it with the security to let you in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_132">
		<text>No, I'm not ready yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1321">
		<text>Well get ready, Marked One! This task can't wait!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_151">
		<text>OK, the documents you brought from the Institute make some things a little clearer but we're still missing the info we need to get a full picture. A lab designated X-18 is mentioned and its description matches the abandoned underground vaults in the Dark Valley. Looks like you'll have to go there and get the info we need. The lab is closed and you'll need two electronic keys to get inside. I'll give you one but you'll have to get the other one from Borov in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1511">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15111">
		<text>All you have to do is to acquire the second key to Lab X-18, get inside and retrieve the second batch of documents. Don't forget to get yourself a protective suit or you won't have a chance of getting to the lab. So, will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15112">
		<text>I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15113">
		<text>Great! I'll be waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15114">
		<text>No, I don't want to do it yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_15115">
		<text>It's up to you but remember: this is the only way that can help us open the road to the North.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_161">
		<text>What do you want, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_162">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! Times change but you're still grumpy and aloof. Here, take a seat, have a drink - maybe you'll mellow a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_171">
		<text>So, Marked One, have you brought the documents from X-18?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_172">
		<text>Yeah. Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1721">
		<text>Good, the situation is becoming clearer. As I expected this Brain Scorcher is man-made. It's a Kaymanov experimental emitter and its components were manufactured in the X-18. These documents refer to the X-16 lab where they sent some components. According to this, the X-16 is located in the production complex area by Lake Yantar. The scientists have set up a mobile lab around there so maybe they can help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17211">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17212">
		<text>The situation is difficult: You need to get to the scientists and find out where the X-16 is so you can get the missing documents. So, you up for it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17213">
		<text>Yeah.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_172131">
		<text>Great! I'll be waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_17214">
		<text>No, I'm not ready yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_172141">
		<text>Well, get ready real quick, Marked One! This sort of business can't wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_173">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_1731">
		<text>What are you wasting time for? Go get those damn documents or we won't make any progress!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_181">
		<text>What do you want, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_182">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! Times change but you're still grumpy and aloof. Here, take a seat, have a drink - maybe you'll mellow a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! Have you brought the documents from the Agroprom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_21">
		<text>No, I haven't got the documents yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_211">
		<text>That's not good, Marked One, not good at all... You understand how much we need them, don't you? We need them real bad, believe me. The Brain Scorcher is right under our noses but we don't even know what it is! Go get the documents right now - we'll talk after that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2111">
		<text>I think I understand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_22">
		<text>Here are the documents from the Agroprom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_221">
		<text>Great work, Marked One! We have the documents at last. I need to have a look at them now and maybe I'll work out how to get North. While I do that, if you have problems with money, you can fight at the Arena. The owner of the Arena is Arnie, I've uploaded his coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_2211">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_22111">
		<text>Now listen up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_3">
		<text>What do you want, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_start_4">
		<text>Hey, Marked One! Times change but you're still grumpy and aloof. Here, take a seat, have a drink - maybe you'll mellow a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_0">
		<text>I want to find out something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_1">
		<text>What is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_10">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_3">
		<text>What do you know about Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_31">
		<text>An experienced stalker as far as I know. He used to "work" through the northern exits from the Zone. He was hardly ever seen here but there are rumours that he took his group right into the centre of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_4">
		<text>What do you know about a stalker they call Ghost?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_41">
		<text>He's one of Strelok's men. They say he can sneak in anywhere without being noticed. I heard that he took out the leader of some crazy group... what was the name? Ah, 'Last Days', that's the one. They were pretty wild those boys... Oh, by the way, I heard that Ghost was doing some job for the scientists, so if you're looking for him try the mobile lab at Lake Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_51">
		<text>He's an old stalker in retirement. He lives in the marshes, I'll mark it on the map for you. He used to be in Strelok's group back in the day.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_6">
		<text>What do you know about a stalker called Fang?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_61">
		<text>There was a man that went by that name, spoke with a lisp... He was a bit weird, that's for sure - talked to himself and stuff... But he seemed like an okay guy. I haven't seen him at the Bar for ages.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_7">
		<text>Tell me about the mobile science labs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_71">
		<text>Scientists set them up from time to time. Isolated metal bunkers with everything you need to live. We're in contact with one of these labs in Yantar. Scientists are good guys - they tell us a lot of interesting things and we help them out when we can... An exchange of sorts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8">
		<text>What is the "Wish Granter"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81">
		<text>Oh! That's an interesting question... I wish I knew the answer. I can tell you the legend about the Granter if you want but you make up your own mind how much truth there's in it. Want to hear it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811">
		<text>Well, that's very interesting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8111">
		<text>This legend is about the "Monolith", which may be what caused the Zone to appear. When the Zone exploded in 2006, they evacuated people living near it and the Zone itself was cordoned off by the Army. Everyone was panicking, nobody knew what was going on, the Zone was expanding and the field labs couldn't do anything! Loads of people died there. Everyone was afraid of the radiation which could affect half of Europe. After a few years passed, some reckless guys like you appeared. They called themselves stalkers. They started to sneak past army cordons believing that there were things in the Zone that would make them rich. Bit by bit, they brought out weird things, artifacts, and immediately there began a race for them. Scientists went after them like crazy. They paid fantastic money for just one piece back then, not like now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81111">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111">
		<text>After a while, the first tales and legends about what's deep inside the Zone by the tumbledown nuclear power plant started to circulate. It was also then that one of the veterans told us the story of a Monolith that allegedly granted one's wishes. You should have seen the hysteria: experienced, level-headed men started trying to break through to the centre - everyone wanted something from the "Monolith". We got some morbid details about the first stalker who made it through to the "Monolith"...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8111111">
		<text>Go on... Tell me more...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_81111111">
		<text>When the Zone just appeared many people got trapped inside and became cut off from the outside world. Most of them died pretty quickly but there were a few lucky survivors who tried to do something about it. One of these survivors found himself by the station and noticed some strange light inside. With no way back he decided to try to get closer. He saw the broken roof of the sarcophagus and the light coming out through it. He climbed up the wall and looked inside. Among the debris of metal and molten concrete there lay a massive black rock. It was the "Monolith". The stalker managed to shake off the "spell" and realised that he had climbed very close to the sarcophagus, which was highly radioactive. He was scared to death but through the fear he could sense the "Monolith" calling him. It called him and he came to see strange, unbelievable things inside his head...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111111">
		<text>Cool...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_811111112">
		<text>I don't know what's true in this story and what's not, but the point is, the guy made a wish which came true, and the Zone grew by 5 kilometres. It seems the Zone gobbles up more land for every wish that is granted... But that isn't going to stop hotshots like you. They keep trying to break through with their precious little wishes in their hearts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_812">
		<text>I'm more interested in other things at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_barmen_talk_info_8121">
		<text>That's your business, man. What exactly do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_11">
		<text>Hic... damn it! Yes, I'm drunk, I'm drunk! They want...they... want to kick me out of Duty if I fail this task too... you know? But I'm not...hic... not feeling too...hic... good at the moment... you know...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_111">
		<text>I feel for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_21">
		<text>What's up? Any news? You haven't whacked the little piece of shit, I can see it in your eyes. Life sucks... Listen, at least have a drink with me, will you, friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_drunk_dolg_start_31">
		<text>Man...hic... you... you... you helped me! Let's drink to Duty... I guess! And...Oh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_finish_0">
		<text>I found it. Here is your rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_finish_1">
		<text>Wow?! You found my rifle?! I'm lost for words, man! Thank you so much! THANK YOU! I'm so grateful! You really helped me out here, you really did. Goddamn it. Here take this - it isn't much but it's all I got. I won't forget your help and I hope to repay you in time. Listen, I'll tell you something. There's a weird boarded-up house near that place where you found my rifle. Nobody knows what's really inside it but you can see through the windows that there are anomalies there, lots of them. There might be artifacts in there too... I don't know how to get there though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_0">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_1">
		<text>I'll give you anything! Just return my rifle, I beg you. I lost it by that place where those damn bloodsuckers live. Here are the coordinates. Be careful though. Bloodsuckers aren't the friendly type.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_11">
		<text>OK, I'll try to get your rifle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_111">
		<text>I wouldn't cheat you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_1111">
		<text>It's in your interest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_12">
		<text>No. I've got more important things to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_121">
		<text>That's up to you... But I hope you change your mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_quest_start_1212">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_start_11">
		<text>I've got a big problem man! I... I lost my family rifle in the Wild Territory. I wanted to shoot some bloodsuckers but I barely got away. Damn! Listen, bro... If you get it back I'll pay you. I've made a little cash here and I'll give you all of it, just get my rifle back. It's a family rifle, you know, passed down from father to son... And I lost it! I've grown used to it, it's like an extension of my arm now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_start_21">
		<text>Hey! Any news? Did you find it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_hunter_start_31">
		<text>Thanks bro! I'll never forget that you helped me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_0">
		<text>Wolfhound said you've got something for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_1">
		<text>Sure. Here is a grenade launcher for helping him with Kruglov, and a "grand" in cash on top. I'll give you some useful info for free to sweeten the deal too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_2">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_reward_3">
		<text>Here's what I got to say. You've helped Freedom and made the right choice. Your fate is now tied with that of Freedom, and Duty has you in its sights. I'd say you ought to go to the abandoned military base and join the ranks of Freedom - they need good fighters. There will be shootouts between the groups soon and whoever chooses the right side won't regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_11">
		<text>I work as a dealer of information. I sell important info and buy charts, documents and lab records. My information is valuable and very useful to the one who possesses it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_21">
		<text>Hello, Marked One. You've helped Freedom and made the right choice. Your fate is now tied with that of Freedom and Duty has you in its sights. I'd suggest you go to the abandoned military base and join Freedom - they need good fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_211">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_start_2111">
		<text>So Marked One, what brings you here? Want to buy some information or are you selling today?</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Anomalous bolts -->
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt">
		<text>I heard that you might have an interesting offer for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_start">
		<text>Yes Marked One, I do have one... Incidentally, have you found any unusual bolts? They are the same as normal bolts which each stalker uses, only they shine in the dark as if illuminated from within. Fuck knows what other properties they possess besides luminescence... Well, there was a person, whose identity shall remain unknown, who came to me recently. He told me he had been part of an expedition of scientists who had dug up such a bolt, somewhere. He was sure that obviously, there were more of these, not just one. Generally, I'm placing an order for 20 bolts at least, if you find more - great, bring them to me. But for lots of 20 bolts, you'll be well compensated... Let's say, 30 thousand. Such a recompense for the bolts, in my opinion, it quite fair. Well, what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_start_yes1">
		<text>Well, okay, I've already scraped up a few bolts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_start_yes2">
		<text>Well, I agree, I will attentively look around for these bolts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_start_no">
		<text>No, not now, I'm not up for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_20">
		<text>About your bolts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_20_done">
		<text>Well done, here, this is for you, in addition to money, a little prize from me</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_20_start">
		<text>Well, did you find any?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_20_yes">
		<text>Here you go. I looked damn everywhere to collect them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_20_malo">
		<text>Yes, but not yet the agreed amount.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_20_no">
		<text>Yes, I found as many as I could.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_over">
		<text>I've found another bolt for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_over_start">
		<text>Have you decided to exceed the the agreed amount of the bolts?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_over_yes">
		<text>Yes, take them. What am I to get for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_osvedomitel_bolt_over_no">
		<text>No, I'm not ready to give them away, I may need them myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_0">
		<text>So you're connected with Freedom then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_1">
		<text>I can't answer that question right now. All I can say is that I am not a member of any group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_0">
		<text>Tell me about the Freedom faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_1">
		<text>Sure, no problem! Freedom is one of the oldest groups in the Zone and the only one that openly opposes government troops and research teams. Its founders are dead - they were killed during a big bloodbath after the army dropped a large assault force in the Zone. But the ability to control the Zone from outside was destroyed at the same time. There is some evidence to suggest that the first Zone was used as a secret army weapons' testing site. If that's true... Well, they must have used some powerful shit. Anyway, what was I saying?.. Oh yeah, Freedom is the only group that is trying to stop the government from gaining control over the testing site again. God knows what will happen if they start testing their shit again, so Freedom is trying to hold out at all costs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_2">
		<text>What about Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_3">
		<text>Duty is basically controlled from the outside by the government. Their current objective is to clear the territory of mutants and destroy Freedom, which is what they are doing at the moment. When the time is right, they will drop a large assault force in the Zone and take control of the area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_talk_about_freedom_4">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_0">
		<text>I want to buy some information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_21">
		<text>Right now, I can sell you information about Strelok's group virtually for nothing - 4000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_211">
		<text>OK, I'll take it. Here's 4000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_2111">
		<text>It's located by the Agroprom Research Institute, there's a stash in the underground. It probably contains information about the group's plans and a list of group members. The coordinates of the stash are attached.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_212">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_2121">
		<text>Up to you. Come to the bar when you decide otherwise - I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_31">
		<text>Right now, I have some information about a group that made it to the centre of the Zone. I'm practically giving it away - only 5000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_311">
		<text>OK, I'll buy it. Here's 5000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_3111">
		<text>Strelok, Ghost and Fang went to the centre of the Zone. What they found there, no one knows, but Strelok went missing while Ghost and Fang came back distraught. The latest news on Ghost is that he went to the mobile lab by Lake Yantar. Coordinates of the scientists' camp are attached.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_312">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_3121">
		<text>Up to you. Come to the bar when you decide otherwise - I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_41">
		<text>I've got some information about the secret of Lake Yantar. The price is just 5500 roubles - any less and I'd be paying you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_411">
		<text>Okay, I'll buy it. Take 5500.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_4111">
		<text>The secret of Lake Yantar is similar to the secret of the Brain Scorcher and their effects are similar in many ways. Some kind of emission zombifies all who come in contact with it. The zombified stalkers move around the centre of some emitter, attacking everyone. There is information to suggest that the solution to the riddle of Lake Yantar is below the ground. Here are the coordinates of the emitter at Lake Yantar and those of the Brain Scorcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_412">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_4121">
		<text>Up to you. Come to the bar when you decide otherwise - I'm always here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_trade_info_999">
		<text>I don't have any new information at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_11">
		<text>...It's about time someone whacked Borov! If I knew who it was, I'd buy him a drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_111">
		<text>Yeah, it was about time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_21">
		<text>...Someone really pissed off Freedom: I heard one of their groups was destroyed in the Wild Territory...I wonder who did it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_211">
		<text>Yeah, I wish I knew...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_31">
		<text>...Finally someone had the balls to clear out the bloodsuckers in the Wild Territory... What was Duty doing all this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_311">
		<text>What was Duty doing? They were doing Freedom, what else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_41">
		<text>...I heard someone whacked the leader of Freedom. They're in for some tough times I think. Duty is going to really put a squeeze on them now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_411">
		<text>Let's hope so.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_51">
		<text>So you wiped out those veterans? Well done, friend! Six stalkers went missing in that area recently... We all suspected those mad veterans. It's a good thing that they've been dealt with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_511">
		<text>Yeah, many people wanted those veterans to "leave".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_61">
		<text>You turned off the emissions at Yantar? Wow... You're a lucky nut, damn it! I'm glad that someone finally managed to deal with that thing! You can't imagine how many of our boys died there... But now the scientists will work out what it was. We might even be able to deal with the Scorcher now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_611">
		<text>I want to believe that the Scorcher can be switched off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_71">
		<text>What do you want? Don't you see, I'm trying to relax here...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_7111">
		<text>I heard the rumour that Strelok came back. He's got all the equipment to get to the Wish Granter... He's hiding now though 'cause a lot of people are after him. Some are open about it while others are trying to keep their interest a secret. Rumour has it even Duty and Freedom have joined the hunt... Each with their own agenda.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_1_start_71111">
		<text>Looks like Strelok is right to hide.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_7111">
		<text>Useful to a rookie? Well, listen up. To the North, not far from the Brain Scorcher, Freedom have set up their HQ in an old military base. They're notorious nihilists, anarchists and criminals - freedom fighters, freaking guerrillas all of them. All they do is sabotage research groups, attack army units and constantly skirmish with Duty. These skirmishes are now spilling over into a small-scale war for survival. Let me give you some advice: never get involved with them. They'll only accept you if you're totally crazy and there's a reward on your head. Ha-ha-ha. Can you believe that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_10_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for your advice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_7111">
		<text>Well, there used to be this group led by Strelok. There were all sorts of legends about it going around the Zone... good and bad, but few people really knew the truth. The truth is that they wanted to deal with the Zone, find out what created it. That's why military stalkers were after them but they didn't know where to look. The government didn't want normal stalkers to know things they shouldn't have known. One day Strelok found something really important and made a move towards the centre of the Zone with some of his boys. Half of the group died on the way but the rest made it through... What happened to them there - no one knows. Looks like they've copped it. The other group members were caught and killed off... I don't think there are any of them left now. Sad story, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_12_start_71111">
		<text>Yeah... Looks like someone really doesn't want the Zone to be understood...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_7111">
		<text>The mercenaries are kind of like Freedom, only worse. At least Freedom have some ideals, but these dogs, they'll do anything for money. Someone really needs to kill them all before they drag something really dangerous out of the Zone into the normal world! They're based in the Dead City and there's a sniper in every tall building, understand? They're not keen on strangers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_13_start_71111">
		<text>I see. Looks like you have to be careful in the Dead City.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_711">
		<text>Can you tell me anything that would be useful to a rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_7111">
		<text>If you haven't been in the Arena, I'd recommend it - it's a good way to make money and show everyone what you can do. Not everyone has the balls to fight a monster and that's a pity! Man, as soon as I save up enough cash for decent armour, I'm there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_81">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_82">
		<text>Are you Baldy? I need to talk to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_83">
		<text>Suppose I am. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_84">
		<text>Spotty got saved from the Scorcher area, but Hunchback is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_85">
		<text>Damn it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_86">
		<text>Spotty is in bad shape, his brain doesn't work well. Maybe you can talk to him? We need to find out the Scorcher's schedule.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_87">
		<text>No! Don't ask me to do this. Hunchback is dead because of me and what happened to Spotty is my fault too. I left them, betrayed them, deserted them and ran away! I can't look Spotty in the eyes after what I did!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_88">
		<text>Come on, chill out. Tell me what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_89">
		<text>The three of us, Baldy, Spotty and myself were getting ready to try to get through to the North. We didn't know when the Scorcher emissions were at lowest, but Spotty managed to get the information somewhere... I don't know where... We were half-way through the sector, when the Scorcher suddenly switched on again. Spotty passed out straight away and fell down the hillside. I panicked and said that we should leave everything and go back. Hunchback managed to pull himself together and said that we had to get Spotty out... I said "You're an idiot, don't you want to live? It's over for him, how are we going to carry him all the way back?" Just as he managed to convince me and started to climb down to get Spotty... another wave came. By the time I came to my senses I was by the military base... I thought Hunchback and Spotty stayed there... But Hunchback got him out and didn't make it himself... He got Spotty out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_90">
		<text>OK, Baldy, OK. Calm down, man. Thanks for telling me what happened. I'll talk to Spotty myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_14_start_91">
		<text>Sorry. I'm not in the mood for talking... I'd rather just have another drink...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_7111">
		<text>There was a guy... He had a lisp and walked with a stoop, so he got the name Hunchback. He was a bit crazy... Talked to himself and to animals... But apart from that, he was alright. He disappeared a long time ago in the centre with Strelok... Though they say Strelok is back now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_2_start_71111">
		<text>I wonder where he is now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_711">
		<text>What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_7111">
		<text>The Wild Territory is infested with bloodsuckers now! They come out at night. I heard there's something really important at the factory that's nearby, something essential to someone. Duty sent some guys in there recently but they all died and their screams were heard kilometres away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_3_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_711">
		<text>What have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_7111">
		<text>If you go around Lake Yantar you'll come to the scientists' camp - they do research of some sort there... They were dropped in by a helicopter and they get regular supplies too. They've got a nice spot there really... You can deal with them too - they buy artifacts and might even give you a job to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_4_start_71111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_711">
		<text>What have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_7111">
		<text>Nobody has managed to get through the vehicle scrap yard because of the Brain Scorcher. Some people did see a stalker go through some invisible border, fall over, then get up in a couple of minutes and head straight for the centre of the scrap yards. He ain't been seen since...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_5_start_71111">
		<text>Interesting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_711">
		<text>What have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_7111">
		<text>Missing stalkers come back from time to time. It's a scary sight, I tell you: they mumble something and try to reach for their weapons, which they lost somewhere... One came to a Duty outpost some time ago and a crowd gathered to look at him. Someone even recognized him... He was scary... red eyes, all bloodshot and bruised... Couldn't say a word, just moaned like an animal and went around in circles. Duty took him in, but he died after a couple of days anyway. Something happens to people in the Zone, but what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_6_start_71111">
		<text>I'd like to know that too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_711">
		<text>What have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_7111">
		<text>There are a lot of zombies around Lake Yantar. They wander around and attack any human they see. If you're spotted you might want to run for your life - there are too many of those former stalkers around there... They died at the lake and that's all that's left of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_7_start_71111">
		<text>Yeah, I wouldn't want to join them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_711">
		<text>What have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_7111">
		<text>Traders say that there's a real treasure trove of artifacts in the centre of the Zone, so anyone who makes it through will make enough money for two lifetimes. Personally, I think there's more to this. Obviously the traders think about their own interests, but there are strange rumours going around. Apparently, there's something better than artifacts there - something that isn't from this world, something alien or from another dimension altogether! They call it the Wish-granting Machine. I heard a legend about a stalker who made it through. Only every time someone makes a wish the Zone grows and nobody who gets there uses his wish to make the Zone disappear. I guess when one gets to the Machine he doesn't give a shit about anyone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_8_start_71111">
		<text>That's sad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_71">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_711">
		<text>What have you heard?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_7111">
		<text>Everyone who believes in the "Monolith" is completely nuts. They keep banging on about it but nobody actually knows what's in the centre of the Zone. An invisible crystal that fell from the skies...ha-ha-ha! I reckon one of the secret labs blew up - I mean some stalkers used to work in a few of them. But, obviously, you can't bomb the Zone. Not only will the radiation spread all over the world, half of Europe would be flattened by the Zone's reaction. Monolithians have gone totally mad lately - I heard they're killing normal stalkers for no reason at all. How do you like that? Damn fanatics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_bar_visitors_9_start_71111">
		<text>I think it deserves some attention.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_0">
		<text>I want to join Duty. What do I need to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_1">
		<text>Pay 1000 roubles. You'll get a pass. Take that to Voronin in the bunker and he'll arrange a test for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_11">
		<text>OK, here's the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_111">
		<text>Right, here is your pass. Go see Petrenko, the administrator. I've marked his location on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_12">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_121">
		<text>Your choice, man. See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_21">
		<text>Because there is no place for those Freedom bandits in the Zone - they must be destroyed. If you're interested, go ask Barkeep to explain everything. I'm busy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_31">
		<text>Pay 1000 roubles and you'll get a pass. Take that to Duty's administrator and he'll arrange tests for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_311">
		<text>OK, here's the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_3111">
		<text>Right, here is your pass. Go see Petrenko, the administrator. I've marked his location on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_312">
		<text>No, I changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_acces_3121">
		<text>Your choice, man. See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_0">
		<text>Barkeep told me that your leader has some sort of assignment for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_1">
		<text>Yes, he let us know about you, but before we let you in I want to brief you on our rules. So listen, our rules are simple. First rule - it's forbidden to shoot on our territory. If you break the rule twice, our patrol will open fire on you. Even if you make a run for it, you won't appear on our territory again - our guards will make sure of that. If you act calmly, you won't have any problems.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_2">
		<text>Got it. Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_3">
		<text>Yes, that's enough. You can pass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_4">
		<text>Got it. Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_rules_5">
		<text>That's all about it. If you want to try to join Duty, feel free. We need good men but I'm warning you: before being accepted, you'll have to do a few dangerous jobs. We don't need pussies so everyone is tested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_11">
		<text>Halt! Outsiders aren't allowed in Duty base!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_21">
		<text>What are you standing there for? Keep moving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_start_31">
		<text>Go on, bro. Remember: Duty's mission is to cleanse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_0">
		<text>Why don't you let outsiders in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_1">
		<text>Where did you naive boys come from? There's a war going on, right? We're fighting Freedom bandits! We have regular skirmishes with their fighters wherever we cross paths.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_2">
		<text>A war with Freedom? Why?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_base_guard_talk_3">
		<text>Because there is no place for those Freedom bandits in the Zone - they must be destroyed. If you're interested, go ask Barkeep to explain everything. I'm busy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_11">
		<text>Halt! Only Duty members can go in there! We can't let you inside the bunker without a special pass. If you want to get one go see Colonel Petrenko. He's in the administration area across the yard.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_21">
		<text>What are you standing there for? Keep moving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_guard_bunker_start_31">
		<text>Go on. Remember: Duty's mission is to cleanse.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_11">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_21">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_start_31">
		<text>Hello, friend.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_job_0">
		<text>What can I do for Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_job_1">
		<text>That's a good question, Marked One and there's an equally good answer to it - kill Freedom anarchists. You'll get a reward for every PDA of theirs you bring and you might get promoted too. Take all the PDAs you get to Petrenko - he gives out the rewards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_0">
		<text>Barkeep told me that you have some assignment for me at the Army Warehouses...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_1">
		<text>I want to ask you to do one thing, personally for me, you see? We're in the midst of territorial warfare with the Freedom faction and we need some weapons more powerful than what we have. Freedom has some excellent M202 flame throwers. If you could penetrate their territory and steal at least one such flame thrower, I would generously reward you. Since you aren't in our faction, you can quickly gain the trust of Freedom and, if you're lucky, get hold of an M202.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_11">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_111">
		<text>I'll upload the location of the Freedom base to your PDA. You'll need to find their cook. He's a member of Freedom. He knows where the M202s are kept. And he likes his booze so bring a lot of vodka with you. So, what do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_1111">
		<text>OK, I'll try to steal an M202 from Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_11111">
		<text>Oh, and one more thing. Colonel Skullov and his boys disobeyed my order and decided to attack the Freedom base without authorization. Well, they can reap what they sow... suicidal bastards. Skull has been long begging to be taught a lesson... Don't get involved in their fight. Just try to get me the flame thrower - nothing else matters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_1112">
		<text>I'm not ready for such exploits just yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_join_11121">
		<text>That's up to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_0">
		<text>I'm ready to take the oath!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_00">
		<text>Well, Marked One. We won't forget what you did for us. Therefore, I am ready to admit you into Duty at any time. Come when you make up your mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_01">
		<text>No, I'm not ready to serve Duty yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_02">
		<text>The war with Freedom is nearing its end, Marked One. You have contributed to our common cause, and now you can become a full member of Duty. Are you ready to take the oath?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hochu_vstupit">
		<text>I decided to join Duty after all, and I'm ready to take the oath!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_1">
		<text>Good man! Repeat after me: "I, a stalker known as Marked One, swear to defend the goals and ideals of Duty."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_2">
		<text>I, a stalker known as Marked One, swear to defend the goals and ideals of Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_3">
		<text>To protect the Earth from the dangers of the Zone, to seek out and destroy anything it spawns within and beyond its borders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_4">
		<text>To protect the Earth from the dangers of the Zone, to seek out and destroy anything it spawns within and beyond its borders.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_5">
		<text>To fight any nonconformists, be they individual stalkers or groups.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_6">
		<text>To fight any nonconformists, be they individual stalkers or groups.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_7">
		<text>And to give my life in the name of justice and order on Earth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_8">
		<text>And to give my life in the name of justice and order on Earth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_prisyaga_9">
		<text>Congratulations! You are now a full member of Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_rg6_finish_0">
		<text>I've completed the mission and brought the M202.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_rg6_finish_1">
		<text>Good job, stalker. This is exactly what we need. Well, Marked One, you fulfilled my request, here's a reward for you. Also, I am ready now to take you into Duty. Are you ready to take the oath, Marked One?\n\n(ATTENTION! Joining the Duty group cannot be undone, and this action effectively cuts you off from Freedom quests.)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_11">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_21">
		<text>What brings you here, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_31">
		<text>You brought the 202?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_311">
		<text>Yes, here is the 202.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_3111">
		<text>Good job, stalker. This is exactly what we need. Well, Marked One, you fulfilled my request, here's a reward for you. Also, I am ready now to take you into Duty. Are you ready to take the oath, Marked One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_41">
		<text>What brought you to me, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_51">
		<text>The war with Freedom is coming to an end, Marked One. You played your part in fighting for the cause and now I want to finish this war. I want you to kill the Freedom leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_leader_start_81">
		<text>What brings you here, brother? You killed the leader of those Freedom anarchists and their group has crumbled. The war is not over yet but its outcome is certain. Your achievements are great and they will not be forgotten.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_newbie_start_11">
		<text>Hello, stalker. Join Duty! We need good fighters! I only joined recently and look at the cool uniform they gave me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_newbie_start_21">
		<text>Hello, Marked One. I'm glad you're with us. Duty is really going to need good fighters soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_2">
		<text>Hey, fellow stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_3">
		<text>Tell me about Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_31">
		<text>We've been here since the beginning. The first group was made up of the surviving members of a special unit sent into the Zone to find out what caused it to appear. They found themselves in pretty dire circumstances. After half of the unit died horribly, those who survived swore that they wouldn't leave until they found out what was going on in the Zone...  Until they defeat it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_4">
		<text>Tell me about Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_41">
		<text>They're thugs who don't understand that the Zone is an ulcer on Earth's body. They want to spread it all over the world, a piece in every household. They'll do anything to achieve that goal and I can't wait us to put an end to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_5">
		<text>You want to defeat the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_51">
		<text>Yes and we managed to a large degree. During the cleaning operations, whole swarms of mutants on the way to the Zone's centre were destroyed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_novice_start_6">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_11">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_21">
		<text>How can I help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_petrenko_start_31">
		<text>Hello brother! What brings you to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_veteran_start_2">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_11">
		<text>Go on, keep moving. What are you staring at?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_21">
		<text>Hey man! I'm glad you haven't been eaten by mutants yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_about_zastava_0">
		<text>Looks like a massacre took place by the outpost. What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_about_zastava_1">
		<text>That's the remnants of the last wave of mutants that came before the Blowout. It's quiet for three or four days and then there's another wave. If not for us, there'd be no Bar, there'd be no Duty; we're the last barrier in the way of these crazy mutants. A lot of our boys met their end here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_0">
		<text>I would like to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_1">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2">
		<text>It's my first time here. Could you tell me a little about this place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21">
		<text>Before the accident in '86 this was an industrial area. As you can see, there isn't much left of it now... In the basement by the hangar you'll find the 100 Rads bar. The place is run by the local trader who doubles up as a barman. If you want to trade, talk, get a mission or find out the latest news, that's the place to go. There's also the Arena where you can fight and make some cash. Duty's base is not far from the Arena. If you want to join Duty go straight over there - they'll tell you who to speak to. Oh, by the way, all of this area is protected by Duty so behave and keep your weapons holstered. If you start shooting, the patrol will "calm you down" pretty quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_211">
		<text>You said there's a bar here. Can you tell me where exactly it is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2111">
		<text>In the basement behind the hangar...I'll mark it on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21111">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_212">
		<text>You said the Duty base is here. How do I get to it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2121">
		<text>It's not far from the Arena. I've marked it on the map for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21211">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_213">
		<text>You said there's an Arena here? Where exactly is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_2131">
		<text>Go out of the hangar with the broken roof and you'll end up right in front of it. I'll mark it on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_21311">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zastava_talk_214">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_0">
		<text>I'm here on business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1">
		<text>I take it you want something from me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_11">
		<text>I shot down a pig on my way here. They say it's a valuable one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_111">
		<text>I heard you shot Borov. You deserve to get some cash and a decent gun for that. Do your new weapon justice!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1111">
		<text>Don't you worry about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_12">
		<text>I had a little "chat" with Tyran of Freedom. Basically, he understood his mistake and promised to behave in future. I'm pretty sure he won't be breaking his word - the dead never lie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_121">
		<text>Tyran was a real pain in the ass for us! I'm glad you terminated him. Here is your reward - our trademark weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1211">
		<text>Not bad. I'm off to do more of the same. See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_13">
		<text>Didn't Voronin tell you anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_131">
		<text>Wow, congratulations! It's quite an achievement to kill Freedom's leader. Man, I wish I were as tough as you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_dolg_zavskald_reward_1311">
		<text>I was just lucky - they nearly wasted me a couple of times. Thanks for the new equipment. I'm off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_0">
		<text>I'd like to know something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_11">
		<text>Who are you and how did you end up here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_111">
		<text>My name is Kruglov. I am a professor of biology, I study the Zone. Yesterday, for example, I found an animal of particular interest - Anthropomorphous Dendromutantus Vulgaris. I mostly find and document new species of mutant animals, their traits and distinctive features. The information is then thoroughly studied and transferred to the outside world. Some of it, of course, goes to Barkeep. My discoveries have helped to save the lives of many stalkers. I was just transporting the results of my latest research to the laboratory near Lake Yantar when the helicopter came under fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_12">
		<text>Tell me about the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_121">
		<text>The Zone is a wonderful gift to humanity. Of course normal existence here is not possible due to the high radiation levels, and aggressive mutants. All of these things are obviously extremely dangerous but they are also things of great scientific value. The Zone is almost a natural experiment, a treasure for scientists! The extent to which humanity's knowledge could be increased through the study of the Zone is unfathomable. Technology, medicine, new plants - medical and edible, biotechnology, cures for incurable diseases... anything! Perhaps we can solve the food problem for the entire planet. If people didn't interfere, science could lead humanity into a new Golden Era!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1211">
		<text>Duty thinks otherwise and even Freedom doesn't seem to want to help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_12111">
		<text>They're simply incapable of grasping the whole picture. Their "here and now" problems are far more important to them than the future of humanity!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_1212">
		<text>Maybe there is some use in studying the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_12121">
		<text>So you understand that too? It's wonderful to discover that there are those among you who are not narrow-minded practical people. I've always said it's important to look at the whole set of issues from a broader perspective, to distance ourselves from the simple human measures. Even if the Zone has done harm to humanity, it can still be of great use to us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_13">
		<text>Why are the mercenaries looking for this information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_131">
		<text>I hope this doesn't offend you, but many stalkers are like children. They are seriously affected by things they find out. Just think of all these legends about a Monolith that grants wishes. What a joke! The problem is that these children play their games with real weapons and cause death. Childish people are often annoyed about the fact that someone doesn't share everything with them, including information that is not meant for them. And they have no limits in the use of force. They shoot without thinking and kill those who study the Zone. They believe that this information will allow them to open the way to the centre of the Zone. They're fools. Naive, yet very dangerous fools!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_14">
		<text>I am looking for the X-16 Lab. Could you tell me where it is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_141">
		<text>Lab X-16? Hmm... Sakharov mentioned something of the sort in passing but I do not recall exactly what he said. Perhaps it's best to ask him yourself... He's currently in the mobile lab by Lake Yantar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_give_info_dp_15">
		<text>Unfortunately I have to go. Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_101">
		<text>Marked One, stop them or they'll kill us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1011">
		<text>Sit tight. I'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_10111">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1012">
		<text>Let's move. We'll try to break through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_10121">
		<text>Let's hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_11">
		<text>Stalker, I'm begging you! We were returning from Yantar when the mercenaries shot down our helicopter. I heard that they are looking for information but I know they'll kill us. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_111">
		<text>Well, let's go, I'll get you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1111">
		<text>Thank you, stalker. I'm not much of a fighter, so... Better you check the way and I will follow you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_112">
		<text>No. Try to get out of here yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_1121">
		<text>No. I am sure you don't mean that. I'll never make it out of here alone. If you change your mind, I'll be here... if I live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_21">
		<text>Hurry, we have to get out of here quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_31">
		<text>Phew! Have we really made it to safety? At last! Thank you so much for your help. I am in debt to you but for now please accept this flash drive. It contains the results of my latest expedition. I am sure the Barkeep would pay well for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_311">
		<text>Yes, we're here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_3111">
		<text>Marked One, if you visit our mobile laboratory at Yantar, we will give you a scientific suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_31111">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_41">
		<text>Good day, stalker. Allow me to express my gratitude on behalf of global science!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_51">
		<text>Marked One, stop them or they'll kill us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_511">
		<text>Sit tight. I'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_5111">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_512">
		<text>Let's move. We'll try to break through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_5121">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_61">
		<text>Marked One, stop them or they'll kill us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_611">
		<text>Sit tight. I'll deal with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_6111">
		<text>OK, I'll wait here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_612">
		<text>Let's move. We'll try to break through...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_6121">
		<text>OK, let's hurry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_71">
		<text>Be careful with the "Burner" anomaly, Marked One. My suit will protect me but you'd better avoid it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_711">
		<text>Thanks for your advice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_professor_start_91">
		<text>Hurry, Marked One. Now is not the time to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_dialog_11">
		<text>Stalker, talk to Professor Kruglov, help him to get out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_dialog_21">
		<text>It's over. They killed Kruglov!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_13">
		<text>Rather crappy actually. However, that's none of your business. It's better to have a beer than tempt fate. This is the Zone after all: I was returning after selling my loot - it's a miracle I came back alive - I could have caught a bullet from one of the patrols - it was sheer luck, and all the rest - is history...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_1">
		<text>1  Yes, and today - it's on the house. Just bear in mind, the first toast goes to Fair One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_2">
		<text>To whom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_3">
		<text>Have you never heard of Fair One?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_4">
		<text>No, never... Who is he?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_5">
		<text>Oh, Marked One! This is the only stalker in the Zone, who cared for others. He gave money to those that were robbed of their loot by bandits, and even bought them drinks. One day he came to me and said that he was leaving to join "Monolith", and asked me to pray for his happiness. He left me all his money and artifacts. He said that if he didn't return the following week for his property, then I was to use it to treat stalkers to beer. Now, I treat you to one. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_6">
		<text>I've heard of him now... Let's have a beer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_7">
		<text>Yes, in respect. Let's drink!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_barman_pivo_8">
		<text>Here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_0">
		<text>Listen buddy, I have some very valuable information for your commander, can you let me pass?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_1">
		<text>In principle it's possible, but quid pro quo. I need you to do something, Marked One. I urgently need an accurate and completely silent weapon. Namely, a crossbow. Can you bring me this thing? I know for sure that there's one in those Freedom assholes' armoury. Will you be able to steal it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_2">
		<text>You're... Okay, wait, I'll get you that shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ohran_propusk_3">
		<text>You're... Forget it, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_friend_propusk_0">
		<text>Hi, sergeant. You haven't forgotten our arrangement, have you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_friend_propusk_1">
		<text>Don't worry, I haven't. Have you fulfilled your part of the bargain?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_friend_propusk_2">
		<text>Yeah, I got it. It wasn't easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_friend_propusk_3">
		<text>Well, that's how it goes. Thanks for getting it, it's an excellent piece! Come on in - don't just stand there.</text>
	</string>
	<!--secret teleport v bar-->
	<string id="veryuseful_0">
		<text>You know a lot of things, but is there anything useful you can tell me about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veryuseful_1">
		<text>For you, "my hero", there is. I'm sure this information will be very useful to you in future. He-he. But it is really very expensive. Ready to give up about fifty grand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veryuseful_2">
		<text>Wow! Okay, take it, I'm sure it's worth the money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veryuseful_3">
		<text>You expect me to pay that sort of money for a cat in a bag? Go take a deep breath!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veryuseful_4">
		<text>So listen. Barkeep often has customers who aren't too keen to come into Duty territory. So, there is a small wormhole leading straight into his storeroom. A stalker named Physicist created it. How? I don't know, so don't ask, Physicist was obviously smarter than all these egghead nerds put together. You'll find the entrance to the wormhole at the back of the Bar, where nobody goes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veryuseful_5">
		<text>Thank you, I'll go look for it. That's really useful information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_1">
		<text>I'm looking for a stalker who recently came to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_2">
		<text>All sorts come to me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_3">
		<text>They call him One-eyed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_4">
		<text>Yes, he was here a couple of days ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_5">
		<text>What did he buy and where did he go then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_6">
		<text>He bought a lot of things, but what it was exactly - that I won't tell you, sorry. Who knows, maybe you turn out to be a gun-runner or a mugger! If I remember correctly, he left in the direction of the Army Warehouses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_odnogl_dialog_1_phrase_7">
		<text>Well, thanks for that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_1">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_2">
		<text>Well, hello, homeboy! I've been looking for you for some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_3">
		<text>Hi. Do we know each other?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_4">
		<text>Of course we do! We only have the same motherland - the Zone, the devil take it! How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_5">
		<text>So-so. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_6">
		<text>I know why you came here. You came to find someone. I am a friend of One-eyed, the one you've been looking for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_7">
		<text>Where're Radioman, Owl and Chatterbox?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_8">
		<text>They're all sitting in a safe place, I was sent here to find you and pick up Veteran's flash drive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_10">
		<text>Wait, are you sure you're his friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_11">
		<text>Well, who else's, blah?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_12">
		<text>Then tell me: out of five of you, who divided the map into five parts? If you really are who you say you are, you must know the correct answer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_13">
		<text>Why should I know? Give me the flash drive, and I'll deliver it to the appropriate person.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_14">
		<text>No, I won't give it to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_15">
		<text>In that case, take the road to the Army Warehouses. One-eyed has been waiting for you over there, in the bushes right around the corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_2_phrase_16">
		<text>Good...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_1_phrase_1">
		<text>Hey, man! Lets have a brief conversation, ok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_kulg_agent_dialog_1_phrase_2">
		<text>Well, no objection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>How about some dice?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Come on. "Under and Over", a fast one. For how much shall we play?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>For 200 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>For 500 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>For 1000 roubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>For booze.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>For artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Well, let's go! Throw the dice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>~ROLL THE DICE~</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>What artifact will you bet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>"Stone Blood"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>"Meat Chunk"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>"Soul"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>"Slug"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>"Slime"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>"Mica"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>"Jellyfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_18">
		<text>"Stone Flower"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_19">
		<text>"Night Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_20">
		<text>"Sparkler"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_21">
		<text>"Flash"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_22">
		<text>"Moonlight"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_23">
		<text>"Wrenched"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_24">
		<text>"Gravi"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_25">
		<text>"Goldfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_26">
		<text>"Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_27">
		<text>"Crystal Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_28">
		<text>"Sea Urchin"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_29">
		<text>"Droplets"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_30">
		<text>"Fireball"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_31">
		<text>"Crystal"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_32">
		<text>Roll the dice!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="play_dialog_phrase_33">
		<text>~ROLL THE DICE~</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_1">
		<text>Well, you woke up? Now then, you better come to your senses if you want to get your ass out of here in one piece!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_2">
		<text>Oh, damn it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_3">
		<text>This is a personal one from me to you. Come on tell me who you are and where you come from!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_4">
		<text>You can go to hell with your questions!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_5">
		<text>All right, wait, I'll tell you everything, sir...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_6">
		<text>Why the hell did you hit me for no reason, no reason at all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_7">
		<text>I see that you didn't understand my question. Okay, let me try to make it more comprehensible...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_8">
		<text>Damn you! Playing the part of an investigator, huh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_9">
		<text>I'm not an investigator but an interrogator, in accordance with the Charter and Service Guide of the Duty faction!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_10">
		<text>Well then, what the hell does Duty want from me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_11">
		<text>You tried to rob our field arsenal full of equipment that our soldiers prepared for a raid! Who gave you the coordinates of the stash? Answer me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_12">
		<text>Do you call that a stash?! It was just a box in the very foreground!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_13">
		<text>Don't try to teach us, how to operate in the Zone... I'll ask you once again: Who told you about the location of our field arsenal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_14">
		<text>I'm telling you: I stumbled upon it by chance, believe it or not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_15">
		<text>Of course I believe you! And you must also add: "I am a stalker, I like to hang around different back streets and crawl into all dirty places"... Stop lying! We learned about your plans to rob our arsenal in ADVANCE. I advise you not to deny it, or it's going to hurt!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_16">
		<text>"Learned" from whom? What kind of nonsense is this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_17">
		<text>I'm getting bored with this conversation. I'll give you one last chance: tell me who pointed it to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_18">
		<text>What are you talking about? This is some sort of set-up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_19">
		<text>I've had enough! According to the Charter of the Duty group, namely section 25 "Code for maintaining law and order in the Zone"; in the name of the law, I sentence you to death for the theft of assets of strategic importance, belonging to Duty. The sentence is to be carried out immediately. I will personally supervise the execution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_20">
		<text>What kind of bullshit is this?!.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_21">
		<text>I'm not going to chew this for another half an hour! Stop wasting my time and quickly answer my questions!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_22">
		<text>What happened, Major? I don't remember anything, my head is pounding...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_23">
		<text>Good acting, you fucking spy! Answer me, why did you try to clean out our stash?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_24">
		<text>I'm telling you, I didn't know that it was yours! I stumbled upon a box and just looked in...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_25">
		<text>"...out of pure curiosity?" Don't lie, you bastard! You heard the message from our checkpoint! Who sent you, answer me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_26">
		<text>Nobody! I wander the Zone alone, collect artifacts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_27">
		<text>Yeah, for sure! I know this tale: "I'm an honest loner; I'm just a golden haired boy!" Don't anger me, it will make things worse for you! Keep in mind that we were told in advance that you planned to plunder our property from the arsenal! I'll give you one last chance: either you answer who told you about our operational arsenal, or be sentenced to death!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_28">
		<text>Wait a minute, I need to remember... My head is ringing like a bell...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_29">
		<text>Yeah! This is another one of my favourite: "I probably have amnesia, first I need to get to a hospital"... You better remember soon, I'm getting impatient!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_30">
		<text>I remember! I came across a dead man on the path to the northern checkpoint. Suddenly, three bandits pounced on me! I took them out, and one of them had a PDA with the coordinates of your box. That's the way it was, I swear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_31">
		<text>What nonsense are you talking?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_32">
		<text>I'm telling the truth! Send some soldiers there, and let them report back what they find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_33">
		<text>Hmm... Actually, Nalivaiko reported this morning about some cusses in cloaks that were loitering near his outpost... That's how we act: we probably won't execute you this time, because I need to personally attend the execution, and I have a bursting hang-over after yesterday's celebrations...  Well, your weapons will be confiscated as a recompense for the theft, and you can get the hell out of here. You have five hours to do so. If you are still here after this period, I'll give the order to shoot you dead! Clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_34">
		<text>It couldn't be clearer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_35">
		<text>You've been arrested for robbing our group's field arsenal and disrupting an important campaign. Confess, who are you working for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_36">
		<text>What robbery? What campaign? I don't understand what you mean...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_37">
		<text>Here's a little bit of information! Did it upload correctly? Do you feel wiser now? Now do you begin to understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_38">
		<text>Shit! I don't work for anybody, I'm a loner...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_39">
		<text>Why have you robbed our cache, bitch? Speak, or I'll strangle you with my own hands!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_40">
		<text>Calm down, major! I'll tell you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_41">
		<text>Quickly, you have three minutes! I'm in a shitty mood today, so you better cut it short - I might not stand your presence longer than that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_42">
		<text>I didn't rob it! I just wanted to take a flash drive out of the box...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_43">
		<text>What kind of flash drive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_44">
		<text>A flash drive with a piece of a map... Whith directions to a Klondike of artifacts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_45">
		<text>Where did you get it from? Speak up, or I'll shoot you down! There are no witnesses around, I'll feed your remains to the mutants and no one will be any the wiser! Talk!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_46">
		<text>So much for Duty... I learned about the map which had been divided into five parts, from a wounded stalker at the Cordon. These parts were uploaded to five flash drives. This is one of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_47">
		<text>Don't badmouth Duty, you reptile! Yeah, interesting stuff happens under the very eyes. So, I need to think... Sit there and don't you even move! I'll be back soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_48">
		<text>Okay, whatever you say.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_49">
		<text>And give me the flash drive. It will be attached to the case as evidence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_50">
		<text>No way! I won't give it to you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_51">
		<text>Yes, of course, here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_52">
		<text>You bastard, don't you understand? Quickly, give me the flash drive, or you will die!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_sergant_dialog_1_phrase_53">
		<text>Here, choke on it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_12">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_11">
		<text>Well, that's all for now. Now stay seated for some time, while I take care of our patients and try to get them on their feet. Oh, Marked One - thank you very much. You helped me a lot, this artifact just had to be found. As a reward, you can keep the protective suit, it can prove useful to you. And here, take these artifacts - the sick stalkers gave them to us when they asked for our help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_10">
		<text>(roll up one sleeve)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_9">
		<text>I have a certain amount of SQ109 with me. It's generally an anti-TB drug, but it also shows great efficiency against this type of bacteria. Your infection has not developed fully yet, so we will treat you first - it will provide a better chance for success. Roll up your sleeve, Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_8">
		<text>What will you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_7">
		<text>The results match. Just as I thought. This artifact is a hotbed for an actively breeding methicillin-resistant staphylococcus aureus. This organism possesses resistance to almost all modern antibiotics. Here we have some new species that is very active. It infests quickly and causes a fulminant pneumonia.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_6">
		<text>Well, what is it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_5">
		<text>Excellent. Now I will take a swab from the artifact, apply it on a test strip and check everything... So, I see...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_4">
		<text>Here, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_3">
		<text>Well then, I'll just have to make three doses, one of them for you. Give me the container with the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_2">
		<text>I don't know, maybe. I am feeling a bit shitty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_1">
		<text>Remarkably, just in time... Oh, you don't look very well Marked One. Have you been infected?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_find_uley_dialog_0">
		<text>Doctor, I've found and brought the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_1_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Okay, I'll try. Apparently he couldn't have gone far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_happy_guys_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Glad to help, guys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_happy_guys_dialog_1">
		<text>Better, more or less. Thank you, Marked One, without you, we definitely would have died.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_happy_guys_dialog_0">
		<text>Well, how do you feel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Well, it seems he went to the Dark Valley. He was very pleased with himself, and was probably going to boast about his prize. Try to go there, judging by how quickly the guys started getting sick, this thug couldn't have gone too far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Damn, how will I find him now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>Shit, so it's because of that... Now I understand, how it happened... We were on our way to the Bar with a bag of artifacts. Near the entrance, Vasya Katchalov, a local criminal, bailed us up and wouldn't let us through. I'm not really a fighter, and the guys were already unable to even lift up their arms. In short, I gave him this artifact so he would leave us alone. Bloody hell, he's probably dead by now, if this artifact was the source of the disease. Serves him right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_1_1">
		<text>Well, it looks like your guys got sick because of it. It carries a dangerous infection. Where is it now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_1">
		<text>What about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_uley_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, about that strange artifact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Is there really someone not afraid to visit us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Who are you? Why are you staying here and not in the Bar?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Why, aren't you aware? I thought, everybody at the Bar knew by now... These stalkers are sick. I want to warn you: they are struck down with an unknown infection, accordingly, there is no vaccine against it. If you value your life, you'd better vacate from here as soon as possible so as to avoid getting infected!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Thank you for your concern. Aren't you afraid of getting infected yourself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Oh, my! Got it, just leaving!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I'm a scientist. The life of the scientist doesn't belong to him, it belongs to science... I specialize in microbiology, I study the framework of the mutations of viruses and bacteria under the influence of anomalous fields and intense radioactive exposure in the Zone. These stalkers are a unique case, they must be studied. In addition, I may also be able to help them. Well, the scientific importance of an accurate observation of the course of the disease and the description of the symptoms cannot be underestimated! Of course, Dr.Gorbovsky was more deeply involved in the study of this disease, I was his assistant only... And frankly, I just don't know what to do now! Without the doctor, I doubt my ability to finish the studies or cure these two patients.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Where is Dr.Gorbovsky?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Oh, a terrible thing happened to him! Imagine that, he was kidnapped by mercenaries! Perhaps they confused him for Professor Sakharov, because there are some similarities between them... The doctor was abducted three days ago, and a ransom note was sent. The amount asked by the kidnappers, is so huge! So... I don't know what to do. Had he not been kidnapped, he most certainly would have managed to create a cure for this disease.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Why didn't you seek help from Duty, for example?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Because I wasn't allowed through the Duty outpost! They were afraid that I had been infected by my patients. If not for me, these poor creatures would have been shot long ago! These poor men are in a terrible state, they rave about a Klondike of artifacts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>I think that I should deal with these mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>I doubt very much that there is something you can do. They looked like a team of well trained professionals.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Just give me their coordinates, and I'll take a look. Maybe I'll come up with something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>But you can't cope with them alone! Perhaps, you should ask for help! The mercenaries are in the Darkscape. At least, that's where the ransom was to be delivered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>Clear. Another question: How much time do I have?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>I think that the patients will last out another 2 days at best. But in any case - good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_start_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>Thank you. Take care of yourself!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I'm not contagious, don't shoot me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_7_1">
		<text>Why are you sitting there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Why are you so confident that you're not sick?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>I was at the Garbage together with Falcon and Tikhon! They're just about to kick the bucket, but I feel fine. The doctor looks after them, and I get food for them from the Bar and drive the dogs away. Hopefully, the guys will manage to recover.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Tell me, what exactly happened there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>They found some hole in one of the garbage heaps and made a cache there a few months ago. A couple of weeks ago I asked to join them and they allowed me to accompany them. I had to climb in that hole and back out with a bag of artifacts - there was even a rare one, I never even heard of! And then, as we almost got back to the Bar, the guys began to get sick. I practically had to drag them the last few metres. I thought, they would receive some proper medical treatment here, but instead...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>When Dutiers at the outpost saw them, coughing and spitting with blood, they took aim at us and ordered us to leave. "Don't bring your diseases here!" - they said. Well, it was pure luck that someone noticed all that and called the doctor, otherwise we'd be doomed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgoy_pomoshnik_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Interesting story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I beg you, just keep quiet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>What's the matter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Shush! Quiet, please!... Otherwise, it will hear us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>What? Why don't you go back to Malyshev instead of sitting here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>I was on my way to the poor sick fellows, but some animal picked up my scent! I decided to hide here and wait - maybe it will go away finally?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Hardly. Well, I'll make it "go away".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_second_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Doctor, I took care of the bloodsucker. Can we go now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_second_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>So, it was a bloodsucker? I'll make sure to make a record in my diary about the peculiar sounds these creatures emit while hunting... Yes, of course! Let's go to the sick right now! I hope they are still alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_second_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>You almost got eaten, and you talk about "peculiar sounds"!.. Okay, let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_second_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Well, how are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_second_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Excellent! Well, now that the doctor is here again, we definitely will be able to find a vaccine and to overcome the disease! This is extremely important! Just think, what would happen in the long term if it broke out of the Zone? A search for a vaccine is a matter of life and death for all mankind! And I am so glad that you rescued the doctor!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_second_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Thank you. I'm happy to help!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_third_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Well, haw are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_third_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Where have you been?.. The unfortunate wretches died in agony. Now it's too late. It's most likely that the cure for the disease will never be found now! To think, that the disease may break out of the Zone! You have no idea what a threat it is to all the mankind!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_lider_third_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Sorry for the poor fellows. Hopefully this disease... will not spread.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Doctor, what is your diagnosis?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Um, well... I think it makes sense to share some thoughts with you. First of all, I want to note that, on the basis of my observations, we can conclude that the infection is not transmitted from person to person. It's not airborne, at least. That is, we have practically nothing to fear. I found this out before I was kidnapped by the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Then why such a fuss?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>You see, this doesn't make the situation less critical. I have every reason to believe that the first victim came in contact with a certain anomalous body, which was an artifact or something like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>What prompted you to come to this conclusion?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I spoke to their assistant - the rookie, who protects us. What he said, confirmed my long-standing suspicion of the existence of an "artifact-hive". For your understanding, we are dealing with an artifact that serves as an incubator and, consequently, a breeding ground for harmful micro organisms that are likely to mutate and are capable of causing a certain number of dangerous diseases to humans. A long time ago, I put forward a theory of the existence of such an artifact, based on the analysis of various artifacts that impact on the development of strains of some diseases known to science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Wow, an artifact! Hopefully, if it exists, it's the only one!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>I hope so, too. Actually, it's indirectly evidenced by the absence of reported epidemics among stalkers; dysentery doesn't count. However, my information needs to be checked. This is what I'm getting at: To definitively prove my theory, I need to find the artifact, and study it. Are you ready to go on a quest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>But what about the patients, what will happen to them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Don't worry, I have drugs that hinder the development of the disease. However, we can only manufacture the vaccine if we have this "Hive" artifact, do you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>Let me think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>I am ready to go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Great, Marked One! Then start by talking to the man that dragged those guys here. He must know where to find this artifact - they came here without it already. He mentioned something about a criminal at the Garbage, try to find out where to look for him. You'll also need a protective suit and a special container. As soon as you find the artifact, place it in the container immediately and bring it to me. I will have everything ready to research it. But don't try to handle the artifact without a protective suit, Marked One! It will most certainly end badly for you. Be sure to wear the suit before you pick the "Hive" up. And don't remove the suit until you bring me the artifact, I'm not quite sure of the integrity of the container.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izgioy_doctor_third_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Okay, I understand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_1">
		<text>Are you having any problems?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_2">
		<text>Apart from you, none.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_3">
		<text>Stop joking... I'm serious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_4">
		<text>You see that safe in the corner? I've lost the combination for it. During my last inventory I found a piece of paper with what seemed the combination for the safe, but my batman, that drunken beast, lost my briefcase with this piece of paper. Seems like he lost it not far from here, in the hangar at the entrance to our base, but everyone is too afraid to search for it. The hangar doors are locked, it has to be entered through the roof. Can you open the safe? I'll owe you one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_5">
		<text>Any ideas what the combination could be?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_6">
		<text>None at all. I tried to use 1,2,3, but that didn't work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_7">
		<text>What a surprise... Is there anything valueable inside?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_8">
		<text>I don't remember. I need it to store weapons and ammunition. So, will you try to help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_9">
		<text>I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog1_phrase_10">
		<text>Nope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_1">
		<text>The safe is open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_2">
		<text>Well done! The combination, what was it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_3">
		<text>4,3,2. It's very tricky, for sure, but you'd better change it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_4">
		<text>I'll change it, of course. What was in there? If you're honest, you'll get a good reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_5">
		<text>Nothing, it was empty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_6">
		<text>Well, some junk, some stalker's gear for dummies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_7">
		<text>Okay, to hell with it. Here's a reward - it's not much, but:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_8">
		<text>Yeah, it's real junk. Okay, hand it over. You can keep the book, it's of no use to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_9">
		<text>Wait, what about the reward?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_10">
		<text>Here, take it:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_11">
		<text>Colonel, do you need the briefcase?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_12">
		<text>Are you kidding? You've found it? Give it here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_13">
		<text>Let's do this way: I'll give you the case in exchange for five "grand".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_14">
		<text>Another damn "businessman". Alright, here's your five "grand".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_15">
		<text>Here you go, I don't mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_seif_dialog2_phrase_16">
		<text>You're a good man, Marked One. Here, take a few grenades, they'll come in handy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Your men just stripped me of everything and threw me in the jail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Who exactly are you accusing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Major Zhivoderov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Ah, you know him... Very intelligent fellow. Neither he nor any of his men would beat you. Anyway, he has reported everything to me during the routine meeting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>But I wasn't going to steal anything! Something of mine was in that box!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Well, who do you think I should believe: the son of a colleague, whom I've known from our childhood, or you? We'll do it this way. If you really want your confiscated goods returned, I'll give you a chance to prove that they are really yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>I don't need to prove to Duty, what is, or isn't mine...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Well, do you want to get your stuff back or don't you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Of course I do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Then listen carefully to what I have to say. The fact is, this area itself is neutral territory. Anyone who calls himself a stalker can come here and trade. Except for the most obvious thugs, of course, for whom there's a reward on their heads. And except for Freedom, obviously... So, there is a problem. A bandit named Caligula has appeared in the Zone recently. At first he traded the little trifle he stole from rookies at the Cordon, and then he decided to pull in the "big fish". He hammered together a gang and started to attack our squads. He'd grab their equipment and loot and the prisoners were sometimes tortured, but more often, they'd be shot. We started to hunt for him and killed all his accomplices, but we never got Caligula himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>You didn't have enough men?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>Don't interrupt me! In short, it's not so simple dealing with this skinhead. The fact is, Caligula has the nerve to come here, to the Bar, drink here and even sell goods stolen from our soldiers!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>How can this happen?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Very simple: Barkeep has some secret agreement with him. We can't just arrest the bandit while he's in the Bar - that would quarrel us with Barkeep. He would survive without us, his main clients are stalkers with artifacts, but we need him more than he needs us... In general, this Caligula is really ruining our lives, and even mocking us. You have to kill him, Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>So General, you have decided to make me your proxy. What if Barkeep gets wind of the deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>He won't. You have to arrange everything as if it were your own doing, you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>Not really...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_18">
		<text>You need to somehow offend or insult this Caligula, so he'll challenge you to showdown. Shooting in the Bar is strictly forbidden, therefore you'll have to deal with him in the Arena. That's where you can safely kill him. Nobody will suspect anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_19">
		<text>Okay. Where can I find Caligula?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_20">
		<text>No, I won't do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_21">
		<text>He'll be in the 100 Rads Bar. Go and do it. If the bandit dies - you get your things back safely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_22">
		<text>Where did you get the idea, watching Mad Max movies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_23">
		<text>No, why do you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_dialog_phrase_24">
		<text>The story is similar... Okay, here goes nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>And who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Oh, just looking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>I know your face from somewhere...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>So, get the fuck out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>What did you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I just remembered, you're the local Gigolo named Vaska Slutsky, the Zone's finest... Well, piss off, your place is in the brothel!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Oh you bitch, you're dead meat! Right, let's go to the Arena now, and sort this out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Come on, I'll pluck out your feathers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Choose, scumbag, which weapon do you want to use: pistols or sawn-off shotguns?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Pistols.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>Knives.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kaligula_start_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>Sawn-off shotguns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>What now, general? Caligula is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Stalker, I'm very grateful, but listen...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Let me guess: my things are gone as payment for their storage?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Nothing is gone anywhere, just wait...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Did Barkeep find out about our affairs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>No. Zhivoderov got into trouble! He has your stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>What happened to him? To clarify: I'm only interested because he has my stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Got deep into some shit. My soldiers are trying to pull him out, but to no avail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Just like in that fairy tale, "The Giant Turnip"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>Consider this, Zhivoderov is the only one who knows the location of your items. And if you save the major, you'll also get a reward from me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>I'll help him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>To hell with your major.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Well, I see that you're a real man! His batman reported to me that the major had found something dangerous in the old cracked tower, right across from our base. He's been trapped in there as if inside an anomaly. Help him, stalker, he's very valuable to me! My soldiers have been there, but for some reason, they can do nothing. Go to him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_kaligula_reward_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Well, as you wish, stalker...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>You're from the General, aren't you?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Yes, what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Here's the problem: the Major entered this fucking tower, but now he can't get out. I've called and called him, and he doesn't come. Then private Brill went in after him but never returned. I went in after Brill, but he was not breathing by the time I approached him. If we can't rescue the Major, the General will tear off my skin. Be a man - help me save the Major.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>If the private is dead, what makes you think that the Major is still alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Listen. You can hear moans coming from the top of the tower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Did you try wearing a suit with psy-protection?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>I tried, but the stupid suit failed, it doesn't work!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>Fuck knows what to do now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_1">
		<text>And who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_2">
		<text>I'm the one who knows how to get the Duty soldier out of the tower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_3">
		<text>You do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_4">
		<text>Believe me, I also know why that dickhead happened to be there. The bastard tried to rummage through my stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_5">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_6">
		<text>I returned to the Bar from Yantar to guzzle the money from the proceeds of my loot. Then this Zhivoderov, drunk as a lord, came up to me and said, that as long as he and his men were guarding me from the bandits, so I was to pay him for. I asked if he would take my loot as payment. When he agreed I then told him about my cache on the top tier of the tower. In there, I hid a single unknown artifact, and something else. The scientists at Yantar hadn't got interested in that artifact as it had no properties, but I figured that before the Major worked out what's what, I'd be long gone from the Bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_7">
		<text>Zhivoderov fell for it. So what happened then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_8">
		<text>He climbed the tower and left his men on lookout. Then they tried to pull him out, but failed. And then you came along... Were you instructed to save him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_9">
		<text>Yes. You said that you know how to do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_10">
		<text>It's necessary to disable the scientific device that he took out of my cache. You see, in addition to the artifact, I also hid some device there, that I had stolen from the scientists. Don't you look at me that way! They can order a new one for themselves, no problem, and I'll have just enough for of a pack of smokes... Win-win, so to say. So, I didn't touch the device, I just put it in there. Apparently, the Major rummaged through my cache for the artifact and came across the device and switched it on out of curiosity. And now it's affecting his brain. It's necessary to turn that device off, then the field will be gone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_11">
		<text>Why is the Major still alive, and his assistant has died?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_12">
		<text>Fuck knows, maybe because every brain is different. My stalker instinct suggests that this artifact he took from my cache, is somehow protecting him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_13">
		<text>Maybe. What do you advise?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_14">
		<text>Just switch off the device, damn it! Nothing else I can think of. Although... I have an idea. While I was at the Cordon, my friend Tolik gave me a bottle of the locally brewed moonshine. He said they called it "Kordonovsky". This bastard packs a punch - it will really numb your brain! So I'm thinking: fight fire with fire, as they say. Drink it and rush to the device. The main thing is to stall for time, before your brain begins to boil. What do you think? Will you try?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_15">
		<text>I don't drink!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog1_phrase_16">
		<text>Come on, it can't hurt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_wounded_help_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>H-help me! Turn it off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_wounded_help_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Wait a second!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_1">
		<text>Look, how do I turn off this damn device?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_2">
		<text>I wish I knew. There was a manual with it, but the instructions were so complicated that I used the pages for cigarette papers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_3">
		<text>Well, you blockhead! How am I going to turn it off then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_4">
		<text>Wait, calm down. Before I used it all up, I did read something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_5">
		<text>Tell me, what did you understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_6">
		<text>Although I'm not an electrician, I did realize something. The manual mentioned something about an overload: it said, to prevent it, a certain button must not be depressed, or the device will burn out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_7">
		<text>There're lots of buttons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_8">
		<text>This is what I remember: "...to reach the correct maximum load output it's necessary to press down the buttons alternately, so as to increase the power of the first phase first, then proceed to the second phase alternately pressing all the buttons, except the last one." So, if you click the last button, the damn thing will get overloaded.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_9">
		<text>Apparently, it's necessary to press the three side buttons in turn, and then click the lower left button, then go back and press all the three side buttons again?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_10">
		<text>Don't ask me that! I don't know, I never used the device! It's just what I've read...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tikar_dialog2_phrase_11">
		<text>If not for your greedy hands, this problem wouldn't have appeared. However, it's in my best interests to save that Dutier in the tower.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog1_phrase_1">
		<text>Listen, do you know how to turn off the unit in the tower?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog1_phrase_2">
		<text>Nah. Had I studied engineering in Kiev, as my parents wanted me to, maybe I could suggest something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog2_phrase_1">
		<text>The Major is safe, I shut down the device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog2_phrase_2">
		<text>Well, thank you, stalker! Listen... Can you tell the General that I helped a little, just a teeny bit, in saving the Major in the tower? He might give me a new weapon, or maybe, award me with a medal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_pomoshnik2_dialog2_phrase_3">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_goto_rest_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Any orders?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_goto_rest_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>What fucking orders, I have a splitting headache... Let's get out of here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_goto_rest_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I rescued your Major.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Stalker, you are a true man of honour! I understand your desire to get even with him. What he did to you was a personal insult. Now I know that you would not steal from Duty's caches - your actions speak of that. By the way, how did it go with Caligula?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>I guess I know why your soldiers couldn't overcome him. He possessed an artifact with strong protective properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>The way it was supposed to. He's dead and can't hurt anyone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Stalker, I ... I mean our group needs this artifact! We need to pass it on to the scientists, this will help them in the development of protective combat armour. Sell it to me. I'll give you a hundred thousand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Here's your reward then for everything you've done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>That's not enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Don't be arrogant, that's 10 times more than any rare artifact of any kind is worth!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>It has properties that make it worth more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>One hundred thousand and our top body armour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>No deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>A hundred thousand, our top suit and a machine gun with a hundred rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>That's quite another matter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>Don't take me for a sucker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>Agreed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voronin_aftertower_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>Well then, piss off out of here with that rock! I thought you were an honest man, but you're just a huckster.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_items_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I hope your head has cleared enough, so you can remember where you put my stuff?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_items_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Enough... Besides your belongings, take this artifact in gratitude:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="major_items_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<!--conversation with tail-->
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Greetings to you, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Are you Tail? Tell me, where do I find one of your friends - Kolya?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>What a smart-ass. And what is it you need from him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>I was asked by Chebu... Uh-uh, I owe him some money, I want to give it back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Ah, stalker, you can keep the money. I don't think you'll ever find Kolya.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Why's that? What happened to him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>He went to the north. Not to Freedom, but to undiscovered places. He was constantly tormented, and frequently had nightmares. He was always muttering about the creatures of the Zone, calling them astral beings, the quintessence of the human information field. Nonsense, in general. Poor guy... No one really understood him. Everyone thought he had gone crazy during one of his raids. But I saw that his mind was clear, though he really believed those things. That subject - we never talked about it. Then one day he packed up and left. He mentioned nothing to anyone, just whispered to me when parting: "I must find him, he will be THERE again, I know it."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Who was he looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>I don't know. Well, whoever it was, no one ever returned from those places.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>And where exactly was he going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>To the north, that's all I can say. Kolya was the only one from locals who had been there. There are legends about that place, it's called the Dead City. It's dangerous out there... Life is worth more than any artifact. Don't think about going there to look for him - you'll disappear as well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>Well, as you can see, I'm not a rookie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>No, you're not a rookie, but a fool. But why should I care? Go wherever you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Hmm, thank you for your encouraging words.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Hey, stalker, don't be offended. It's a bad idea to go there. But if you've made up your mind, it's your business then. If you happen to find Kolya and get back from there alive, please, be so kind as to let me know if he's alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_return_phrase_1">
		<text>I found Kolya.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_return_phrase_2">
		<text>Judging by the expression on your face, I fear for the worst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_return_phrase_3">
		<text>Yes, he got killed in the Dead City.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_return_phrase_4">
		<text>So, that's where he went alone. Yes, he liked to take risks. Well, God rest his soul... Did he find what he was looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_return_phrase_5">
		<text>I doubt it. I found nothing unusual on him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hvost_dialog_return_phrase_6">
		<text>It's a pity. Well, stalker, thank you for coming. Kolya left a little money with me to look after. He no longer needs it, so you can have it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_talked_about_new_weapons_1">
		<text>How are the valiant soldiers of the Zone doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="petr_talked_about_new_weapons_2">
		<text>Well, just well... We received an order from the mainland to test an all-purpose weapon. Supposedly, "to fine tune this universal tactical machine of the future to operate under simulated combat conditions." They're bent. What will they use as a simulation - shooting of wild boars at the military post or something? In such cases a good old AK-74 will suffice. However, I have an order - so I must obey. The guns look quite interesting. Like a normal AK, but it has so many features, that it will blow your mind. Just the sights alone. The boxes of equipment we got - loads of them! As for me - well, as usually, I keep selling gear to stalkers. I promote, so to speak, unification, he-he. Why don't you take one, and then, in the blink of an eye, you will have a new AK to go. If you hesitate, soon enough you might find yourself being ridiculed for using that dated weapon of yours.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

