<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_fmj_short">
		<text>.45 ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_fmj_descr">
		<text>.45 ACP - Automatic Colt Pistol, 11.43x23mm. This cartridge boasts a heavy steel bullet with a lead core, as well as a relatively weak powder charge. This combination resulted in pretty low flight velocity, but it's balanced out by good accuracy and sufficient stopping power.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_hydro">
		<text>.45 ACP Hydra-Shok rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_hydro_short">
		<text>.45 Hydra</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_hydro_descr">
		<text>.45 ACP "Hydra-Shok" - This variant of the .45 ACP ammunition sports a jacketed hollow point bullet with a flat tip. This cartridge offers good stopping power due to reliable expansion and deeper penetration of organic tissues.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.7x28">
		<text>5.7x28mm FN SS190 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.7x28_short">
		<text>5.7x28mm FN SS190</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.7x28_descr">
		<text>The 5.7x28mm round was developed by Belgian company Fabrique Nationale de Herstal (FN Herstal) specifically for the FN P90 submachine gun in the mid-1980s. Later on, this round was used in "Five SeveN" pistol. This round has higher penetration power than other pistol rounds. The bullet has a muzzle velocity of up to 716 m/s, and it's capable of piercing through bulletproof vests. If you compare 5.7x28mm to 9x19mm in terms of stopping power, 5.7x28mm has significantly more stopping power.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_buck">
		<text>12ga. Buckshot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_buck_short">
		<text>12ga. Buck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_buck_descr">
		<text>12 gauge buckshot - A standard shotgun shell filled with 6mm lead pellets. It has great stopping power at close range. It's most effective at ranges under 30 meters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_zhekan">
		<text>12ga. Slug rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_zhekan_short">
		<text>12ga. Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_zhekan_descr">
		<text>12 gauge slug - A round composed of a single, large lead projectile inside a shotgun shell. It's intended for big game hunting, but that doesn't stop anyone for using it on something else. The projectile itself does not pierce, but actually forces itself through bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_ap">
		<text>5.45x39mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_ap_short">
		<text>5.45x39mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_ap_descr">
		<text>5.45x39mm low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge with an armor-piercing bullet (7N22), designed to penetrate advanced body armor and light vehicles. The bullet can penetrate a 6mm-thick armor plate (standard for modern body armor) at up to 250 meters with 80% reliability. The bullet is lacquer-coated and has a black tip.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_fmj">
		<text>5.45x39mm EPR rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_fmj_short">
		<text>5.45x39mm EPR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_fmj_descr">
		<text>5.45x39mm low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge. The small-caliber bullet provides a flatter trajectory, increasing its effective range. The round's disadvantages include lower blunt stopping power (although the bullet has a great tendency to yaw), and its tendency to ricochet. 5.45x39mm EPR (7N10) denotes enhanced penetration, with a heat-treated steel core. Standard in the Russian and Ukrainian armies since 1992, replacing the 7N6 and 7N6M. The bullet is lacquer-coated and has no distinctive color.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_ap">
		<text>5.56x45mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_ap_short">
		<text>5.56x45mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_ap_descr">
		<text>5.56x45mm NATO low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge with a armour piercing bullet, was designed to penetrate advanced body armor and light vehicles.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_fmj">
		<text>5.56x45mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_fmj_short">
		<text>5.56x45mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_fmj_descr">
		<text>5.56x45mm/.223 Rem low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge with a full-metal jacket (FMJ). Based on the .223 Remington hunting cartridge, the SS109 bullet, designed by Fabrique Nationale in Belgium, was adopted by NATO in the mid-1980s under index STANAG 4172.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_fmj">
		<text>7.62x39mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_fmj_short">
		<text>7.62x39mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_fmj_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x39mm intermediate rifle cartridge was designed by N.M. Elizarov and B.V. Semin in 1943. The cartridge is known coloquially as the M43, and sometimes called ".30 Short Russian" in the US. 7.62 FMJ (57-N-231) denotes a bullet with a heat-treated steel core. The round can punch through a steel helmet at up to 900 meters and pierce standard body armor at up to 600 meters. At 100 meters, the round can destroy 12-15cm-thick brick wall. The bullet has no distinctive color.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_ap">
		<text>7.62x39mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_ap_short">
		<text>7.62x39mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_ap_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x39mm intermediate round with an armor-piercing bullet (7N23). Developed in the late 1990s by D.I. Veronskiy and V.V. Zakharyaschev, and adopted by the Russian military in 2002. This new round has over three times the penetrative power of the FMJ round, while retaining the FMJ round's trajectory. It can penetrate a Russian 6B5 vest at up to 250 meters. At 100 meters, the round can destroy 12-15cm-thick brick wall. The bullet has a black tip for identification.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h1">
		<text>7.62х54mmR 7N1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h1_short">
		<text>7.62х54mmR 7N1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h1_descr">
		<text>7.62х54mmR rifle cartridge was developed in 1891 as a munition for the Mosin rifle. After modernization in 1930 the cartridge received the M1908/30 designation. When the SVD was developed the cartridge was modernized to improve accuracy and power at which it was designated 7N1. Full-metal jacket with no specific coloring.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h14">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N14 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h14_short">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h14_descr">
		<text>7.62х54mmR 7N14 armor-piercing sniper rifle cartridge. In 1990 there was a modernization program for 7.62x54mmR cartridges. One of the goals was to improve piercing ability for bullet. 7N14 sniper rifle cartridge has improved piercing ability and accuracy.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_ap">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N13 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_ap_short">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_ap_descr">
		<text>7.62x54mmR AP round. These 7.62x54mmR rounds are mainly meant for machine gun use. While they are not sniper rounds, they can be readily loaded into Dragunov rifles.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_fmj">
		<text>9х18mm PM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_fmj_short">
		<text>9х18mm PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_fmj_descr">
		<text>9х18mm PM - Simple full metal jacket bullet with a steel core. Weak armor penetration. Probably the most widespread type of ammunition in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_pmm">
		<text>9x18mm PMM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_pmm_short">
		<text>9x18mm PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_pmm_descr">
		<text>9x18mm PMM - The Russian military was looking to extend the life of the standard Soviet 9x18mm pistol round, which resulted in creation of the PMM variant. It boasts enhanced ballistic parameters. Due to higher muzzle velocity and use of a steel core, it's much more efficient than the standard cartridge. The armor penetration capabilities have been hugely improved.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_fmj">
		<text>9x19mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_fmj_short">
		<text>9x19mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_fmj_descr">
		<text>9x19mm FMJ - A standard issue cartridge in use by NATO forces. The cartridge itself is a standard full metal jacket bullet. Weak armor penetration.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_pbp">
		<text>9x19mm HP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_pbp_short">
		<text>9x19mm HP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_pbp_descr">
		<text>9x19mm Hollow-Point - This round boasts a copper bullet with a lead core which flattens itself on impact, resulting in frightening wounds. Frivolous use of such ammunition often results in the barrel getting clogged up with lead due to the fact that the HP rounds have a softer tip, which is often a cause of many misfires. The bullet flight trajectory has also been negatively affected and armor penetration remains pretty weak.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_ap">
		<text>9x39mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_ap_short">
		<text>9x39mm SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_ap_descr">
		<text>9х39mm SP-6 - Armor-piercing variant of the Russian subsonic rifle round. The heavy bullet produces no supersonic shockwave during flight, making it noiseless. The SP-6 round can penetrate body armor up to 350 meters away.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_pab9">
		<text>9x39mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_pab9_short">
		<text>9x39mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_pab9_descr">
		<text>The subsonic SP-5 round is comprised of a bullet with an bimetallic shell. The cavity behind the bullet's steel core is filled with lead. SP-5 rounds require the use of a silencer to ensure silent firing. These are distributed in some former Warsaw Pact countries for use by special forces.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_gauss">
		<text>2x10mm M62 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_gauss">
		<text>2x10mm M62</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_gauss_descr">
		<text>2x10mm M62 - Custom projectiles for the Project 62 Gauss rifle. A ferromagnetic projectile composed of tungsten with a relatively small size that is accelerated to a high velocity when fired.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m209">
		<text>40mm M406 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m209_short">
		<text>40mm M406</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m209_descr">
		<text>40mm M406 grenade - A high-explosive grenade for the AG36, M203, and L123A2 UGL grenade launchers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m397a1">
		<text>40mm M397A1 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m397a1_short">
		<text>40mm M397A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m397a1_descr">
		<text>40mm M397A1 grenade - An improved variant of the 40mm grenade that can be used by the AG36, M203, and L123A2 UGL grenade launchers. It has better aerodynamics, allowing it to hit enemies behind cover more accurately.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_og_7b">
		<text>PG-7VL rocket-propelled grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_og_7b_short">
		<text>PG-7VL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_og_7b_descr">
		<text>The PG-7VL rocket-propelled grenade is the standard anti-tank warhead used by the RPG-7V. It's terrifyingly effective against hostile mutants, stalkers, or soldiers. These have far more reach than hand grenades, allowing you to blow up enemies from a considerable distance.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25">
		<text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25_short">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25_descr">
		<text>40mm VOG-25 grenade - A fragmentation grenade used by the GP-25 grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25p">
		<text>VOG-25P grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25p_short">
		<text>VOG-25P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25p_descr">
		<text>40mm VOG-25P bounding grenade - A improved variant of the VOG-25 grenade used by the GP-25 grenade launcher. Prior to explosion, the grenade leaps up about one meter into the air, increasing the damage it does.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="ammo-m208a">
		<text>40mm M208A HEAB grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m208a_s">
		<text>40mm M208A HEAB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m208a">
		<text>40mm M208A HEAB grenade - A high-explosive fragmentation grenade that has an remote detonation built into it. These higher-end grenades are meant for rifles equipped with grenade launchers that have electronic targeting systems, such as the XM8 rifle or the FN2000 rifle, although 40mm grenade launchers that don't have the electronic targeting system (such as the AG36, the M203, and the L123A2 UGL) can still use these. With enough practice, it's possible to take down aerial targets.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ammo_atom">
		<text>40mm ATOM grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_atom_s">
		<text>40mm ATOM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-atom">
		<text>40mm ATOM grenade - A nuclear charge packed into a standard 40mm grenade, compatible with most western grenade launchers. Nobody knows who produces this type of ammunition, let alone where. No one knows how Monolith soldiers managed to get their hands on these grenades.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Ammo">
		<text>Ammunition type</text>
	</string>
    <string id="fuelcan">
		<text>Gas bottle</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bomba">
		<text>Fuel bomb</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bochka">
		<text>Fuel tank</text>
	</string>
    <string id="kanistra">
		<text>Gasoline canister</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_kanistra">
		<text>A gasoline canister, used to fuel vehicles. It may also be used as a crude sort of bomb, placing it in position and detonating it with gunfire.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="dinamito">
		<text>Crate of dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_explosive_bomba">
		<text>A wonderful tool to use when you want to get rid of your enemies from a distance. Shooting this thing will bring pain and destruction to everything and everyone within 8 meters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_f1">
		<text>F-1 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_f1_descr">
		<text>Common anti-personnel frag grenade, coloquially referred to as "limonka". Still used by the Russian Army since the Great Patriotic War. Those who haven't been hit by the explosion itself are going suffer from shrapnel-induced damage. Toss only from from behind cover.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgd5">
		<text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgd5_descr">
		<text>An offensive hand grenade with a small radius of splinter damage. The grenade's designation is shorthand for Ruchnaya Granata Distantsionnaya, or 'Hand Grenade Remote'.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgn">
		<text>RGN grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgn_descr">
		<text>The RGN (Ruchnaya Granata Nastupatel'naya, or 'Hand Grenade Offensive') grenade is meant to flush out or kill enemy soldiers, detonating instantly if it hits a surface hard enough. Its lethal radius is about 4 to 10 meters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgo">
		<text>RGO grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgo_descr">
		<text>The RGO (Ruchnaya Granata Oboronitel'naya, or 'Hand Grenade Defensive') grenade is a regular hand grenade, although it does have the same impact fuse that the RGN grenade has.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_smoke">
		<text>RDG-M smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_smoke_descr">
		<text>A hand-thrown smoke grenade. Smoke grenades are useful for creating visual cover, making it harder any hostiles to see you. It takes about 10 seconds for the smoke screen to fully form after the fuse goes off.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_flashbang">
		<text>CTS 7290 flashbang grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_flashbang_descr">
		<text>A flashbang grenade made in the USA. It's designed to temporarily incapacitate hostiles by overwhelming anyone who is caught in the blast radius with noise and light.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Misc -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_knife">
		<text>OTs-04 combat knife</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_montirovka">
		<text>Crowbar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_montirovka_short">
		<text>Crowbar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_montirovka_descr">
		<text>Simple heavy crowbar which used to belong to a foreigner called "Freeman". The handle is stamped - "Manufactured in Black Mesa, New Mexico, USA"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pipe">
		<text>Lead pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pipe_short">
		<text>Lead pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pipe_descr">
		<text>Probably the most common thing you'd expect to find in the Zone. If you use it properly, you might even be able to bash someone's skull in.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Pistols -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pm">
		<text>Makarov PM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pm_descr">
		<text>Standard sidearm of the Ukrainian military, in service since 1951. It doesn't offer much stopping power or accuracy, but its small size allows you to keep it hidden in your jacket without any problems, but there's nothing you can hope for in a real battle, although its reliability and ease of use and maintenance remains unrivaled.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pmm">
		<text>Honorary PMM-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pmm_descr">
		<text>The PMM-12 (GRAU index 56-A-125M) is a modernized variant of the Makarov PM, developed in early 1990s. 70% of the PMM's parts are interchangeable with the original Makarov PM. The PMM's barrel frame is reinforced, and bolt's mass has been increased. Additionally, spiral grooves have been etched into the barrel, which gives the PMM better accuracy and allows it to use 9x18mm high velocit rounds in addition to conventional 9x18mm rounds. There's an engraving on the pistol that reads: "Succesful execution of highly dangerous state orders, as well as valor and courage shown in the line of duty."</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pb">
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pb_descr">
		<text>A pistol based on the Makarov PM using an integrated 2-part suppressor. It was built for military reconnaisance units and KGB personnel. Nowadays obsolete, but still very dangerous in the hands of a skilled soldier.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort12">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort12_descr">
		<text>The standard sidearm of the Ukrainian military. Its ergonomics are a vast improvement over the Makarov PM, as well as its accuracy, recoil and rate of fire. It's also noticeably larger and heavier.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort17">
		<text>Fort-17</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort17_descr">
		<text>The Fort-17 is an improved version of the Fort-12 pistol. Its numerous improvements include a polymer frame made of fiberglass reinforced with impact-resistant polymide, and a picatinny rail for mounting lights or laser pointers. Thanks to being largely made out of military-grade polymers instead of metal, the Fort-17 is much less expensive to produce than the Fort-12, and also much lighter.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gsh18">
		<text>GSh-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gsh18_descr">
		<text>The GSh-18 pistol was developed in the late 1990s by Vasily P. Gryazev and Arkady G. Shipunov, both working for the Tula Instrument Design Bureau. It has a fairly low weight, a large magazine capacity of 18 rounds, a low profile barrel and good accuracy.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grach">
		<text>MP-443 Grach</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grach_descr">
		<text>The MP-443 pistol, which was first presented in 1993 at a state-sponsored competition to replace the Makarov PM pistol that was in service but not fully compliant with modern requirements, became the winner 7 years later in 2000 after many design revisions, and was named MP-443 'Grach'. It was officially adopted by the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation in 2003. On October 9th, 2008, the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs announced the changeover from the Makarov PM to the MP-443 Grach as their standard sidearm. In 2011, mass production of the MP-443 was launched for the Russian army.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_stechkin">
		<text>Stechkin APS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_stechkin_descr">
		<text>The Stechkin automatic pistol (APS) was developed somewhere in between the 1940s and 1950s by Igor Yakovlevich Stechkin and was adopted by the Soviet Army in 1951. The pistol was intented to be a personal defense weapon for soldiers and officers who didn't need to rely on the Kalashnikov rifle or the SKS and regarded the Makarov pistol as garbage. In comparison with the Makarov, the APS curb-stomps it in almost every aspect - superior firepower, high rate of fire, bigger magazine and a longer barrel.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_apb">
		<text>Stechkin APB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_apb_descr">
		<text>The Stechkin APB is a suppressed version of the APS, originally designed to be used by Soviet Spetznas forces. It was officially adopted in 1972, 14 years after the production of its progenitor was discontinued. The only difference it has compared to the APS is a threaded barrel so that a suppressor can be attached.</text>
	</string>

        <string id="gunsl_wpn_tt33">
		<text>Tokarev TT-33</text>
	</string>
        <string id="gunsl_wpn_tt33_desc">
		<text>The TT-33 - Veteran of the Great Patriotic War. In its day, the pistol used to be considered a perfect companion for a Red Army soldier thanks to its almost unrivaled reliability, as well as easy maintenance and repair. Its biggest problems were the tricky safety switch, inadequate stopping power of the light 7.62 cartridge and a rather uncomfortable grip.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sr1m">
		<text>SR1MP Gyurza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sr1m_descr">
		<text>The SR1MP Gyurza was designed from the ground-up for special forces, developed and designed by Petr I. Serdyukov while he was working for TsNIItochmash. The SR1MP variant is the latest version of the weapon, which has better ergonomics, picatinny rails on both the bottom and top for mounting laser pointers, sights or lights. Additionally, a threaded barrel was added so you can attached a silencer to the weapon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_beretta">
		<text>Beretta 92FS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_beretta_descr">
		<text>The Beretta 92FS is considered to be a fairly reliable but somewhat cumbersome pistol. The main target of criticism is its enormous grip which is only comfortable if you have very large hands, if you don't mind the gun itself being big enough.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_walther">
		<text>Walther P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_walther_descr">
		<text>A German-made pistol that has high reliability, a large magazine, good accuracy and excellent ergonomics. The P99 has become one of the most common pistols in the Zone for both professionals and beginners that afford can afford it.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_hpsa">
		<text>Browning Hi-Power</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_hpsa_descr">
		<text>The Browning Hi-Power pistol deserves to be considered as one of the best pistols of the 20th century, thanks to its reliability and great stopping power.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_glock17">
		<text>Glock 17</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_glock17_unic">
		<text>Modified Glock 17 </text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_glock17_descr">
		<text>The Glock 17 is a pistol developed by Glock for the Austrian army. It was the first weapon developed by Glock. The pistol proved to be quite successful and convenient to use. Due to its combat characteristics and reliability, it became widely used as a civilian self-defense weapon. The pistol design features no fuse or trigger flag. Most of the gun is made of highly durable, heat-resistant plastic. Thanks to this, Glock 17 is lightweight and extremely durable. The principle of Glock 17's operation is "snatch and fire" - however, there is no fuse, so the gun won't fire without fully depressing the dual safety trigger.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_colt1911">
		<text>Colt M1911A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_colt1911_descr">
		<text>The Colt 1911 is a true All-American masterpiece, which appeared in all the conflicts of the 20th century and entered the new century with confidence. Its small-size magazine is partially compensated by the use of a high-powered round which literally liberates the brains out of its targets.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220">
		<text>SIG Sauer P220</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220_descr">
		<text>The P220 is the only remaining variant of SIG's most popular pistol in mass production. The P220 is known for its excellent ergonomics and excellent accuracy. Its low magazine capacity is compensated by the powerful round it uses and its flawless reliability. It's no wonder that this pistol is in constant demand among experienced stalkers and mercenaries.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220_nimble">
		<text>SIG Sauer P220R</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220_nimble_descr">
		<text>A unique variant of the SIG Sauer P220 pistol. It was produced in small batches for a commission ordered by a special forces unit. The modifications done to this weapon include an larger magazine, an extra strong steel barrel, and a lightweight polymer cover for the barrel.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp">
		<text>HK USP Tactical</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp_descr">
		<text>A solid piece of quality German engineering - The USP, a compact pistol designed for close-quarters combat. It's pretty popular among hardened veterans of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp_match">
		<text>HK USP Match</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp_match_descr">
		<text>A variant of the USP designed for competitive shooting. The Match's distinctive feature is its unique recoil compensator, which helps to reduce muzzle climb. The USP Match was discontinued in 1999 and it's an extremely rare weapon, so you can only guess how it ended up in the Zone. This specific weapon was rumored to belong to a mercenary nicknamed Volkodav.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fiveseven">
		<text>FN Five-seveN USG</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fiveseven_descr">
		<text>The FN Five-seveN pistol is the companion for FN P90 submachine gun, designed and manufactured by the Belgian company Fabrique Nationale of Herstal. The 5.7x28mm rounds for the P90 was developed by FN in early nineties, and the Five-seveN came around in late nineties, using the same 5.7x28mm round. Since its introduction, it has been offered in various commercial versions, most recently as the Five-seveN USG. Its low weight, large magazine capacity, powerful rounds and reliability make the FN Five-seveN one of the best pistols.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_eagle">
		<text>Desert Eagle Mark XIX</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_eagle_descr">
		<text>A real gun for real heroes. It is big, heavy and powerful as all hell. It's not very popular in the Zone due to its price and size. After all, you don't go hunting for elephants every day.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_deagle_uniq">
		<text>Big Ben</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_deagle_uniq_descr">
		<text>A gun that is already powerful, reworked to fit 9x39mm bullets. Absolutely overkill for close-range combat. If you value your eardrums, don't fire this gun, ever. There's one question about it - how the hell did these bullets fit in? Looking closely at this gun, it becomes clear that the entire frame as well as the handle have been designed from scratch to sport a bigger magazine. Clearly the gunsmith who made this modified Desert Eagle was smoking some real good stuff.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Shotguns -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bm16">
		<text>TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bm16_descr">
		<text>Full-length TOZ-66 hunting shotgun with horizontal barrel alignment. Most of these have been sawn-off for the rookies, but some of these have been preserved in their original state and thus saved from the castration. The long barrels give this shotgun much-needed accuracy to deal efficiently with the target.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_toz34">
		<text>Sawn-off TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_toz34_descr">
		<text>You wanted a hunting shotgun? Here's your fucking hunting shotgun. You wanted an actual full-length hunting shotgun with a stock and long barrels? Fuck you. Hunting shotguns require a lot of skill, and that involves aiming. Can you aim? Hell no. Use a sawn-off shotgun, like this one. Its two shortened barrels can do miracles at close range, but the brutal recoil is gonna snap your wrists thrice the moment you pull the trigger.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300">
		<text>Winchester Model 1300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
		<text>Smoothbore pump-action shotgun of American origin, designed for use in demanding scenarios where reliability is of highest importance.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper">
		<text>Predator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper_descr">
		<text>A tailor-made pump-action shotgun which used to belong to a stalker named Trapper. The hunter's only requirement in respect of his weapon was that it needed to kill mutants in one shot. This philosophy was based on the belief that no matter how many people an animal had killed, it was still just an animal, and thus should not suffer.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12">
		<text>Franchi SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12_descr">
		<text>Smoothbore semi-automatic shotgun developed during the 70s in Italy, intended for use by police and military units. Its reliability and automatic fire mode are exceptionally admirable. On the other hand, it's quite heavy and expensive. Nonetheless, you're gonna have a hard time finding a better shotgun than that in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12_nimble">
		<text>Carabiner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12_nimble_descr">
		<text>An army shotgun designed specifically for assault units on the basis of the SPAS-12. Capable of automatic fire like its predecessor, but provides better recoil compensation thanks to a balanced shock free system.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_protecta">
		<text>Armsel Protecta</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_protecta_descr">
		<text>The Armsel Protecta is a fairly unique shotgun of South African origin. It's a smoothbore combat revolver-type shotgun intended to provide extreme firepower for militarized units. The weapon benefits from a large magazine and a high effective rate of fire, but its bulkiness and considerable weight, combined with a long reload time, are the price to be paid for these advantages. Rare in the Zone and is used primarily to clear closed spaces of mutants.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_saiga12">
		<text>Saiga 12K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_saiga12_unic">
		<text>Modified Saiga 12K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_saiga12_descr">
		<text>Semi-automatic 12 gauge shotgun built on the basis of the Kalashnikov rifle. The fact it's based off an AK makes it just as simple to use and reliable as one. Horrifyingly efficient in close quarters combat. Its removable magazine makes reloading quicker.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mr133">
    	<text>MR-133</text>
  	</string>
	
  	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mr133_descr">
		<text>The MR-133 is a Russian smoothbore shotgun, which is used for various types of hunting, sports shooting, security and self-defense. The shotgun was developed on the basis of the IZH-81 rifle and has been mass-produced by the Izhevsk Mechanical Plant since 2000.</text>
  	</string>

<!-- Sniper -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez">
		<text>VSS Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_tact">
		<text>Modified VSS Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_descr">
		<text>Noiseless VSS Vintorez sniper rifle. It's similar in function and construction to the AS Val, to the point where both guns share 70% of their parts. Relatively small recoil combined with specially designed high quality subsonic ammunition with an effective range of 400 meters contribute heavily to its accuracy. The heavy bullet makes almost zero noise due to absence of supersonic shock waves, its weight also helps it stabilize during flight, which has a positive impact on the flatness of bullet's trajectory.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_nimble">
		<text>Tide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">
		<text>A weapon made for military units on the basis of the VSS Vintorez silent sniper rifle. The rifle has higher stopping power than the VSS Vintorez, its predecessor, at the expense of its rate of fire, which allows the shooter to eliminate enemy forces one by one without revaling his position.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd">
		<text>Dragunov SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd_descr">
		<text>Dragunov sniper rifle. Almost as reliable as a Kalashnikov, with simplistic design and easy handling. Even a rookie is able to understand the convenient layout of the rifle scope. It proved itself to be an exceptionally efficient and deadly weapon. In the Zone it is preferred mostly by experienced Dutyers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd_nimble">
		<text>Lynx</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">
		<text>A hand-assembled version of the Dragunov SVD sniper rifle. No different in appearance, it nonetheless provides an ideal combination of accuracy and stopping power.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu">
		<text>OTs-03A SVU-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu_descr">
		<text>SVU-A (Snayperskaya Vintovka Ukorochennaya Avtomaticheskaya). A relatively rare find in the Zone due to limited production. The general idea was to create a shortened version of the SVD sniper rifle with as little negative impact on the accuracy as possible, so the designers went with a bullpup design. The barrel has been shortened and comes with a pre-attached sound suppressor which also acts as a muzzle brake. The plastic pistol grip is located near the middle of the gun and has a comfortable shape. The SVU-A allows for automatic fire, but it should be noted that it should be used only in the most extreme cases of emergency, as both the barrel and the small magazine weren't intended for this kind of abuse.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu_nimble">
		<text>Modified OTs-03A SVU-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu_nimble_descr">
		<text>A modified SVU-A sniper rifle that originally belonged to Max, a famous Freedomer. Most of its parts have been remade from lightweight materials and besides that the gun utilizes a more capacious magazine, a rifle scope with higher magnification and an integrated suppressor. As a result, the gun allows for accurate fire at long distances with slightly reduced recoil. The ultimate dream rifle of every sniper. Unfortunately, this rifle has been modified to an extent where cartridge quality has an impact on its operability, making 7N1 rounds no longer suitable for use with this gun.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gauss">
		<text>Gauss rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gauss_descr">
		<text>Project 62 Gauss Rifle - Incredibly accurate coilgun built on the principles of electromagnetism, developed in secret laboratories hidden deep within the Zone, which are now occupied by the Monolith. It is almost entirely noiseless as the gun utilizes energy of electromagnets instead of gunpowder. Despite the tremendous firepower of the Project 62, the recoil is insignificant. The accuracy of this gun combined with the stopping power and velocity of the cartridge exceed those of all other small arms as the bullet's high kinetic energy renders virtually every bulletproof vest useless. A weapon so rare that Stalkers think that the stories about it are bordering on fiction.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_umirotvoritel">
		<text>Unknown weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
		<text>You have no idea how this gun works or what kind of weapon it is. Pulling the trigger doesn't do anything.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Assault -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74u">
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74u_tact">
		<text>Modified AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74u_descr">
		<text>5.45mm Kalashnikov compact assault rifle with a folding stock (6P26). The AKS-74U is based on the AKS-74 rifle, and designed for tank, artillery, and missile crews, as well as special forces. It was adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces and MVD in 1979. If compared with the AKS-74, it has a shorter barrel and lower weight, leading to a decrease in effective range and accuracy of fire. A great number of AKS-74U variants are still in service with the MVD and various security services.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74ub">
		<text>AKS-74UB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74ub_descr">
		<text>A variant of the AKS-74U carbine with a non-detachable suppressor.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74">
		<text>AK-74M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74_tact">
		<text>Modified AK-74M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74_descr">
		<text>5.45mm Kalashnikov assault rifle. The AK-74 was adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces in 1974, in connection with the transition to new, low-recoil cartridges. Compared to the AKM, the AK-74 has a higher effective range and accuracy of fire. A significant innovation in the weapon's design was a two-chambered muzzle device, which serves as a muzzle brake, recoil compensator, and flash suppressor. A few decades later, the AK-74M introduced, which combined all of the improvements that later variants of the AK-74 had into one weapon. These improvements include a polymer buttstock that can be folded, and a dovetail mount for mounting optical sights.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak101_name">
		<text>AK-101</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak101_name_tact">
		<text>Modified AK-101</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak101_descr">
		<text>The AK-101 is a variant of the AK-74M that's chambered for NATO-standard 5.56 ammunition. This weapon is intended for export.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_an94">
		<text>AN-94 Abakan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_an94_descr">
		<text>The AN-94 was originally designed to replace the AK-74, but it failed - the AN-94 is hideously complex if compared to the AK-74. The reason for is its unique and highly accurate 2 round burst mode: many parts work together in unison to achieve this, so a lot can go wrong if the weapon breaks or gets dirty.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza">
		<text>SGK OTs-14-4A Groza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_tact">
		<text>Modified SGK OTs-14-4A Groza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_descr">
		<text>Strelkovo-Granatomyotnyi Kompleks OTs-14-4A "Groza" - A magnificent modular bullpup assault rifle which is compact, reliable and very powerful, with the power factor multiplied further by the under-barrel grenade launcher. A single trigger controls both the grenade launcher and the rifle itself, with a separate barrel selector. The rifle also allows for mounting a rifle scope. A very efficient gun, favoured especially by military Stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_nimble">
		<text>Storm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">
		<text>An experimental version of an assault rifle and grenade launcher system, a Russian modification of the standard OTs-14-4A Groza, this weapon was specially designed for units operating in the Zone. Notable for its increased magazine capacity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_val">
		<text>AS Val</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_val_tact">
		<text>Modified AS Val</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_val_descr">
		<text>The AS Val is a weapon designed specifically for the Russian Spetsnaz. It is similar in function and construction to the VSS Vintorez, to the point where both guns share 70% of their parts. The main differences between this gun and the VSS are the bigger magazine and a folding stock. The main focus of the Val was to provide fully automatic fire with almost zero noise. This weapon allows the user to pierce virtually any bulletproof vest or a helmet at a distance of up to 400 meters while not giving the shooter's position away.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bizon">
		<text>PP-19 Bizon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bizon_descr">
		<text>A submachine gun developed by order of the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs in the early 1990s. The design, like many other weapons from Izhmash, is based on Kalashnikov's assault rifle, due to which many parts are interchangeable with it. While the designers were reworking Kalashnikov's design for a pistol cartridge, they downsized it considerably for the sake of compactness, although the PP-19 works by harnassing the recoil's energy to cycle the weapon instead of using a gas-operated system like an AK. The weapon is equipped with a compact and capacious helical magazine, and there's also a dovetail mount for mounting sights.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_p90">
		<text>FN P90</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_p90_unic">
		<text>Modified FN P90</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_p90_descr">
		<text>The FN P90 is a Belgian submachine gun that was developed from 1987 by FN Herstal. It was developed primarily for tankers and drivers of combat vehicles, and it has a comfortable and compact ergonomic design. The P90's development led to the introduction of the 5.7x28mm round, which has high penetration and it isnt likely to ricochet. 5.7x28mm has a muzzle velocity of up to 715 meters per second, and is capable of piercing NATO-standardized titanium or Kevlar armored vests up to 200 meters away.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5">
		<text>HK MP5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5_descr">
		<text>Heckler and Koch MP5 submachine gun, based on the G3 assault rifle. Widely used by various police and military forces of many countries in Europe and other continents as well. Eventually the MP5 became one of the most common and recognizable sub-machine guns in the world. The factors which contributed to MP5's success are its relatively compact size, ease of use, high accuracy and an adequately powerful cartridge. Its reliability is stuff legends are made of. When it was gradually replaced with more up-to-date models or newer sub-machine guns, it appeared on the black market, and ended up in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ump45">
		<text>HK UMP45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ump45_unic">
		<text>Modified HK UMP45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ump45_descr">
		<text>Heckler and Koch UMP45 submachine gun, developed in the 1990s as an addition to the HK MP5 submachine gun family. Its creators inteded to create a new generation of close combat weapons that are compact, accurate, and powerful.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5sd">
		<text>HK MP5SD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5sd_descr">
		<text>Heckler and Koch MP5SD3. This particular model came equipped with a non-detachable integral suppressor. Other than being quiet, it shares pretty much all advantages and disadvantages of the standard MP5.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_l85">
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_l85_tact">
		<text>Modified L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_l85_descr">
		<text>A British bullpup assault rifle that's known for its troubled history. Due to major reliability and performance issues, the British Army commissioned Heckler and Koch to make a radically improved version of the L85 rifle. an order for modernization of the automatic rifle. The end result was the L85A2, which is a far superior weapon than the L85A1. Its main advantages are high accuracy if used in single-shot mode, the weapon's potential for upgrades. However, when firing in bursts, the L85A2's accuracy drops dramatically, and the weapon tends to perform sluggishly if used in full-auto mode.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_lr300">
		<text>LR-300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_lr300_descr">
		<text>A new step in the development of the M16/AR famous weapon family. The changes were made to the upper half of the steel construction comprising the barrel, gas tube and bolt assembly, reducing the weapon's weight, improving ergonomics and its gas system. The weapon is highly accurate, although its propensity to catch dirt makes it a poor choice for the Zone's difficult conditions.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig550">
		<text>SIG 550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig550_tact">
		<text>Modified SIG 550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig550_descr">
		<text>SIG SG 550 assault rifle, produced by Swiss Arms AG. Its accuracy, high reliability and overall quality have earned it quite a following and it's the standard service rifle of the Swiss Army for all the aforementioned reasons. To decrease the weight and size of the rifle, some of its parts such as the foregrip, stock and the 20 or 30 round magazines are made of plastic.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552">
		<text>SIG SG-552 Commando</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552_descr">
		<text>A shortened version of the Swiss SIG SG-550 assault rifle, designed for special police units. Unlike the SG-550, the return spring acts directly on the bolt carrier rather than on the gas piston rod. Like the base model, the SG-552 is very reliable and accurate, for which it enjoys well-deserved popularity in the security forces of many states, such as SWAT operators from the US and the British SAS.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552_strelok">
		<text>Strelok's SIG SG-552</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552_strelok_descr">
		<text>A Swiss-made SIG SG-552 Commando assault rifle. Although it is hardly new, it is clear that the previous owner took good care of it: the weapon has been taken apart and put back together, with every component fine-tuned for optimum performance, increasing stopping power. The letter "S" has been carved into the stock, along with 16 small notches.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_g36">
		<text>HK G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_g36_descr">
		<text>The German Heckler and Koch G36 assault rifle. Used as a main service rifle by the German Bundeswehr, as well as the Spanish army and the British police. The G36 is probably the first-grade specimen of modern weaponry: lightweight, efficient, patented, made of plastic and heinously overpriced. There's one unsolved mystery though - how the hell did that rifle end up in the Zone in the first place? This gun is exported only with permission of the German government with a sickening load of background checks, so there's no way it could arrive in Ukraine legally.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fn2000">
		<text>FN Herstal F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fn2000_descr">
		<text>The Belgian F2000 is a modular bullpup assault rifle with a proprietary FN EGLM grenade launcher. What makes this gun special is a computerized fire control system which includes a laser rangefinder as well as a trajectory and ballistics calculator.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak_alfa">
    	<text>АК-Alpha</text>
  	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak_alfa_tact">
    	<text>Modified АК-Alpha</text>
  	</string>
	
  	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak_alfa_descr">
		<text>The AK-Alpha was developed in Israel by Command Arms and Accessories. It was was first shown to the public in 2009. Its designers intended to improve the ergonomics of the Kalashnikov assault rifle while maintaining its main advantages – high reliability and ease of maintenance.</text>
  	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_m4">
    	<text>Colt M4A1</text>
  	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_m4_tact">
    	<text>Modified Colt M4A1</text>
  	</string>
	
  	<string id="gunsl_wpn_m4_descr">
		<text>The all-American M4A1 carbine assault rifle, chambered for 5.56 ammunition. One of the most widespread carbines in the world. The ultimate rival of Kalashnikov's AKS-74U, beating it down in single-shot accuracy, ergonomy and modularity. Its smaller profile makes it ideal for vehicle crews, support units, or soldiers needing something more portable in urban combat scenarios.</text>
  	</string>

<!-- Heavy -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pk">
		<text>PK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pk_descr">
		<text>The PK (Pulemyot Kalashnikova, or "Kalashnikov's machine gun"), is a belt-fed general-purpose machine gun, chambered for the 7.62?54mmR rimmed cartridge. Designed in the Soviet Union and currently in production in Russia, the original PK machine gun was introduced in 1961 and the improved PKM variant was introduced in 1969. The PK was designed to replace the SGM and RP-46 machine guns that were previously in Soviet service. The weapon remains in use as a front-line infantry and vehicle-mounted weapon with Russia's armed forces and has also been exported extensively and produced in several other countries under license.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pkm">
		<text>PKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pkm_descr">
		<text>Modernized Kalashnikov general-purpose machine gun. It's big, heavy, belt-fed and very scary, using 100-round munition boxes. Set it up in the right place and you can mow down entire platoons of enemies. Heavy military units assigned for patrolling the Zone are often armed with such machine guns. In the Zone itself it's a pretty rare sight due to its large size and weight. On top of that, using this weapon requires special training and lots of physical preparation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rg6">
		<text>RG-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rg6_descr">
		<text>This revolver-type grenade launcher uses six rifled front-loading barrels, identical to underbarrel launcher attachments. The drum is also front-loading. Widely used for rapid suppression of enemy firing positions and, when in the open, attacking defended fixed targets or fighting particularly tough monsters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rpg7_descr">
		<text>The Russian RPG-7V rocket launcher can be considered as one of the most successful weapons in its class. The main purpose of this weapon was to destroy tanks but there's no problem in using it against infantry either. Since there's a big surplus of them in Ukrainian Army warehouses, they must've arrived in the Zone eventually, but so far Stalkers have never seen or held one yet. Its bulky dimensions and weight aren't something to sing odes about, but when you want to take out multiple targets at once from a large distance, it's certainly irreplaceable.</text>
	</string>
<!-- LASTOCHKA -->
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2">
		<text>PSO-1M2 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2_descr">
		<text>Optical sniper scope PSO-1M2. It was designed for sniper firing during day and night. It has a specific range grid that allows to account for horizontal corrections. It can be attached on the standard Soviet mount - "dovetail" side rail. 4x magnification.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2_1">
		<text>PSO-1M2-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2_1_descr">
		<text>A widely used Soviet scope with 4x magnification. A modification of the PSO-1M2 to match the ballistics of 9x39mm weapons. The scope can be mounted using a dovetail mount used by any Warsaw Pact weapon.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_4">
		<text>1PN93-4 night vision scope</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_4_descr">
		<text>The 1PN93-4 is a fixed multiplex scope that has night vision. It's intended for combat in poor visibility conditions at long ranges with sniper rifles that have Warsaw Pact dovetail mounts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_1">
		<text>1PN93-1 night vision scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_1_descr">
		<text>The 1PN93-1 is a fixed multiplex scope that has night vision - this variant is meant for shorter range. It's intended for combat in poor visibility conditions at close to medium ranges with assault rifles that have Warsaw Pact dovetail mounts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kashtan">
		<text>1P78-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kashtan_descr">
		<text>The 1P78-1 scope is a telescopic scope that has 2.8x magnification and is intended for close to medium range combat with assault rifles that have Warsaw Pact dovetail mounts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_cobra">
		<text>EKP Kobra scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_cobra_descr">
		<text>EKP "Kobra" open collimator sight with electronic controls for brightness and reticle type. It was designed to improve the speed of shooting at emerging and moving targets, in daylight or low-light conditions. The design and housing bracket allows the optic to be installed on any weapon with a Soviet-standard dovetail mount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pka">
		<text>PK-A scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pka_descr">
		<text>The PK-A collimator scope is meant to be used with an assault rifle that has a Warsaw Pact dovetail mount. It can be used both during the day and night, lending it a lot of flexibility.</text>
	</string>

<!-- PICCATINY -->

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_susat">
		<text>SUSAT scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_susat_descr">
		<text>A 4x magnification SUSAT scope produced for the British military, mostly seen on rifles like the L85. It can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_aimpoint">
		<text>Aimpoint CompM4s sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_aimpoint_descr">
		<text>The CompM4s is an enclosed collimator sight designed and developed by the Swedish company Aimpoint AB. Its designed for close to and medium range combat. It can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kemper">
		<text>Firefield Kemper XL-M sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kemper_descr">
		<text>The Kemper XL-M is a open, panoramic collimator sight, ideal for high-intensity shooting, offhand shooting and shooting at moving targets. It can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_eotech">
		<text>EOTech XPS3-0 sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_eotech_descr">
		<text>The XPS3-0 is an holographic scope from the American company EOTech. The XPS3-0 is smaller than other holographic sights, but it's not inferior in terms of speed or functionality. It can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_elcan">
		<text>Elcan Specter DR 1x/4x scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_elcan_descr">
		<text>The Specter DR 1x/4x is an optical sight from the Canadian company ELCAN Optical Technologies. It has 4 magnification modes, and it can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pn23">
		<text>PN-23 night vision scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pn23_descr">
		<text>The PN-23 is a small night vision scope from the Russian company Novosibirsk Instrument-Making Plant. It has 3 magnification modes, and it can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_acog">
		<text>ACOG sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_acog_descr">
		<text>The ACOG (which is short for Advanced Combat Optical Gunsight) family of sights comes from Trijicon, an American company. This specific sight comes with a USMC standard reticle, has a magnification of 3.5x, and it can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_leupold">
		<text>Leupold Mark 8 CQBSS 1.1-8x24 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_leupold_descr">
		<text>The Leupold Mark 8 1.1-8x24 is a scope with a wide range of magnifications. This scope is perfect for shooting at short distances, although you shouldn't adjust the zeroing, since it's already well-adjusted for accurate shots at medium distances.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Other scopes -->
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_rakurs">
		<text>Rakurs-PM scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_rakurs_descr">
		<text>The Rakurs-PM is a telescopic scope that has a wide viewing angle. It increases the effectiveness of long-range weapons and it can be used up to 400 meters for moving or stationary targets. This variant is meant to be installed on any weapon that has a Weaver bar.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pu">
		<text>PU 3.5x22 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pu_descr">
		<text>This scope is a hunting scope that has a magnification of 3.5x. It can be mounted on the TOZ-34.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pgo7v">
		<text>PGO-7B scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pgo7v_descr">
		<text>The PGO-7B scope was developed by the Russian company Tochpribor Central Design Bureau to supplement the RPG-7 family of RPG launchers, allowing them better accuracy.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_po4x34">
		<text>PO 4x34 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_po4x34_descr">
		<text>This 4.0x fixed zoom optical scope was designed specifically for the Groza bullpup assault rifle. It's not popular with snipers due to its limited magnifcation options, but it's great for increasing the Groza's accuracy.</text>
	</string>

<!-- SILENCERS -->

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_pb">
		<text>PB silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_pb_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for PB pistol. Incompatible with other weapons. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_m4_2000">
		<text>AAC M4-2000 silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_m4_2000_descr">
		<text>This silencer is for automatic rifles and carbines chambered for 5.56x45mm.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_apb_silencer">
		<text>APB silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_apb_silencer_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for the APB machine pistol. Incompatible with other weapons. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_svd">
		<text>TGP-B silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_svd_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for the SVD sniper rifle. Incompatible with other weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_tgpa">
		<text>TGP-A silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_tgpa_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer that's compatible with the AK's chambered for 5.45x39mm.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_colt_p220_silencer">
		<text>AAC Black Box silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_colt_p220_silencer_descr">
		<text>The Advanced Armament Corp. Black Box silencer is meant for various pistols chambered for .45 ACP.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon12">
		<text>Hexagon 12K silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon12_descr">
		<text>A silencer developed and designed by the Hexagon corporation, meant for various shotguns chambered for 12 gauge.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon">
		<text>Hexagon silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon_descr">
		<text>A silencer developed and designed by the Hexagon corporation, meant for various weapons chambered for either 7.62x39mm or 7.62x54mmR.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28">
		<text>P90 silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for the P90 submachine gun. Incompatible with other weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28_pistol">
		<text>GEMTECH SFN57 silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28_pistol_descr">
		<text>GEMTECH SFN57 - Standard-issue detachable silencer for the Five-SeveN pistol. Incompatible with other weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18smg">
		<text>Bizon silencr</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18smg_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for the Bizon submachine gun.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18">
		<text>9x18mm silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18_descr">
		<text>This silencer is compatiable with all pistols chambered for 9x18mm, although it does require a threaded barrel in order to be attached.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x19">
		<text>9x19mm silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x19_descr">
		<text>This silencer is compatiable with all pistols chambered for 9x18mm.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x21">
		<text>SR1MP silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x21_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for the SR1MP pistol. Incompatible with other weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_groza">
		<text>OTs-14-4A Groza silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_groza_descr">
		<text>Standard-issue detachable silencer for the OTs-14-4A bullpup assault rifle. This silencer has a rubber casing on it that allows you to use the silencer as a handgrip, protecting the user from the heat the silencer absorbs when the weapon fires.</text>
	</string>

<!-- GRENADE LAUNCHERS -->

	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_gp25">
		<text>GP-25 Kostyor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_gp25_descr">
		<text>Under-barrel mounted grenade launcher for AK family rifles. A quick and efficient way to send explosive death to multiple enemies at once in a ten meter radius, which makes it very useful.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_l123a2">
		<text>L123A2 UGL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_l123a2_descr">
		<text>A grenade launcher that's based on the Heckler and Koch AG36. The A2 model has numerous revisions that improve it. This grenade launcher is chambered for 40x46mm, which allows it to use any grenade that was developed for any NATO-standardized grenade launcher, such as M433 HEDP, M397A1, and many others.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_m203_descr">
		<text>Under-barrel mounted M203 grenade launcher for NATO rifles. Single shot, reload functions by moving the barrel forward and replacing the spent shell with a new one.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_groza">
		<text>GP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_groza_descr">
		<text>A grenade launcher module designed to be used in conjunction with the OTs-14 Groza's automatic grenade launcher system. It's based on the GP-25 underbarrel grenade launcher, and if compared to the GP-25, the GP-5 has undergone a number of changes and improvements. The most significant of these is consolidating both firing modes into one trigger - and you can switch to what firing mode you want with a switch. Due to the fact that this grenade launcher is proprietary and can be attached only to the OTs-14 Groza, it cannot be used with any other weapon.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="mil_m202_name">
	<text>M202 FLASH</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_m202_desc">
	<text>The M202 FLASH is an American rocket launcher equipped with four tubes that fire incendiary rockets. It was designed to replace the standard flamethrower currently used by the US Army during the Vietnam War, but only a small amount of these were actually made, so it didn't fully replace older flamethrowers. The heat created by the incendinary rockets is much greater than napalm because of the aluminum-based mixture that the rockets use in order to increase their effectiveness. The light and heat created by the mixture is so intense that it can cause severe burns even if you're a fair distance away from the impact area.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
