<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="af_maska_1">
		<text>Respirator</text>
	</string>
		<string id="enc_zone_af_maska_1">
		<text>An essential item for wandering around in the Zone. It protects the lungs from radioactive dust, harmful gases, vapors, and biohazard agents in the air. Encourages the wearer to take deeper, more concentrated breaths, and therefore does not impact stamina greatly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_maska_2">
		<text>GP-5 gas mask</text>
	</string>
		<string id="enc_zone_af_maska_2">
		<text>A standard gas mask, being massively produced in the USSR. Over the years, millions have been stockpiled and used in the army. It provides better protection than a simple respirator, but running long distances while wearing this is not recommended.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mine">
                <text>PMN anti-personnel mine</text> 
        </string>
	<string id="af-mine_s">
                <text>PMN mine</text> 
        </string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mine">
		<text>A "blast-mine" (pressure-activated anti-personnel mine), designed to incapacitate enemy infantry. When stepped on, the mine usually destroys the lower leg and does not wait until pressure is released to explode. The blast usually severs the foot completely, and depending on the distance of the other leg, can severely damage it, too. In addition, the shock wave is enough to knock a man unconscious, and the hot gases can cause severe burns to legs. Death may occur from the painful shock, or from severe bleeding if it's not stopped quickly. The mine can be placed on the ground or slightly buried; even under snow the firing mechanism works manually. The term "combat mine" is not necessarily correct for this mine, as it is not equipped with a self-destruct device. Anti-handling and anti-disturbance devices are not present on the mine. The mine's fuse (MD-9 type) is part of the mine's internal design, and makes setting the mine reasonably safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapiska">
		<text>Written note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapiska_s">
		<text>Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapiska_l">
		<text>A piece of paper, on which is written: "The next time he goes to the Arena, make sure he doesn't come back. V."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapiska_m1_l">
		<text>A clumsily-written note, saying: "All right, I'm willing to make a temporary truce... just for this case. PS: Dude, what the hell is with these paper notes? It's the 21st century!"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zapiska_m2_l">
		<text>An unknown note, written: "I'm glad you understand my meaning. You guys really know how to crush heads, so this time I'll let you take care of our friend. p.s. Don't underestimate the paper medium :) Â."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amk_matras">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amk_matras_s">
		<text>Sleeping bag</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_amk_matras">
		<text>A sleeping bag for hiking. Probably the most convenient way to spend a night in the Zone. It doesn't protect against radiation, but it will keep you warm and dry.</text>
	</string>
        <string id="guitar">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
        <string id="harmonica">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
        <string id="hand_radio">
		<text>Handheld radio</text>
	</string>
        <string id="hand_radio1">
		<text>Broken radio</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-heavy">
		<text>Heavy stalker armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-light">
		<text>Light stalker armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-medium">
		<text>Midweight stalker armor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandage">
		<text>"IPP-1" bandage pack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_descr">
		<text>Army binoculars with adjustable (up to 7.5 diopters) magnification. Allows you to view the terrain and buildings in detail from a long distance away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular_name">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
        </string>
	<string id="pivo">
		<text>Beer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voda">
		<text>Mineral water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kefir">
		<text>Kefir</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_desc">
		<text>A detailed map of the Dead City, with a layout of mercenary positions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_name">
		<text>Map of Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctors_key_desc">
		<text>Doctor's key from the Pripyat stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctors_key_short_desc">
		<text>Doctor's key</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Conserva">
		<text>"Tourist's Delight"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Devic">
		<text>Instruments and devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-PDA">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
		<text>A protective suit, weighing 18 kg. It protects the body from "Jelly", "Burnt Fuzz", and a majority of other anomalies and mechanical damage. The chest and back are protected by built-in metal plates. It is also equipped with a sealed, metal/plastic helmet and two oxygen cylinders. Warning: with continuous use it will become damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
		<text>A protective suit, weighing 8 kg. Provides moderate protection from weak anomalies and mechanical damage, and is equipped with an oxygen mask. Warning: with continuous use it will become damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
		<text>A protective suit, weighing 12 kg. It protects the body from "Jelly", "Burnt Fuzz", and a majority of other anomalies and mechanical damage. It is equipped with a sealed helmet and oxygen tank. Warning: with continuous use it will become damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
		<text>An "EXP-4" scientific protective suit with an airtight red helmet. Weighs 11 kg. It protects the body from fire, acid gases, a variety of anomalies (including "Burnt Fuzz"), and mechanical damage. Equipped with two oxygen cylinders. Warning: with continuous use it will become damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Detect1">
		<text>DAA-02 anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect2">
		<text>DAA-02 anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect3">
		<text>DKG-01I dosimeter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect4">
		<text>DAS-4M universal detector</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="detect">
		<text>DKS-04 dosimeter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
		<text>The first and best device for a stalker who doesn't want become bald after two days in the Zone. When radiation is detected, the device beeps.\n Must be placed in a special equipment slot for proper operation.</text>
	</string>
        <string id="enc_equipment_devic_hand_radio">
		<text>Army hand radio. Effective radius - 5 km. Tunes in a fairly wide range of frequencies, catching some pretty interesting activity.</text>
	</string>
        <string id="enc_equipment_devic_hand_radio1">
		<text>Looks like someone tried to MacGyver an army radio from an FM-radio, but it didn't work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA1">
		<text>A personal digital assistance (PDA) - an irreplacable device in the zone ... if it works.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch">
		<text>Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
		<text>A regular flashlight. Very useful when there's no other lights. In case of emergency, you can swing at mutants with it, although this doesn't do much at all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m1">
		<text>An upgraded flashlight with a more powerful lightbulb and an improved transformer, reducing charging time. However, the weight of the transformer (10 kg) makes this a questionable purchase. It could be very useful for looking for artifacts at the bottom of rivers or reservoirs, looking for a quick route there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
		<text>"S.T.A.L.K.E.R" - a great energy drink. If you're too tired to move, it's a great choice!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
		<text>No one knows who manages to bake bread in the Zone, but this loaf is not contaminated and is almost completely edible. In any case, stalkers don't seem to complain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
		<text>Tinned stew meat. Pork and beef. 1st class - produced for USSR Ministry of Defence by one of the military factories in Ulan-Ude. It is ideal for field use - no warming up is required. Withdrawn from Army provision stores and supplied to the Zone by greedy warrant officers, it may be considered pretty fresh-made, as long as no "best-before" date is known to have ever been stated on soldier's rations. Among the stalkers its got the nickname "Porcow".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
		<text>Often this is a breakfast, dinner and supper for a stalker when no other food is available. There's trace amounts of radiation in this sausage, as animals native to the Zone were processed for it. Anyway, it looks eatbale.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
		<text>Vodka made by a local distillery. If you smell it, you can imagine that this vodka was made from old, unwashed socks, but it goes down very smoothly.\nRecomendation: drinking this can reduce the impact of radiation if consumed before exposure. But main benefit of vodka in the Zone is that it restores psychic health, and protects you from the effects of psy-zones by numbing your brain. There's a rumor that if you take that couple of shots before fighting a controller, it'll help you maintain control of yourself. Remember - if you feel like you're going nuts, take a swig of vodka.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="enc_equipment_food_guitar1">
                <text>An ordinary six-stringed guitar. Most stalkers like to strum on the guitar when taking a rest after a long and dangerous sally into the Zone. It helps them to relax and feel cozier.</text>
	</string>
        <string id="enc_equipment_food_harmonica1">
                <text>Though every additional kilogram may cost you your life in the Zone, harmonicas are quite popular with music-lovers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_voda1">
		<text>A plastic bottle filled pure mineral water. Due to the lack of fresh water in the Zone, stalkers have to buy imported bottles.\n Water helps with fatigue and the negative effects of taking drugs and medkits too often.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_kefir1">
		<text>Kefir is a rare thing in the Zone. Efficiently reduces the effects of alcohol.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_pivo1">
		<text>Beer is beer. It's wonderful to gulp it, especially while watching TV. Due to a certain lack of TVs in the Zone, beer is mostly used to withdraw radionuclides.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Antirad">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
		<text>Perfectly filters out radionuclides from the body and reduces the impact of absorbed radiation. There's also a supplied bar of hematogen in a separate packet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
		<text>The IPP-1 is a bandage pack for individual use. It consists of sterile bandage sealed in a waterproof package. This pack is meant for first aid treatment of bullet wounds and any kind of bleeding. No side effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
		<text>An all-purpose medkit. Used to treat injuries of various types and severities - wounds, burns, poisonings, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit2">
		<text>A specialized medical set to fight against physical damage and blood loss. Contains coagulants, antibiotics, immunal stimulators, and painkillers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit3">
		<text>A medical kit that's designed specifically for scientists working in the Zone. The set includes means of healing wounds as well as means of eliminating radionuclides from the body. Prevents the development of radiation sickness and lowers the dose of accumulated radiation. Antidepressants are also included.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_name">
		<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R Energy Drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_short_name">
		<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R Energy Drink</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Equipment">
		<text>Gear and food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Food">
		<text>Food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Kolbasa">
		<text>"Diet" sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medi">
		<text>Medicaments</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit">
		<text>Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit_army">
		<text>Army medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Medkit_scientific">
		<text>Scientific medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Sci2">
		<text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Vodka">
		<text>«StalkerOFFka» vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_gd5">
		<text>GD-05 smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar">
		<text>Bioradar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_bioradar">
		<text>This device detects most living beings, both cold and warm-blooded, in a range of up to 50 metres. The device's core principle of detection is picking up electromagnetic waves generated by moving and muscle contraction of living beings. It was considered that those weak signals can be detected only with special lab equipment, but scientists discovered a very interesting effect of one Zone artifact - the "Crystal ball". A small pocket device sitting in science assistant Semenov's coat began to gain a high-frequency signal of a small radio situated in Argentina. After researching what caused this, the scientists discovered a simple explanation: the "Crystal ball" artifact amplifies radio signals and filters it from noise. Obviously, a small part of the signal coming from Argentina was being detected by radio recievers at the Yantar base, but no one was able to pick it up clearly enough. But when there was "Crystal ball" added to the equation, receivers started to get various well-filtered signals from ranges up to 14 thousand kilometers away! The "Crystal ball intercept" project was immediately classified, but some devices that used this wonderful effect have been leaked to the public. The bioradar device detects living biological tissue signal and filters it by frequency and range. As a result you can see spots that represent living organisms on the screen. The device originally was created for intelligence gathering work in the Zone, so Semenov added in device firmware-based detection of some common Zone creatures. Extra firmwares are available in science labs. Basic firmware are able to detect humans, dogs, fleshes and boars.\nYou should place this device in the special inventory slot to get it working.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bread_rad">
		<text>Contaminated bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_food_bread_rad">
		<text>This used to be an ordinary loaf of bread. Now, after being contaminated by a large amount of radiation, it has been turned inedible. If you're fed up with life, you're welcome to eat this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kolbasa_rad">
		<text>Die-it sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_food_kolbasa_rad">
		<text>No one knows what the sausage produced in the Zone is made out of, but one thing is certain: you'd need to down a lot of vodka after eating this contaminated sausage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tag_bad_food_tip">
		<text>Damn it! Some food supplies got spoiled.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kefir_rad">
		<text>Contaminated kefir</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_kefir1_rad">
		<text>Kefir is a rare thing in the Zone. Efficiently reduces the effects of alcohol. You are going to need to cure yourself of radiation poisoning if you drink this contaminated kefir.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Conserva_rad">
		<text>"Tourist's Denied"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1_rad">
		<text>Even the tin can could not protect the meat inside from being exposed to radiation. Must be disposed of.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="repairkit">
		<text>Field repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_repairkit">
		<text>A set of tools, gadgets and rags for maintenance and repair of accoutrements in the field.\nUnfortunately, these sets were made by local craftsmen and can't stand intensive use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sigaret">
		<text>Cigarettes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_sigaret">
		<text>These look like ordinary cigarettes, but the quality of the filling that's in them is of questionable quality. What's actually in these may be partially answered by judging by the nicknames stalker give these: "Tales of the Crazy Forest", "Grandma's pillow", "Coal resins".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="D-IX">
		<text>"D-IX" drug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_D-IX">
		<text>Do want to act like a diesel-powered truck in the North Pole with no brakes? Pop a few of these. Mix together 5 mg of syntetic cocaine, 3 mg of pervitin, 5 mg of oxycodone, and you get this drug. If you take this, you can march up to 90 kilometers while fully kitted out without getting tired.\nThis drug is meant for soldiers, and it's straight from Herr Doktor's lab. Of course, taking this isn't without consequence - like any serious stimulant, these are habit-forming, and consuming an entire bottle of these is a great way to induce a heart attack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bipsizon">
		<text>"Bi-Psi-Zon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_bipsizon">
		<text>This excellent medicine has been created to meet the specific needs of those in the Zone. It can protect from psi-emissions and controller's mental impact for a short period of time, or remove the effects of said impacts entirely.\nSome claim this drug to have been developed by one of the Ministry of Public Health Institutes specially for the field Zone research squads, while others ascribe the invention to Military Stalker Colonel Bibik and swear that the drug's name is the abbreviation for "Bibik - psi-protection - Zone". Whoever has invented it, the drug is very popular with the stalkers, but is very expensive and hard to get.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="autodoctor">
		<text>"SLSA 0.01.1EM"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_autodoctor">
		<text>System of Live Support , Automatic, Experimental Military. Was developed by order of Zone control comittee for military stalkers and assault units. Consists of a device, couple of sensors and set of cartridges with drugs of various functions. Constantly examines user's condition and applies medicines in proper dose when needed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cart_a">
		<text>Combined Cartridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_cart_a">
		<text>A cartridge containing 20 charges of full set of drugs used for the "SLSA 0.01.1EM" device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cart_h">
		<text>Therapeutic cartridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_cart_h">
		<text>A cartridge containing 20 charges of drugs used for support system of the "SLSA 0.01.1EM" device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cart_s">
		<text>Stimulator cartridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_cart_s">
		<text>A cartridge containing 20 charges of stimulation drugs used for the "SLSA 0.01.1EM" stimulating system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cart_r">
		<text>Antirad cartridge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_cart_r">
		<text>A cartridge containing 20 charges of antiradiation drugs used for the "SLSA 0.01.1EM" antirad system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detector_minefinder">
		<text>ASM-2m scanning mine detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detector_minefinder_s">
		<text>ASM-2m</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_minefinder">
		<text>This brand new compact scanning mine detector has been dubbed the "ASM-2m". The device effectively locates landmines within 7 meter radius and emits a sound when it detects them. Another remarkable feature this device has is that it may also transmit the locations of any detected mines to a GPS navigator.</text> 
    </string>
	<string id="yod">
		<text>"B-190" drug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_yod">
		<text>This almost nontoxic medicine helps you survive even lethal radiation overdoses! (Note: this works 9 cases out of 10) The drug must be taken BEFORE you are subjected to intense radioactive emissions, otherwise no effect will take place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pnv_1">
		<text>Old army NVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pnv_1_description">
		<text>An outdated night vision device: it's cheap, but heavy and inefficient.</text> 
    </string>
	<string id="item_pnv_2">
		<text>Modern NVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pnv_2_description">
		<text>A modern night vision device: it's much more lightweight, high image quality is far better. However, it's more expensive.</text> 
    </string>
	<string id="item_termovizor">
		<text>Thermal vision device</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_termovizor_description">
		<text>This device detects objects by detecting thermal radiation. It allows its user to detect any object that emits heat behind smoke, during heavy rain and even through brush or thickets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="art_analyzer_name">
		<text>Special Artifact Analyzer (AAS)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="art_analyzer_short_name">
		<text>AAS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="art_analyzer_desc">
		<text>Special Artifact Analyzer (AAS) - a device allowing scientists in the field to study unknown anomalous formations in harsh conditions. Data is written to a memory card, which is built-in to the device. Of course, the data you input will not be as accurate as data from a research institute, but this device is great for initial data collection. Stalkers are only issued AAS devices in exceptional cases - usually for jobs involving the discovery and extraction of unknown artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="telekill_case_name">
		<text>"Prudenko's isolator" case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="telekill_case_short_name">
		<text>"Prudenko's isolator" case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="telekill_case_desc">
		<text>A case made from an unknown alloy named "Prudenko's isolator", which should theoretically protect you from the mind-affecting properties of artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="telekill_case_with_art_name">
		<text>Artifact in "Prudenko's isolator" case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="telekill_case_with_art_short_name">
		<text>Artifact in "Prudenko's isolator" case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="telekill_case_with_art_desc">
		<text>An unknown artifact in a "Prudenko's isolator" case. The artifact doesn't show itself, except occasionally jumping around in the container. It should probably be taken to the scientists quickly.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_dog_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Dog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_dog_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Dog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_dog_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="bioradar_psevdodog_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Pseudodog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_psevdodog_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Pseudodog"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_psevdodog_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_flesh_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Flesh"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_flesh_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Flesh"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_flesh_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_boar_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Boar"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_boar_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Boar"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_boar_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_tushkano_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Rodent"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_tushkano_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Rodent"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_tushkano_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_krovosos_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Bloodsucker"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_krovosos_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Bloodsucker"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_krovosos_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_burer_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Burer"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_burer_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Burer"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_burer_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_zombie_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware "Zombie"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_zombie_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Zombie"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_zombie_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_snork_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Snork"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_snork_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Snork"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_snork_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_kontroler_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Controller"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_kontroler_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Controller"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_kontroler_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_poltergeist_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Poltergeist"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_poltergeist_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Poltergeist"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_poltergeist_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_psevdogigant_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Pseudogiant"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_psevdogigant_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Pseudogiant"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_psevdogigant_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_cat_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Cat"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_cat_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Cat"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_cat_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="bioradar_chimera_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Chimera"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_chimera_name_short_name">
		<text>Bioradar firmware: "Chimera"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bioradar_chimera_name_desc">
		<text>An encrypted memory card with Bioradar firmware with the relevant signatures.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="id_simple">
		<text>'Response' Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_id_simple">
		<text>An outdated, first-generation anomaly detector. It emits a light when it detects anomalies. In addition, it can also detect artifacts and measure the distance to the closest one. The distance to the artifact is indicated by the how frequently the light emits. To ensure reliability, readings should be done when stationary.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="id_advanced">
		<text>'Scout' Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_id_advanced">
		<text>A second-generation anomaly detector. It's equipped with a radar for anomalies and an LED display that shows the direction and distance of any detected artifact relative to the user.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="id_elite">
		<text>'Search' Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_id_elite">
		<text>A third-generation anomaly detector/scanner, used by scientists. Thanks to three independent sensors, the approximate location of the artifact is indicated on a special screen. The device's search mode can be activated via a switch on the front side of the device; in this mode, all known artifacts can be detected. It is also capable of wireless communication, so it can stream the coordinates of nearby anomalies to any GPS device.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_treasure_name">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_item_treasure_desc">
		<text>A small-sized backpack. Its made from rubberized fabric, so it won't get wet. In this you can store valuables somewhere in a secluded place - which is a excellent way to make a cache.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
