<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="detector_upgrade_tip">
		<text>PULSE RESONATOR: Use ">" key for frequency selection, "Enter" to generate a pulse, "K" key to exit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detector_normal_tip">
		<text>Normal: Press "K" key to activate the pulse resonator.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="o2_level">
		<text>AIR SUPPLY: </text>
	</string>
	<string id="o2_level_breather">
		<text>Air supply [active regeneration] </text>
	</string>	
	<string id="neutral_killer">
		<text>Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="iskatel">
		<text>Artifact Hunter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral_military">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulg_band">
		<text>Kulgavy's Bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kulg_band_2">
		<text>Unknown</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bratstvo_9">
		<text>Cleaner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_prebandit">
		<text>Loner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="csky">
		<text>Clear Sky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor">
		<text>Loner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_zombied">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="actor_dolg">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_stalker">
		<text>Military Stalker</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="actor_freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arena_enemy">
		<text>Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bad">
		<text>bad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bandit">
		<text>Bandit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg">
		<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ecolog">
		<text>Ecologist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="quest_stalker">
		<text>Stalker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enemy">
		<text>enemy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="excellent">
		<text>excellent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="experienced">
		<text>experienced</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Found_PDA">
		<text>Found PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Science_memo">
		<text>A Memorandum of the expedition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="freedom">
		<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="friendly">
		<text>friend</text>
	</string>
	<string id="good">
		<text>good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="indifferent">
		<text>neutral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="killer">
		<text>Mercenary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l01_escape">
		<text>Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l01_escape_description">
		<text>Predbannik Zona, army cordon. In the cellar behind the village near the army roadblock you will find a merchant. Do not go to the checkpoint and get in front of the soldiers, they have orders to shoot without warning ... You can't kill soldiers, only as a last resort, for each killed merchant has to pay for it and he will not be happy with this arrangement. There are large packs of blind dogs on the plains, only suicide bombers go to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l02_garbage">
		<text>Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l02_garbage_description">
		<text>It's a big stinking dump where mountains of radioactive garbage were taken after the accident in '86... Broken cranes, machinery... You can find the remains of old buildings. You can meet mutants. It's mostly newcomers and bandits, but not without them. You can find small artifacts, but it's better not to stop here for a long time. There are a lot of radiation hotspots, you can't go there without protection.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l03_agroprom">
		<text>Agroprom Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l03_agroprom_description">
		<text>A seemingly unremarkable area. In the South-West is the building of the Research Institute "Agroprom". It has no permanent "owners". For a while it was the main base of the "Duty" group, but now it's occupied by a platoon of soldiers. They have dug up something there, they say it's not clear, but they won't let them get close. They also use the buildings of the Research Institute as a repair base for patrolling the perimeter of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l04_darkvalley">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l04_darkvalley_description">
		<text>This is the dark valley, it is always gloomy and foggy. It rains often. It also has one of the highest concentrations of anomalies.... You can get good artifacts, or you can easily part with your life.... You're bound to meet veterans, they make money pulling artifacts out of their asses. I've heard about Borov's gang, they're back, but I don't know, they've all been shot. There's an entrance to the lab, but no one's ever come back from there, so I wouldn't advise going in there... It looks like dwarves, or maybe something worse...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l05_bar">
		<text>Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l05_bar_description">
		<text>Before the crash in '86, this was just an ordinary urban-type settlement. Now, as you can see, it's the ruined remains of a former settlement... In the local underground grocery store cafeteria you'll find a stalker bar, stalkers from all over the Zone gather here, a local merchant works here as a bartender... keeps the place running, so to speak. You can go there if you want to trade, socialize, and get an interesting assignment... And get the latest news. If you walk from the village, you'll come to the old Rostock factory. Behind the factory is the base of the group "Duty". The base is closed from outsiders, I advise you not to break there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l06_rostok">
		<text>Wild Territory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l06_rostok_description">
		<text>Wild Territory used to be a rather large factory, of which now only ruins remain. Many stalkers have found their end in them: there are all sorts of unclean things there, as if they converge there from all over the Zone. According to rumors, though, there is something very important in this factory, so there are always plenty of people willing to try their luck there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l07_military">
		<text>Army warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l07_military_description">
		<text>An abandoned army base there, an old village and a small lake. And on the army base a group has settled down. It's called Svoboda, anarchists who believe that the Zone is a free reserve. They are harmless, in principle, plus they do important work - from Radar monsters and fanatics of the "Monolith", so the guys there hold them back. If you go further into the Zone from the base, you'll get right to the Brain Burner: it blocks the way to Pripyat and Chernobyl NPP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l08_yantar">
		<text>Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l08_yantar_description">
		<text>The legendary Lake Amber, how oh how, of course I know. Black, oily... It drinks the souls of stalkers, just go to the shore, and you're gone in no time, only a shell of empty bultykh in the water and there ... to the island, so, in the fog floats ... And zombies, empty shells wander around, they see - howl and start to follow you, then you have to do legs, because a lot of them, former stalkers, died on this lake, and now the empty shells only wander.... If you go around the lake and zombies, you will find a scientific camp, they are studying something there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l10_radar">
		<text>Red Forest</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l10_radar_description">
		<text>Somebody tried to get through the Burnout again, they say. Well, with the ends, of course, to hell with the man ... You haven't heard of the Brain Burner? Come on, man! It's the biggest bogeyman in the neighborhood. The only trouble is, the horror stories about it are mostly true. It's a scary place. You can die here, even if you've been lucky all your life. Anyone who comes close to the Brain Burner, goes crazy, turns into a zombie and then wanders around the Zone, wandering, unaccustomed. Only shells of people remain, and no one has ever returned from there in their right mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l11_pripyat">
		<text>Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l11_pripyat_description">
		<text>This was a town of power engineers - it was built together with the Chernobyl NPP. It was a small town... But now nobody lives there anymore - except, of course, for all sorts of evil things like mutants and zombies. To all appearances, it is impossible to get there: the Brain Burner is blocking the way. However, there are always hotheads trying to get past it, but none of them has ever returned...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12_stancia">
		<text>CNPP-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12_stancia_description">
		<text>A former nuclear power plant that everyone has heard of at least once. It is the very heart of the Zone. If legends are to be believed, somewhere there is an anomaly that can fulfill any wish - it is called Monolith. The station is completely under the control of the Monolith group. These fanatics carefully and selflessly guard this territory. Many stalkers dream of getting to the Chernobyl station: some of them want to fulfill their wishes, some want answers to their questions, and some just want to get rich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12_stancia_2">
		<text>CNPP-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12_stancia_2_description">
		<text>A former nuclear power plant that everyone has heard of at least once. It is the very heart of the Zone. If legends are to be believed, somewhere there is an anomaly that can fulfill any wish - it is called Monolith. The station is completely under the control of the Monolith group. These fanatics carefully and selflessly guard this territory. Many stalkers dream of getting to the Chernobyl station: some of them want to fulfill their wishes, some want answers to their questions, and some just want to get rich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="k01_darkscape_ogse">
		<text>Darkscape</text>
	</string>
	<string id="k01_darkscape_ogse_description">
		<text>One of the very first territories captured by the Zone during its first expansion. It was here that man first tried to fight back and stop the Zone's further expansion. Dangerous and unpredictable terrain. Due to the very long exposure to the Zone, the Hollow has become overgrown with many very powerful anomalies, some of which are not found anywhere else in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l09_deadcity_ogse">
		<text>Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l09_deadcity_ogse_description">
		<text>Have you heard of City 32? That's where they got caught. It was quiet at first, well, within limits. They were filming and measuring, collecting samples, poking at anomalies with instruments... And then they went crazy. A mass insanity. People started to slowly go crazy. Ours, the one who retired, told me... Some started tearing their throats with their fingernails, some smashed their heads against the wall, and some just put a gun in their mouths and..... And then the beasts came. Whoever was in their right mind barricaded themselves in the house. You can imagine, can't you? Outside it's night and all the neighborhood critters, and inside the people are going crazy one by one. Since then no one has been coming to Gorodok-32...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l13_generators_ogse">
		<text>Generators</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l13_generators_ogse_description">
		<text>With the help of satellites it was possible to find out that the epicenter of the explosion was not near the units of the nuclear power plant itself, but a kilometer away from them. The central part is occupied by a structure consisting of balls (generators) lined up in a circle and an antenna located in the center. Around each balloon is an area of bloated earth. The area is covered with dead forest, and swamps are present. Not far from the installation is a military base with an underground passage to the outside. There is also a small ruined village with a lot of different animals and quite a high level of radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l22_marsh">
		<text>Marshes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l22_marsh_description">
		<text>The water in the marshes is very radioactive, as there is a large amount of various impurities and radioactive dust on its surface. Everything is overgrown with grass and reeds. In the marshes there are various low-dangerous mutants, like flesh and boars, but there is a small chance to meet and swamp creatures. All of them can lurk in the reeds and at any moment suddenly attack from behind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l23_x9">
		<text>Metro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l23_x9_description">
		<text>The hub branch of the underground railroad that connected the laboratories in the Zone to Pripyat. Communication systems, transportation tunnels, laboratories, warehouses and huge factories were all hidden underground. Back then, the Soviet Union tried to keep its secrets as much as possible. The same was done with the secret facilities at Chernobyl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="master">
		<text>master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military">
		<text>Military</text>
	</string>
	<string id="monolith">
		<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="neutral">
		<text>neutral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novice">
		<text>rookie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_no_active_task">
		<text>No active task</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_time_till_surge">
		<text>Time to release:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker">
		<text>Loner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="terrible">
		<text>terrible</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader">
		<text>Trader</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsmith">
		<text>Gunsmith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="guider">
		<text>Explorer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_community">
		<text>group</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_price">
		<text>Price</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_rank">
		<text>rank</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_relation">
		<text>attitude</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_reputation">
		<text>reputation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="very_bad">
		<text>very bad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="very_good">
		<text>very good</text>
	</string>
	<string id="veteran">
		<text>veteran</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zombied">
		<text>Zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_Cancel">
		<text>Cancel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_No">
		<text>No</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_OK">
		<text>OK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Btn_Yes">
		<text>Yes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="global_map">
		<text>Map of the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_autosave">
		<text>Auto-saving...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_game_over">
		<text>Game over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_item_used">
		<text>Used</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_not_enough_money">
		<text>This character hasn't enough money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_not_enough_money_npc">
		<text>This NPC hasn't enough money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_opponent_items">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_search_treasure">
		<text>Search the cache ($$ACTION_USE$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="inventory_item_use">
		<text>Take the object ($$ACTION_USE$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_check_updates">
		<text>Game updates</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_mm_alternative">
		<text>Alternative</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_health">
		<text>Health</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_radiation">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_satiety">
		<text>Hunger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_thirst">
		<text>Thirst</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_alcohol">
		<text>Alcohol</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_power">
		<text>Endurance</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_bleeding">
		<text>Bleeding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_inv_psy_health">
		<text>Psy-health</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_inv_additional_weight">
		<text>Max weight</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_inv_additional_weight2">
		<text>Weight</text>
    </string>
	<string id="st_mp_say_to_all">
		<text>To all</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_say_to_team">
		<text>To team</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_knife">
		<text>Knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_disabled_voting">
		<text>Voting is not available on this server.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_no_current_voting">
		<text>No active voting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_ready">
		<text>ready</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_voting_succeed">
		<text>Vote successful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mp_voting_failed">
		<text>Vote failed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l03u_agr_underground">
		<text>Dungeons SRI "Agroprom"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l03u_agr_underground_description">
		<text>"So you move down a spiral staircase to a room with columns, then to the exit, get to a large room with pipes on the ceiling. From there down to the second exit, go into the tunnel and turn left. At the end there will be a passage to the right. There will be a small room, cross it and turn right. Look for a hole on the left wall, next to the inscription "Don't get in - it will kill you!". That's where the stash should be" - Mole, experienced lone-digger, leader of a large group of stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l04u_labx18">
		<text>Lab X-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l04u_labx18_description">
		<text>The underground laboratory is a gloomy place; it is said to contain documents that unlock the secrets of the Zone, but most likely it is just some documentary junk. It lies on the lower levels of the laboratory, there, according to rumors, the whole piles of documents that once did not have time to burn. And, of course, there are some of the darkest representatives of the dungeons - burers and bloodsuckers ... Almost no one has ever seen dwarfs, they say that they can't cope with ordinary weapons, bullets bounce off.... Here, and kind of throw heavy cobblestones and metal armatures with the help of strange forces. And a lot of stalkers died in this lab...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l08u_brainlab">
		<text>Lab X-16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l08u_brainlab_description">
		<text>Secret non-government laboratory located in the Yantar location. There are a lot of zombified people on the territory of the complex. In the center of the underground complex is a psi installation, the basis of which is an artificially grown brain of considerable size. The installation in X-16 was built as a prototype emitter after successful research and experiments with test subjects in X-18 to study the psi-field.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l10u_bunker">
		<text>Lab X-10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l10u_bunker_description">
		<text>The Rainbow Aggression Suppressor (also known among stalkers as the Brain Burner, Radar or Woodpecker) is a psychotronic installation located in the control bunker of the old antenna system and connected directly to them. Apparently it is a development of the same theme that created the Kaimanov Radiator. At first it was used for experiments on working with noosphere, later it was re-equipped to prevent access of outsiders to Pripyat and Chernobyl NPP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12u_sarcofag">
		<text>Sarcophagus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12u_sarcofag_description">
		<text>The interior of the fourth unit of the Chernobyl nuclear power plant destroyed by an explosion in 1986. Radiation hell, boiling for decades, where no man in his right mind would even think of sticking his nose in. Except for stalkers, of course, although whether they have a sane mind is an open and very debatable question. Somewhere here, inside, stands the legendary Monolith, which fulfills wishes - the object of every stalker's dreams.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12u_control_monolith">
		<text>Monolith control</text>
	</string>
	<string id="l12u_control_monolith_description">
		<text>But really, Monolith is just a program that creates the illusion requested by the stalker. Nothing actually happens to the stalker, he enters a state of happiness and euphoria due to the psi waves sent by the installation. Because of this, you can notice the ecstasy and detachment of monoliths when there is no enemy nearby, they are immersed in their inner world of fantasies come true, also they do not moan when wounded. In general, the main purpose of the Wish Maker is to distract people, being the last barrier for those who get too close to the O-Consciousness scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Hunter_tips">
		<text>Zakharych's caches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="find_kolya">
		<text>Find Kolya the stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kolya_locator">
		<text>Location of Kolya.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
