<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
<string id="Transmut">
	<text>Transmutes</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_1">
	<text>"Sky"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_1">
	<text>In its outward appearance the artifact resembles the "Jellyfish". There is a theory that it is in fact a "Jellyfish", which has been subjected to a powerful electric field. Due to its new attributes, the artifact greatly increases the muscle tone of the bearer, boosting tear, rupture and hit resistance. Highly radioactive.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Night Star", "Moonlight", "Battery".</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_2">
	<text>"TdW"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_2">
	<text>TdW - Triumph des Willens. Heightens the psi-emission immunity. Due to its great effectiveness, the artifact is highly demanded.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Moonlight", flesh's eye.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_3">
	<text>"Capricorn horn"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_3">
	<text>This fancifully shaped artifact may seldomly be found in areas with high gravitational activity. The effect of the artifact is in curvature of the gravitational field around the living being, with which it must be in direct contact. The field's flexure influences all high-velocity particles, whatever their dimensions are, slowing them down. Thus the artifact may be used for protection against bullets and blast waves.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Night Star", "Mama's Beads", "Gravi", "Droplets".</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_4">
	<text>"Hermes" (aka "Fleecer")</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_4">
	<text>Some call it "Hermes" in honour of the swift messenger of the gods, while the others name it "Fleecer" for the artifact's side effect. The artifact boosts the bearer's metabolism, allowing him to move longer without fatigue, meanwhile incinerating his tissues.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Moonlight", "Plasma Cactus", "Slime".</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_5">
	<text>"Sponge"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_5">
	<text>The artifact represents a porous structure, which absorbs radiation and heat. It is very helpful against both outer emission and the one caused by contaminated particles in the body. Also protects against high temperatures.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Mica", "Shell", "Fireball".</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_6">
	<text>"Honeycomb"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_6">
	<text>The artifact is generated by several combined hollow organic formations. It emits a gaseous substance, able to neutralize the negative influence of numerous toxins on human organism.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Pellicle", "Wrenched".</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_7">
	<text>"Red Star"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_7">
	<text>Due to unique amalgam of the artifacts and specimen of bloodsucker's tissues (which display impressive regeneration abilities), the artifact promotes faster health restore and wound healing.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Soul", "Mica", bloodsucker's tissues pattern.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-transmut_8">
	<text>"Eye"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-transmut_8">
	<text>This artifact is formed of organics being subjected to powerful psi-impact. It has never been found anywhere but the lake Yantar region. It noticeably boosts the organism's metabolism, thus promoting faster wound healing and increasing the bearer's endurance. Also, the "Eye" emits specific psi-aura, which supresses snorks' and burers' aggression towards the artifact's owner.
Prolonged exposure to the aura may lead to nervous breakdowns and epilepsy episodes. Sustained use is not recommended.\n\nNecessary ingredients: "Goldfish", "Mica", controller's hand.</text>
</string>

<!-- klondike artifacts -->
<string id="af_klondike_1_name">
	<text>"Zombie-Volt"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_1_name">
	<text>Artifact, that exists only in tales for the Zone. Allegedly, zombies can wear that kind of artifacts which allows them to walk through electric anomalies without any harm. How it can be formed, how zombies can wear artifacts or why nobody ever found it - there are no answers in tales, so artifact existance is doubtful.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_2_name">
	<text>"Moebius"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_2_name">
	<text>First touch on artifact causes hallucinations and nausea, but not for long. It protects from psy attack, but people say that it could turn human into zombie. However, maybe this is just envy talks....</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_3_name">
	<text>"Inferno"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_3_name">
	<text>Force field, formed by the spyral parts of Inferno, unpredictably changes bullet trajectories around artifact host. The huge money that faction leaders offer for artifact, is still not worth it, considering the enormous bonus it gives during fight. Money is paper and life is only one.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_4_name">
	<text>"Triple"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_4_name">
	<text>Smells like "Triple" cologne and it might be good for stalkers, who didn't shower in months. Possibly it was an actual cologne bottle that experienced Zone's anomal affection and in this case this artifact is extremely rare. It can protect its host from "Fruit Punch" and "Burnt Fuzz" impact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_5_name">
	<text>"Mandarin"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_5_name">
	<text>It was assumed that this artifact is another fable for romantics of the Zone: allegedly, someone already have found these artifacts, but they appeared very fragile and fell to pieces after touch. It turns out that the fable can become true: this specimen is solid. Cost of artifact is much higher, than that for other hit protection artifacts because of its improved protection parameters.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_6_name">
	<text>"Gold burr"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_6_name">
	<text>Platinum plexus with bright yellow glow inside. Origin is unknown, temperature of the artifact is low, so don't touch it with bare hands.	It seems there is gold inside. Apparently, gold can be extracted from the artifact, but who can destroy such a beautiful thing which is more valuable than gold and can protect you from thermal impact?!</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_7_name">
	<text>"Watermelon crust</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_7_name">
	<text>Stalkers fantasize that one can obtain this artifact if he drops watermelon crust in "Vortex". Because of the absence of watermelons in the Zone it's difficult to verify this tale. Artifact is constantly moist, covered with liquid that accumulates radiation from the host organism.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_8_name">
	<text>"Fitting"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_8_name">
	<text>Theoretical possibility of artifact existance was described by professor Kruglov in his paper. This artifact apparently can be formed as a result of extremely rare events, when anomaly appears not on the surface, but in something. In this case - in concrete block or even in wall. Kruglov assumed that strong gravitational impact can tore material apart and those frags that got into the anomaly can gain properties which are opposite to anomaly impact. That paper was sensational, but there are no practical confirmation.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_9_name">
	<text>"Il'ich's testaments"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_9_name">
	<text>Melted piece of stone, similar to granite. Legend, that is told by veterans, claims about outstanding miracle power of the anomalies, formed near Lenin's monument in Pripyat. It seems to be true: artifact is heavy and there is no granite in the Zone except in Prypiat. Artifact increases the endurance of its host, so the always brisk and vigorous Vladimir Il'ich is definitely involved...</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_10_name">
	<text>"Sevenbolt"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_10_name">
	<text>Seven bolts, throwed in anomaly, may cause something like this artifact. It's known that bolts can get special properties while being in anomalies, but no one ever achieved this intentionally. 	This artifact can increase endorphin production which leads to better mood and, as a consequence, higher health.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_18_name">
	<text>"Green Gray"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_18_name">
	<text>This artifact is paradoxical like all in the Zone. It seems fragile, but can protect you from cuts and tears. Keep an eye on it: every stalker, that plans to go through undergrounds, will try to steal it while you're sleeping, because artifact can't be bought or found.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_19_name">
	<text>"Galaxy"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_19_name">
	<text>Very very unusual artifact even for the Zone. Scientists sugget that those artifacts may be formed in "Electro" as a result of total discharging and collapsing. But "may" isn't "is", there are no known specimens, so don't waste your time sitting near "Electro".</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_20_name">
	<text>"Dynamo"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_20_name">
	<text>Wonderful object: rotation of spikey inner matter in the sphere impacts walking. Being put on belt in "forward" direction it helps to walk, "reverse" direction causes extensive loss of power. Second mode is cleary never used by any stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_21_name">
	<text>"Blue blende"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_21_name">
	<text>Every stalker likes this artifact for something: someone likes its soft blink light, someone adores its calm unstoppable rotation, someone admires its wonderful design... But that's not the point. There are good news for pragmatic stalker minds also. Being put on belt it confuses the controller during his attack: fast multidirectional rotation of two spheres around the fixed one can cause an illusion of blood moving in controller's head. So he splits his attack between two objects and artifact host suffers only half of controller's psy power.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_klondike_22_name">
	<text>"Alive malachite"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_af_klondike_22_name">
	<text>Something that was made from malachite, but became a strange spyral with cyan inner surface after Zone's impact. Its rotation can't be stopped so prepare some space in pocket. It's uncomfortable to use but if you like your feet, better have it with you when you step in "Fruit Punch" - artifact provides best chemical protection ever. It also creates an illusion of living moving creature on the belt which gives you something special - optimism and good mood!</text>
</string>

</string_table>