	<string id="cit_doctor_task">
		<text>Stash in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_task_0">
		<text>Find Strelok's hiding place in Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_task_1">
		<text>Get to the hotel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_task_2">
		<text>Find the room with the cache</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_task_3">
		<text>Inspect the cache</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="deadcity_vault_mark">
		<text>Bar and "Shelter"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mg_too_much_psi">
		<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Damn, the radiation is too strong, my protection is not enough to go down there. It's necessary to talk with the colonel, he may be able to think of something.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mg_trader_come_in_day">
		<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Holy shit, Strelok, is that you? For nearly a month your PDA's signal didn't register on the network, we thought you were dead. Reach us if you can, we've got serious problems. Catch the mark on the map. Try to get to us before dusk, at night the city is deadly! We turn on the siren for 20 minutes before closing the door.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mg_trader_come_in_night">
		<text>%c[100,50,250,50]Holy shit, Strelok, is that you? For nearly a month your PDA's signal didn't register on the network, we thought you died. Reach us if you can, we've got serious problems. Catch the mark on the map. But don't go through the City at night, it's deadly!%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_first_enter_quest_str">
		<text>Holy shit, Strelok, is that you? For nearly a month your PDA's signal didn't register on the network, we thought you died. Reach us if you can, we could really do with your help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_name_quest_str">
		<text>Owner of the Dead City</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_name_quest_descr">
		<text>Bosun and Prokhorov told me about what had happened to the expedition. The colonel says that everything that happens in the City is because - of an entity, Master, this creature lives under the city and drives people insane. It may be of course just delirium caused by the Colonel having received a high dose of radiation, but I should at least investigate. After all, something is causing the radiation in the City, and is nearly stronger than the radiation at the Yantar factory. Three of the nine missing scientists have the necessary data, but what exactly - is not clear.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_master_p1_quest_str">
		<text>Find the bodies of the scientists and read the data on their PDAs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_data_part_found">
		<text>%c[100,50,250,50]You found part of the triangulation data on this scientist's PDA.%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_all_data_part_found">
		<text>%c[100,50,250,50]You found the last part of the triangulation data on this scientist's PDA. The data is not encrypted and is available for use immediately.%c[default]</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_master_p2_quest_str">
		<text>Find the den of the Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_p3_quest_str">
		<text>Kill the Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_logovo_quest_str">
		<text>Find a way to enter the lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_logovo_quest_descr">
		<text>According to the data removed from the scientist's PDAs, a very strange picture emerges. It seems that there is another prototype of the biological emitter, similar to what is at Yantar. Apparently, it was transported here through the underground tunnels connecting the laboratories. However, if it is - how can it work? After all, it's not connected to anything. Another mystery... I found the entrance to some dungeon, clearly the radiation source is inside, but I can't enter, the level of radiation is such that my protective helmet can't cope with it. We need to come up with a solution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_logovo_label">
		<text>Lair of the Master</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_logovo_mark">
		<text>Somewhere in there, according to the data from the scientist's PDA, is a source of radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_logovo_short_quest_str">
		<text>Infiltrate the lair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_tell_colonel_quest_str">
		<text>Talk with Prokhorov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_colonel_reward_str">
		<text>Collect your reward</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_scout_logovo_quest_str">
		<text>Explore the lair of the Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_scout_logovo_quest_descr">
		<text>The colonel is not as silly as he looks. Now I understand why he was appointed head of security for the scientific expedition. This soldier managed to modify Sakharov's protective psi helmet, making it universal. Now I can enter the dungeon and explore it to find the source of radiation and figure out how to turn it off.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_scout_logovo_short_quest_str">
		<text>Scout the den</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_return_colonel_quest_str">
		<text>Back to Prokhorov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_make_bomb_quest_str">
		<text>Craft a thermite bomb</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_make_bomb_quest_descr">
		<text>In the cave under the city, I found something disgusting. Something of nightmares. It seems that the second prototype of the biological emitter was much more powerful than the first, and thus it kept consciousness. Apparently he took control of the workers in the underground transportation hub, came out of his flask, he survived, probably due to water flooding the tunnels, developed, and now purposefully crushes the City with his radiation. Apparently, he leads zombies into its tunnels, causing them to drown, and then feeds on  the soluble substances their bodies slowly secrete into the water. This creature must be destroyed, and the Colonel has a plan how to do it. A thermite bomb will quickly turn this abomination into rich broth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_worker_log_name">
	    <text>Transport hub employee's log</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_master_worker_log_descr">
		<text>I... I'm recording this for those who may one day find us, to let them know, what happened here, so they won't have need to venture forward. In general, we've had a biological accident occur. At the moment it seems that I'm the only survivor, and again, it looks like it won't be for long. Damn thing. Kaymanov's emitter is lousy. Fuck Lebedev's group, the bastards. They gave us this monster. He wasn't supposed to have self-realization! So, I have to pull myself together, shit... In general, the following happened: Kaymanov sent us another prototype emitter for preservation but we sent it for recycling. Structurally, it's a brain... Well, not quite a brain, but in general it's a biological structure of human neurons. It lives, but does not think. At least it never thought, not once. It looks like this neural network was able to collect a sample of the structure of internal communications, sufficient to ensure that it had a consciousness. In general, everything became clear, that is, he understood what they were going to do with him. When it was brought here to us, we all felt a slight headache. No one in particular paid any attention, because everyone thought they were the only one. Well, in general, we all began to work quietly. About an hour later, some of the boys noticed that a couple of the employees who worked directly with the container, started to behave in a strange way. For some reason they began to unscrew the cover of the main gate valve of the capsule. The boys tried to stop them, they got up close ... and oddly they fell down, then got up and began to help them! I watched all this through a video surveillance system from here, in the control room. While three workers unscrewed the capsule cover, a couple more opened the gates valves of the drainage system, then the hall began filling with water. I tried to contact the task force security, but for some reason I could not pick up the phone. My hands would not obey. And then ... they unscrewed the lid. It splashed into the water, it was already waist-deep there. It turned out he wasn't a bad swimmer, I don't know how he could do it without limbs. Actually, it climbed on the back of one of the guys and penetrated him with some appendage. God, he screamed, how he screamed. I thought I would go crazy with this screaming. I panicked and tried to escape, but I couldn't - I think this thing did something to my brain. Wherever I went, I always came back here, to my post, I have tried to go into the tunnel, trying to get out through the emergency exit. I go, I go, I turn - my post. I can't go anywhere, it doesn't let me, this is it. And it is calling me. The farther I go, the louder I hear his voice in my head. For the present I can resist, the force has come to an end, but I don't know how much longer ... RECORDING INTERRUPTED</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_find_magnesium_quest_str">
		<text>Find the landing gear rim</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_find_aluminium_quest_str">
		<text>Find a large sheet of aircraft skin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_bring_to_colonel_quest_str">
		<text>Bring ingredients to Prokhorov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_wait_bomb_quest_str">
		<text>Wait for the bomb assembly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_take_bomb_quest_str">
		<text>Pick up the finished bomb from Prokhorov</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="chinook_layer_desc">
		<text>A large piece of panelling of the helicopter. It consists mainly of duralumin, an aluminium alloy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chinook_layer_name">
		<text>A piece of helicopter skin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chinook_wheel_desc">
		<text>Heavy landing gear wheel from the cargo helicopter. In theory, it should be made of magnesium alloy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="chinook_wheel_name">
		<text>Helicopter wheel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bidon_bomb_desc">
		<text>A heavy sealed can of thermite mixture with a primitive fuse. The mixture is able to burn through a concrete slab. It's fair to say that it is better to be as far away as possible from the can at the moment of detonation. The installed delay fuse is for two and half minutes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bidon_bomb_name">
		<text>Thermite bomb</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_kill_the_master_quest_str">
		<text>Kill the Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_kill_the_master_quest_desc">
		<text>The bomb is ready, it only remains to put it in place and activate it. Don't forget to get out of there quickly, you only have two and half minutes. I hope this will be enough time to leave the den. Let's see how the Master enjoys his warm greeting.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_bomb_master_quest_str">
		<text>Activate the thermite charge as close as possible to the Master</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_escape_logovo_quest_str">
		<text>Leave the den before the charge explodes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_escort_colonel_quest_str">
		<text>Escort Prokhorov to the checkpoint at the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_escort_colonel_quest_str_short">
		<text>Escort Prokhorov to the checkpoint</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_escort_colonel_quest_desc">
		<text>The Master is destroyed, one less problem in the Zone and it has become a little safer. Now I need to help the Colonel reach the Cordon, clearly he cannot do it alone. I hope I don't become trapped by my altruism. However, the Colonel has promised a decent reward, we'll see, maybe it's not been in vain.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="deadcity_colonel_survive_quest_str">
		<text>The Colonel must survive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_timer_str">
		<text>Time until detonation</text>
	</string>	