<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!--Transport-->
	<string id="Vehicles">
		<text>Transport</text>
	</string>

<!--Niva-->	
	<string id="Niva">
		<text>Niva 2121</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_niva">
		<text>Passenger car with increased off-road performance.\n
Trunk load: 60 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>

<!--btr-70-->
	<string id="btr-70">
		<text>BTR-70(z)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_btr-70">
		<text>An armored personnel carrier, used by army detachments in the Zone for patrolling. Has almost nothing common with the primary prototype. Has strengthened armour, thermal aiming and image identification module, electronic aiming and barrel stabilization systems. The hull has been made airtight, all analogue controls have been replaced with actuator systems. The APC is fully operable by a single person and allows aimed fire to be carried on by means of an integrated gun. There's still room for a landing party. \n
Trunk load: 100 kg.\n
Items required for use: very heavy accumulator battery, plenty of fuel.</text>
	</string>

<!--mi-24-->
	<string id="mi-24">
		<text>Mi-24 helicopter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_mi-24">
		<text>An army assault helicopter.\n
Capacity: eight paratroopers with weapons, ammunition and equipment.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>

<!--Kamaz-->
	<string id="Kamaz">
		<text>KAMAZ truck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_kamaz">
		<text>A commonly used Soviet truck. Big and reliable.\n
Capacity: the driver, his friends and damn plenty of stuff.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>

<!--Traktor-->
	<string id="traktor">
		<text>Traktor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_traktor">
		<text>Abandoned machinery found its use in the Zone. Has great rough-terrain performance, but grouses a lot.\n
Trunk load: 40 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>

<!--Moskvich-->
	<string id="Moskvich">
		<text>Moskvich 2141</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_moskvich">
		<text>A passenger vehicle. In spite of its disadvantages was quite popular with the summer residents. Was also frequently used by the police.\n
Trunk load: 60 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Moskvich2">
		<text>Moskvich 412</text>
	</string>

<!--Zaporozhets Gorbatiy-->

	<string id="Zaporozh_gorb">
		<text>ZAZ 965 ("humpback")</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_zaporozh_gorb">
		<text>Aka "zaporozhets" - a transport loved by everybody and glorified in an enormous amount of jokes. Has adequate rough-terrain performance and a wonderful antitheft protection: "Hell no, man, I ain't gonna steal this piece 'a shit!"\n
Trunk load: 40 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel, strong hands to push this rust forward.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--Zaporozhets Ushastiy-->
	<string id="Zaporozh_ush">
		<text>ZAZ 968 ("lop-eared")</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_zaporozh_ush">
		<text>By no means less popular in the jokes descendant of the "humpbacked", produced by the Zaporozhsky Car Factory.\n
Trunk load: 40 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel, something to push this rust forward (hands or legs, depending on the degree of disability of the owner).</text>
	</string>

<!--UAZ-->	
	<string id="Uaz">
		<text>UAZ 469 ("goatling")</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_uaz">
		<text>Product of the Uralsky Car Factory. A reliable "goatling". Proved itself good in the army use.\n
Trunk load: 80 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--UAZ Buhanka-->
	<string id="Uaz_buh">
		<text>UAZ 3962 ("brick")</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_uaz_buhanka">
		<text>A reliable minivan with remarkable flotation.\n
Trunk load: 100 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--Baggi-->
	<string id="Baggi">
		<text>Buggy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_baggi">
		<text>Handmade of metal scrap. It's fast, cheap and allows all-round fire. Has got no armour.\n
Trunk load: 40 kg.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel and nitrous oxide if you happen to find it.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--ZIL MMZ-->
	<string id="Zil_MMZ">
		<text>ZIL MMZ truck</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_zil_mmz">
		<text>These trucks have gained themselves an ill fame in the Zone - they are mostly known as "Death trucks".\n
Capacity: it's very doubtful that anybody ever counted the dead bodies in the trunk.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--GAZ66-->
	<string id="GAZ66">
		<text>GAZ 66 truck ("shishiga")</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_gaz66">
		<text>Russian pronunciation of the number of the hull (66) gave this truck its nickname - "shishiga", which means an evil wood goblin female. A reliable truck with nice off-road performance. It's almost a house with wheels.\n
Capacity: great.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>
	
<!--GAZ53-->
	<string id="GAZ53">
		<text>GAZ 53 bus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_vehicles_gaz53">
		<text>A bus based on the GAZ-53 truck.\n
Capacity: great.\n
Items required for use: heavy accumulator battery, fuel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_veh_health">
		<text>Condition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_trunk_max_weight">
		<text>Max weight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_trunk_weight">
		<text>Loaded</text>
	</string>
	<!--Описания машин на продажу-->
	<string id="uaz2_esc_sidor_desc">
		<text>We can deliver Goat to Escape. Shabby, but can move. You can pick it in ATP in garage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskvich_garb_sidor_desc">
		<text>Got Moskvitch 412. It is in abandoned car camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uaz_garb_sidor_desc">
		<text>There is a UAZ in Garbage. It'll be near the ruins, close to the Duty checkpoint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uaz_agr_sidor_desc">
		<text>Can deliver a Goat. You can get it near the railroad tunnel.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="niva_agr_sidor_desc">
		<text>Maybe Niva. You can find it there... On the road near the exit of insitute...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="uazbuhanka_dv_sidor_desc">
		<text>We can deliver Brick to Dark Valley. Dangerous place. It'll be on gas station near Borov base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="niva_bar_sidor_desc">
		<text>There will be Niva in Bar. Near the road against tanker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zaz_jantar_sidor_desc">
		<text>There is Humpbacked on Yantar! Little and unreliable! Go get it! You'll see it when arrive to valley!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="baggi_mil_shur_desc">
		<text>Want Buggy? If you do, pick it right near the exit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="moskvich2_mil_shur_desc">
		<text>I can deliver Moskvitch to you. In bloodsucker village... An you can hunt there, he-he.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zaz968_rad_shur_desc">
		<text>There was something on Radar... I don't know what is there but it yours now. We'll deliver it to monolith blockpost. Full service.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

