<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_fmj_short">
		<text>.45 ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_fmj_descr">
		<text>.45 caliber shell rounds has been popular for over a hundred years. A heavy bullet with a relatively weak powder charge flies at a slow speed, but has a significant stopping effect.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_hydro">
		<text>ACP Hydroshock Applets .45.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_hydro_short">
		<text>.45 Hydro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_11.43x23_hydro_descr">
		<text>Non-standard rounds type for the .45 ACP caliber is a half shell bullet with an expansive hollow point and a steel core. This combination of semi-axpanded bullets and armor-piercing bullets has all advantages and disadvantages of both types.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.7x28">
		<text>5.7x28 FN rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.7x28_short">
		<text>5.7x28 FN</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.7x28_descr">
		<text>The 5.7x28 (SS190) rounds was developed by Belgian company Fabrique Nationale de Herstal (FN Herstal) specifically for FN P90 submachine gun in mid-1980s. Later this rounds was used in "Five SeveN" pistol. This rounds has higher penetration power than other pistol roundss. The bullet has muzzle velocity up to 716 m/s and is capable of piercing through the vest. The stopping effect of the bullet is three times higher than that of 9x19 mm rounds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_buck">
		<text>Ammo 12x70 shot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_buck_short">
		<text>12x70 dr</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_buck_descr">
		<text> Normal 12-gauge shotgun rounds, 6mm diameter. It has a huge kill and stopping effect at close range. Designed to fire only a smoothbore weapon. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_zhekan">
		<text>Ammo 12x76 Jekan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_zhekan_short">
		<text>12x76 jk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_12x70_zhekan_descr">
		<text>12-gauge shell with a shellless bullet. Usually used for hunting large animals, but it is also suitable for other purposes: its heavy bullet does not penetrate, but actually squeezes the bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_ap">
		<text>5.45x39 mm BP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_ap_short">
		<text>5,45x39 BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_ap_descr">
		<text>Army 5.45x39 mm 7H22 caliber rounds with armor-piercing bullet is used in automatic rifles of many countries - members of Warsaw Pact. Inside the bullet is an armor-piercing carbide core. It is effective against bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_fmj">
		<text>5.45x39 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_fmj_short">
		<text>5,45x39</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.45x39_fmj_descr">
		<text>Caliber 5.45x39 mm 7H10 ammunition with high penetration bullet is used in automatic rifles of many countries - members of Warsaw Pact. Thanks to the reduced recoil impulse and longer range, the bullet provides better accuracy than the old 7.62 mm caliber rounds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_ap_short">
		<text>5,56x45 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_ap_descr">
		<text>NATOV 5.56x45 mm high penetration rounds, known as SS190/M855. Effective against bulletproof vests. Widely used in small arms by armies and special services of Western countries.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_fmj">
		<text>5.56x45 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_fmj_short">
		<text>5,56x45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_5.56x45_fmj_descr">
		<text>NATO small-pulse rounds of 5.56x45 mm caliber, designed for firing in bursts. It is known under the index SS109. Possesses excellent ballistic characteristics.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_fmj">
		<text>7.62x39 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_fmj_short">
		<text>7.62x39</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_fmj_descr">
		<text>Intermediate cartridge with non-protruding edge design by N. M. Elizarov and B. V. Semin</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_ap">
		<text>7.62x39 мм AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_ap_short">
		<text>7.62x39 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x39_ap_descr">
		<text>Compared to the standard type, it has improved penetration characteristics</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h1">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7H1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h1_short">
		<text>7,62x54 7H1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h1_descr">
		<text>Specially designed 7.62 mm sniper rounds. The bullet is equipped with a steel core. Compared to a standard rounds of the same caliber, it has improved ballistic characteristics and increased penetration.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h14">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7H1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h14_short">
		<text>7,62x54 7H1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_7h14_descr">
		<text>Specially designed 7.62 mm sniper rounds. The bullet is equipped with a steel core. Compared to a standard rounds of the same caliber, it has improved ballistic characteristics and increased penetration.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_ap">
		<text>7.62x54 mm PP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_ap_short">
		<text>7,62x54 PP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_7.62x54_ap_descr">
		<text>Expensive standard 7.62mm rounds. Due to its design features it is not suitable for sniper rifles and is used as a weapon for RP-74 machine guns.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_fmj">
		<text>9x18 mm PM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_fmj_short">
		<text>9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_fmj_descr">
		<text>The metallic shell of the bullet of this ammunition is hidden by a steel core and a lead shirt. It has a good stopping effect, but has little effect against bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_pmm">
		<text>9x18 mm PMM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_pmm_short">
		<text>9x18 PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x18_pmm_descr">
		<text>High-pulse chuck designed for PMM pistol (Not suitable for PM pistol due to insufficient strength of the barrel). Maximum pressure in the barrel channel of the gun has increased by 15% with a new rounds. In comparison with a conventional 9x18 mm rounds, the bullet velocity is significantly increased. It is not very effective against bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_fmj">
		<text>9x19 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_fmj_short">
		<text>9x19 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_fmj_descr">
		<text>Standard 9x19mm rounds with shell bullet. It has good ballistic characteristics and at the same time is inexpensive in manufacturing, which caused its wide distribution. It's not effective against bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_pbp">
		<text>9x19 mm JHP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_pbp_short">
		<text>9x19 JHP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x19_pbp_descr">
		<text>Expanded bullet has a high stopping effect and is not prone to ricochets. It is used mainly as a "police" ammunition and in civilian personal protection weapons. It's not very effective against bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_ap">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_ap_short">
		<text>9x39 SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_ap_descr">
		<text>Sound "automatic" rounds SP-6 is equipped with a half shell bullet with partially open core of hardened steel. It requires a silencer to ensure silent firing. Distributed in some countries - members of the Warsaw Pact. Effective against bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_pab9">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_pab9_short">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_9x39_pab9_descr">
		<text>Sonic "sniper" rounds SP-5 is equipped with a bullet with bimetallic shell. The cavity behind the steel core is filled with lead. Requires the use of a silencer to ensure silent firing. Distributed in some Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_gauss">
		<text>Batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_gauss">
		<text>Batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_gauss_descr">
		<text>Энергетические элементы для гаусс-пушки, изготовленные в заводских условиях при помощи высокотехнологичного оборудования.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m209">
		<text>Grenade M433 HEDP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m209_short">
		<text>M433 HEDP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m209_descr">
		<text>Firing for 40mm caliber shell system grenade launchers such as AG36, L123A2 UGL... The radius of the effective shrapnel hit zone is about 5 m.P</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m397a1">
		<text>Grenade M397A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m397a1_short">
		<text>M397A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_m397a1_descr">
		<text>Improved type of shot for 40mm caliber shell system grenade launchers such as AG36, L123A2 UGL... Possesses better ability to hit hidden targets. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_og_7b">
		<text>Firing PG-7VL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_og_7b_short">
		<text>PG-7VL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_og_7b_descr">
		<text>The PG-7VL (L - "Beam", name OkR) shot with the RPG-7V launcher allows you to hit your hiding enemy at a distance beyond the range of the hand grenade throw.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25">
		<text>Grenade AD-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25_short">
		<text>VOG-25P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25_descr">
		<text>Splinter grenade of the GP-25 underbarrel grenade launcher "Fire"; also used in the complex "OC-14 Thunder" and grenade launcher "RG-6". The radius of the effective zone of shrapnel hitting is about 5 m.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25p">
		<text>Grenade AD-25P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25p_short">
		<text>IG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_ammo_vog25p_descr">
		<text>The improved type of underbelly nylon grenades used in Soviet and Russian weapons have a better ability to hit hidden targets.</text>
	</string>	

	<string id="ammo-m208a">
		<text>Grenade HEAB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m208a_s">
		<text>HEAB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m208a">
		<text>HEAB (High Explosive Air Bursting). High-explosive fragmentation grenade with air remote detonation for rifles equipped with electronic sighting modules (XM8, FN2000). With proper skill, it allows you to shoot down air targets.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="ammo_atom">
		<text>Atomic charge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_atom_s">
		<text>ATOMIC</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-atom">
		<text>An atomic charge made in the size of a 40 mm charge for Western-made grenade launchers. It is not known by whom and where it is produced, with the use of what technologies and how it gets to the Monolith group. Use is possible only with rifles equipped with an electronic aiming module.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Ammo">
		<text>Ammunition type</text>
	</string>
    <string id="fuelcan">
		<text>Gas bottle</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bomba">
		<text>Fuel bomb</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bochka">
		<text>Fuel tank</text>
	</string>
    <string id="kanistra">
		<text>Canister</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_kanistra">
		<text>A canister containing something explosive. You can pick it up, put it where you need it and blow it up with a shot from afar.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="dinamito">
		<text>Crate of dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_explosive_bomba">
		<text>An excellent tool for destroying the enemy at a distance. By shooting through this contraption, you can arrange a real mini-apocalypse within a radius of 8 meters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_f1">
		<text>F-1 Grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_f1_descr">
		<text>Handheld defensive grenade; its shrapnel can penetrate medium defensive vests, and the blast wave hits targets within a 7-meter radius. It usually hits stalkers in exchange with the military.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgd5">
		<text>Grenade RGD-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgd5_descr">
		<text>Aggressive hand grenade with small shrapnel radius. The blast wave has a radius of about 5 meters. Often used by stalkers to smoke mutants out of the norm.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgn">
		<text>RGN Grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgn_descr">
		<text>RGN (hand grenade offensive) - antipersonnel shrapnel blast distance. Designed to defeat live force in combat.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgo">
		<text>Grenade RGO</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_rgo_descr">
		<text>RGO (manual defensive grenade) is a hand-held anti-personnel defensive strike and distance weapon. Designed to defeat live force in defensive combat.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_smoke">
		<text>RDG-M smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_smoke_descr">
		<text> Hand smoke grenade. It is intended for installation of a smoke screen. Time of the smoke screen formation - 10 seconds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_flashbang">
		<text>CTS 7290 light-noise grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grenade_flashbang_descr">
		<text>Light-noise grenade made in the USA. Designed to provide light and sound effects on the enemy for temporary psychophysiological (distracting and overwhelming) and mechanical immobilizing action to temporarily disable him.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Misc -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_knife">
		<text>Battle knife OC-04</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_montirovka">
		<text>Crowbar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_montirovka_short">
		<text>Crowbar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_montirovka_descr">
		<text>Simple heavy crowbar which used to belong to a foreigner called "Freeman". The handle is stamped - "Manufactured in Black Mesa, New Mexico, USA"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pipe">
		<text>Lead pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pipe_short">
		<text>Lead pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pipe_descr">
		<text>Probably the most common thing you'd expect to find in the Zone. If you use it properly, you might even be able to bash someone's skull in.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Pistols -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pm">
		<text>PM</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pm_descr">
		<text>The Makarov pistol is the most common pistol in the area, a legacy of the Soviet era, the PM is one of the best representatives of the compact self-defense weapon class. It is small in size, extremely reliable, easy to use and maintain. Its shortcomings include short range and accuracy of fire, low bullet efficiency and - in comparison with modern pistols of the same class - rather large weight with insufficient magazine capacity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pmm">
		<text>PMM-12 "reward"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pmm_descr">
		<text>Makarov modernized gun (GRAU Index - 56-A-125M) - developed in early 1990's. 70% of PMM pistol parts are interchangeable with PM pistol. Barrel frame is reinforced and bolt mass is increased. The PMM pistol is equipped with spiral grooves, which allows to use 9x18 mm PM high pulsed roundss in addition to conventional 9x18 mm PM roundss. The engraving reads: "For successful performance of especially dangerous tasks and the courage and valor shown in it". %c[01,255,128,0]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pb">
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pb_descr">
		<text>Silent PB gun (index 6P9) was developed on the basis of Makarov PM pistol for army intelligence groups and KGB personnel, adopted for service in 1967. The pistol is an integral silencer, and unlike most similar systems, the silencer is made in two parts. This solution allows the pistol to be carried and stored with the silencer front part (nozzle) removed, and the pistol can be quickly installed on the gun before use. Safe for the shooter to fire with the bipod removed, which is important in critical situations. The pistol uses standard 8-round PM magazines.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort12">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort12_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian-made gun, intended mainly for arming law enforcement agencies and security services. Possesses better accuracy of fight in comparison with PMM, reception and capacity of the shop. Mainly falls into the Zone among the scraps widely sold here (mainly early samples with all "childhood diseases"). However, it is in demand among stalkers because of its fairly high combat characteristics.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort17">
		<text>Fort-17</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fort17_descr">
		<text>Ukrainian self-loading pistol for 9x18 mm PM rounds. It is developed and produced by NPO "Fort". The "Fort-17" is a modification of the "Fort-12" pistol with a polymer frame made of fiberglass reinforced impact polyamide, separated by an overlay on the grip (allowing for adjustment of the arrow on the hand) and a "picatinny" fixture for laser designator installation. Fort-12 and Fort-17 pistol magazines are interchangeable, although they have different caps. Fort-12 magazine cover is metal, while Fort-17 is made of plastic. The use of polymers allowed to reduce weight, increase manufacturability and reduce production cost of the gun. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gsh18">
		<text>GSh-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gsh18_descr">
		<text>GSh-18 (GRAU index - 6P54) - Russian pistol, developed in the late 1990s by Tula Instrument Design Bureau. The name was given by the first letters of the names of the designers under whose supervision it was designed (Vasily Petrovich Gryazev and Arkady Georgievich Shipunov) and the number "18", meaning the capacity of the shop. Serially produced since 2001, offered for export. In 2000 GSh-18 was adopted for service by special units of the Ministry of Justice of the Russian Federation, in 2001 - for service by special units and certain categories of employees of the Ministry of Internal Affairs. In 2003, following the results of the competition for a new army pistol capable of replacing the Makarov pistol in service, it was adopted by the Russian army. Since December 2005, it has been on the list of award weapons. In September 2006, it was adopted by the Russian Prosecutor's Office as a weapon for personal protection of prosecutors and investigators.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grach">
		<text>GRACH</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_grach_descr">
		<text>The Yarygin (PJ) pistol, which was presented in 1993 at the competition to replace the PM (Research and Development Program "Grac") pistol that was in service but not fully compliant with modern requirements, became the winner in 2000 and was named MP-443 "Grac". In 2003, under the name "9mm Yarygin pistol" (YA), it was adopted by the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation (AF of Russia). On October 9, 2008, the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs announced the changeover from a Makarov to a Yarygin pistol as a standard weapon. In 2011, mass production of the Makarov pistol was launched for the Russian army.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_stechkin">
		<text>APS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_stechkin_descr">
		<text>9-mm Stechkin automatic pistol (APS, GRAU Index - 56-A-126) is an automatic pistol developed in the late 1940s - early 1950s by designer I.Y.Stechkin and adopted by the USSR Armed Forces in 1951, simultaneously with the Makarov pistol. The APS is intended for arming officers directly involved in combat operations, as well as for soldiers and sergeants of some special units.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_apb">
		<text>APB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_apb_descr">
		<text>Silent version of the famous Stechkin pistol, modified by order of the special forces. Adopted in 1972, 14 years after the production of its progenitor was discontinued. Surprisingly, at the same time, the APB is practically no different from it - only a barrel with a thread for a silencer and a folding butt (unfortunately, lost in this instance) stand out from the significant changes.</text>
	</string>

        <string id="gunsl_wpn_tt33">
		<text>TT-33</text>
	</string>
        <string id="gunsl_wpn_tt33_desc">
		<text>The first Soviet Army self-loading pistol developed in 1930 by Soviet designer Fyodor Tokarev (GRAU index - 56-A-132) to replace the Nagan revolver and several models of foreign-made revolvers and pistols that were in service with the Red Army by mid-1920s. German 7.63x25mm Mauser rounds was adopted as the standard rounds. Later USSR bought a license from German company "Mauser" for rounds production and started production under the designation "7.62mm pistol rounds "P", 1930 issue. In the TT zone it was a big success with gangsters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sr1m">
		<text>SR1MP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sr1m_desc">
		<text>The pistol for special-purpose power units, developed under the research and development program "Grac" by designers of TsNIItochmash P.I. Serdyukov and I.V. Belyaev under the rounds of increased efficiency 9x21 mm rev. 1995. SR1MP is the newest modification, differing in the presence of grooves on the sides of the front part of the frame, to which the Picatinny bar can be attached for mounting various accessories on the weapon: collimator sights, laser designators (LCU) and combat (tactical) lights. Sound suppressor can be attached to SR1MP pistol. In addition, button of automatic grip safety was enlarged. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_beretta">
		<text>BERETTA 92FS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_beretta_descr">
		<text>Guns of this series have a reputation of reliable, though somewhat cumbersome, weapons all over the world and are in service with military and police forces of many countries. They are no less popular with criminals due to their powerful ammunition and capacious magazine. As a rule, not the newest models get into the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_walther">
		<text>WALTHER P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_walther_descr">
		<text>The perfect Western-made pistol with high reliability, large magazine, good combat accuracy and perhaps the best ergonomics in its class. Once in the Zone, it has become one of the most common pistols for both professionals and beginners with money.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_hpsa">
		<text>BROWNING HI-POWER</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_hpsa_descr">
		<text>J. Browning and Didier Sav's first half 20th-century self-loading pistol. Despite its venerable age, the popularity of this model around the world is still very high.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_glock17">
		<text>GLOCK 17</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_glock17_unic">
		<text>GLOCK 17  Unique Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_glock17_descr">
		<text>Austrian pistol developed by GLOCK for the Austrian army. It was the first weapon developed by GLOCK. The pistol proved to be quite successful and convenient to use. Due to its combat characteristics and reliability it became widely used as a civilian self-defense weapon. The pistol design features no fuse or trigger flag. Most of the gun is made of highly durable, heat-resistant plastic. Thanks to this Glock 17 is lightweight and extremely durable. The principle of operation is "snatched and fired", there is no fuse, however, the shot will not be fired without fully pushing the trigger of "safe action".</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_colt1911">
		<text>COLT M1911A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_colt1911_descr">
		<text> An improved model of the gun, which has become a classic automatic weapon and has honorably passed all the armed conflicts of the XX century. Both original and modified versions are still produced by dozens, if not hundreds of manufacturers. The only drawback is the low capacity of the magazine, but to a certain extent this is compensated by a powerful ammo.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220">
		<text>SIG Sauer P220</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220_descr">
		<text>The only remaining model of the world's most popular gun in mass production. This weapon is characterized by excellent ergonomics and excellent combat accuracy. Low magazine capacity is compensated by the powerful rounds and reliability of Swiss watch. No wonder that the pistol is in constant demand among experienced stalkers and mercenaries.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220_nimble">
		<text>SIG Sauer P220R</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig220_nimble_descr">
		<text>A unique model of the CIP-t M200 pistol. It was produced in small batch by order of unknown special unit. This modification is characterized by an enlarged capacity magazine, extra strong steel barrel and polymer barrel cover.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp">
		<text>HK USP Tactical</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp_descr">
		<text>The main features of the German Heckler & Koch USP pistol are the highest reliability and survivability with excellent combat accuracy. Despite some drawbacks (e.g. large size, high center of gravity and massive bolt, which makes it difficult to carry hidden), it is very popular among Zone veterans. USP tactical version has long barrel for silencer installation.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp_match">
		<text>HK USP Match</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_usp_match_descr">
		<text>Sports version of the USP gun. The distinctive feature is the special barrel nozzle (compensator), which reduces the barrel flip when shooting due to the weight. USP Match was discontinued in 1999, a rare specimen in the Zone. It is rumored to belong to a mercenary nicknamed Volkodav.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fiveseven">
		<text>FN Five-seveN USG</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fiveseven_descr">
		<text>Companion pistol to the FN P90 submachine gun, designed and manufactured by the Belgian company Fabrique Nationale of Herstal. The 5.7x28mm rounds for the P90 was developed by FN in early nineties and Five-seveN in late nineties as a pistol using the same rounds. Since its introduction, it has been offered in various commercial versions, most recently as the Five-seveN USG. Low weight, large magazine capacity, powerful rounds and reliability make Five-seveN one of the best guns.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_eagle">
		<text>DESERT EAGLE mark XIX</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_eagle_descr">
		<text>The real "pocket gun" is a large, heavy and extremely high killing power. It was developed as a specialized weapon for hunting medium and large game, as well as for sport shooting silhouette targets at ranges from fifty meters. Due to its price, weight and impressive size, it was not particularly popular in the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_deagle_uniq">
		<text>DESERT EAGLE .50AE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_deagle_uniq_descr">
		<text>The real "pocket gun" is a large, heavy and extremely high killing power. It was developed as a specialized weapon for hunting medium and large game, as well as for sport shooting silhouette targets at ranges from fifty meters. Due to its price, weight and impressive size, it was not particularly popular in the Zone. \n \n %c[01,255,128,0] An unusual modification. The custom-made wooden handle fits well in the palm of your hand, which allows you to better hold the gun and thus improves accuracy. %c[01,255,255,255] </text>
	</string>

<!-- Shotguns -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bm16">
		<text>TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bm16_descr">
		<text>Hunting shotgun is "horizontal." Widely distributed in the ranks of bandits and beginner stalkers. Pretty effective in close combat.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_toz34_descr">
		<text>Widepread vertical hunting shotgun, thanks to sufficient accuracy and good stopping action, provides more reliable protection against mutants than a gun. Very cheap and affordable compared to most weapons, so it is actively used by beginners and bandits on the outskirts of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300">
		<text>"Chaser-13"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
		<text>Smooth-barrel shotgun of western production, which is widely popular due to its reliability and high recharge rate. All parts of this weapon are provided with an anti-corrosion coating.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper">
		<text>"Predator"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper_descr">
		<text>Bespoke pump shotgun is a former St. John's Wort property. The owner's main requirement for this weapon was the ability to shoot the most survivable mutant with a single shot.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12">
		<text>SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12_descr">
		<text>Smooth automatic special purpose shotgun with switchable firing modes. Developed back in the second half of the 20th century, it continues to be used as a universal combat weapon by police and assault units of the army. It is distinguished by high reliability and tactical flexibility. Despite its large mass, sophisticated device and high price, it is quite popular in the Zone as an effective means of fighting against mutants.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12_nimble">
		<text>"Carabiner"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_spas12_nimble_descr">
		<text> Designed specifically for SPSA-14 assault units. Like its "parent", the mechanism provides automatic fire, but kickback compensation in this model is much more effective.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_protecta">
		<text>"Bouncer"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_protecta_descr">
		<text>Smooth shotgun, designed to increase the firepower of special forces of the army and police. Its main advantages are its high capacity and practical speed of fire; the main disadvantages are its impressive size and weight, as well as low reload speed. In the Zone is rare and used mainly for mutant logs cleaning.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_saiga12">
		<text>Saiga 12K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_saiga12_unic">
		<text>Saiga 12K Unique Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_saiga12_descr">
		<text>Samo-shotgun of 12 caliber with folding plastic buttstock based on Kalashnikov assault rifle. Shop for 8 rounds, without adjustable sighting bar. Used to belong to stalker ant.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mr133">
    	<text>MR-133</text>
  	</string>
	
  	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mr133_descr">
		<text>MR-133 - is a Russian smoothbore shotgun, which is used for various types of hunting, sports shooting, security and self-defense. The rifle was developed on the basis of the IZH-81 rifle and has been mass-produced by the Izhevsk Mechanical Plant since 2000</text>
  	</string>

<!-- Sniper -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez">
		<text>VSS "Vintorez"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_tact">
		<text>VSS "Vintorez" Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_descr">
		<text>"Special sniper rifle" is intended for silent and free sniper shooting during special operations, when it is necessary to keep secret the position of the shooter. The rifle is fitted with integrated silencer and optics, and has high armor-piercing and stopping capabilities. Despite its small-capacity magazine, it is highly valued by Stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_nimble">
		<text>"Surf"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">
		<text>It was created for special purpose army units based on the silent Vintar-VS sniper rifle. Compared to the "parent" rifle, it has a reduced rate of fire and increased kill power.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd_descr">
		<text>This type of sniper rifle has been on the market for half a century and since then it has proved to be extremely reliable and easy to handle weapon. In the army it serves mainly to hit distant targets, which can not be reached from the rifle, but stalkers appreciated SVD in many respects for the fact that the bullet from it allows you to penetrate even the thickest skin of the mutant or a good bulletproof vest.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd_nimble">
		<text>"Lynx"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">
		<text>A variant of SVDm-2 sniper rifle, piece by piece. It does not differ externally from the standard model, but in fact shows a much more impressive accuracy to kill ratio.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu">
		<text>SVU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu_descr">
		<text>Sniper Rifle Shortened is a more modern version of SVD sniper rifle, which uses bullpup layout to reduce its size. This rifle has a higher rate of fire at lower mass, and accuracy at short and medium ranges remains approximately the same as the "parent" rifle. Today it is quite well-deservedly popular among the troops and stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu_nimble">
		<text>SVU-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_svu_nimble_descr">
		<text>Sniper Rifle Shortened Automatic - further IED development. A variant with automatic fire mode. Equipped with extremely rare 20 round magazines. Formerly owned by Max, the legendary keeper of the Liberty group.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gauss">
		<text>Gauss gun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_gauss_descr">
		<text>The super-precision high-tech weapon known as "Product No. 62" was developed by designers of secret laboratories within the Zone. Its principle of operation is based on the overclocking of the bullet by a system of electromagnets; the bullet is capable of developing ultra-high speed, which provides an enormous piercing ability. The recoil is insignificant and corresponds to 7.62x54 mm sniper rifle. The latter uses particles of certain artifacts to ensure sufficient power capacity of the batteries. The weapon is equipped with integrated electronic telescope sight with adjustable multiplicity and night vision mode, which is powered by batteries. A mini-computer mount is provided on the left side of the housing, which allows you to monitor the status and characteristics of the weapon. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_umirotvoritel">
		<text>Unknown weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
		<text>Unstudied sample whose mechanism of action has not yet been set. Anyway, the weapon is obviously faulty: pressing the trigger does not produce any result.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Assault -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74u">
		<text>AK-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74u_tact">
		<text>AK-74U Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74u_descr">
		<text>Auto Kalashnikov folding shortened (GRAU Index: 6P26) - a shortened version of the AK74 assault rifle, was developed in the late 1970s and early 1980s for arming crews of combat vehicles, aircraft, gun calculations and paratroopers. It is also used in MIA and security structures due to its small size. Advantages are high mobility, concealed carrying capability and high penetration of the bullet. Shortcomings - short range of sight, low stopping effect of the bullet and the tendency to quickly overheat during heavy firing.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74ub">
		<text>AK-74UB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74ub_descr">
		<text>A folding Kalashnikov folding silent assault rifle (GRAU Index: 6P26) - a shortened version of the AK74 assault rifle, was developed in late 1970s and early 1980s for arming crews of combat vehicles, aircraft, gun calculations and paratroopers. It is also used in MIA and security structures due to its small size. Advantages are high mobility, concealed carrying capability and high penetration of the bullet. Shortcomings are short range of sight, low stopping effect of the bullet and the tendency to quickly overheat during heavy firing. \n \n %c[01,255,128,0] Special-purpose force variant, featuring the replacement of the standard muzzle head with a thread for attaching the silencer. PBS-4 is installed. Standard wood workshops and metal buttstocks are replaced with plastic ones. %c[01,255,255,255]</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74">
		<text>AK-74M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74_tact">
		<text>AK-74M Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak74_descr">
		<text>Automatic model of 1974, with the advent of which the armies of the Warsaw Pact countries began to switch to small caliber and small-pulse ammunition. The massive compensator further reduces the already low recoil, which has a positive impact on accuracy and pile-up in all modes of fire. The upgraded version has several improvements. Equipped with polymer buttstock, which folding to the left side of the receiver, and universal iron sights (dovetail rail), which can be fitted to the left side of the receiver. Thus, the AK-74M replaced four models at once: AK-74, AKS-74N and AKS-74N.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak101_name">
		<text>AK-101</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak101_name_tact">
		<text>AK-101 Tactical Option</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak101_descr">
		<text>A relatively recent development of the world famous arms concern, created to enter the markets of the countries of the North Atlantic Alliance. The main difference between this weapon and the base model AK-74M is a different barrel caliber and the use of standard NATO ammunition.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_an94">
		<text>AN-94 "Abakan"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_an94_descr">
		<text>The modern automatic machine designed to replace the aging AK-74. One of the main features is the ability to fire in 2 bursts of fire with high accuracy (the rate of fire is twice as high as the base one), so that at a distance of one hundred meters both bullets lie in one point. This significantly increases the chances of hitting the target due to the combined stopping and punching action of the bullets.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza">
		<text>"ThunderC14"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_tact">
		<text>"ThunderC14" Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_descr">
		<text>Automatic grenade launcher complex, 70% unified with AKM-74 type automatic rifles (main differences - 9x39 mm caliber, "bullpup" layout scheme and wider opportunities for modernization). Designed for armament of rapid reaction units. Very much appreciated by the military and stalkers for the ability to reliably hit a protected bulletproof vest or located in the shelter of the enemy.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_nimble">
		<text>"Storm"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">
		<text>A prototype of an automatic grenade launcher system, a Russian version of the standard "Grom-S14" designed specifically for the special units operating in the Zone. It differs in the increased capacity of the store.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_val">
		<text>AS "Val"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_val_tact">
		<text>AS "Val" Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_val_descr">
		<text>This weapon was created on the basis of a special sniper rifle "Vintorez" as a silent weapon for special forces. It allows the shooter to fire effectively against an enemy protected by a bulletproof vest without disguising his position. One of the main features is the use of an integrated silencer and 9x39mm roundss with a heavy bullet.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bizon">
		<text>PP-19 «Bizon»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_bizon_descr">
		<text>A submachine gun developed by order of the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs in the early 90s. The design, like many other Izhevsk samples, is based on the components of the Kalashnikov assault rifle, due to which many parts are interchangeable with it. In the process of reworking it for a pistol cartridge, the designers changed the automation scheme for the sake of compactness, and in the PP-19 it works due to the recoil energy of the free shutter. The weapon is equipped with a compact and capacious auger magazine, there is also a dovetail mount for mounting sights.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_p90">
		<text>FN P90</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_p90_unic">
		<text>FN P90 Unique Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_p90_descr">
		<text>FN P90 - Belgian submachine gun (personal self-defense weapon), developed in 1986 - 1987 by FN Herstal. It was developed primarily for tankers and drivers of combat vehicles and vehicles. It has a progressive and comfortable ergonomic design. Especially for the P90 was developed the 5.7x28mm SS190 chuck, which has a high penetration power and low ricochet. The bullet of this rounds has a muzzle velocity of up to 715 m/s and is capable of piercing the titanium/Kevlar armored vest that meets the NATO CRISAT requirements from 200 meters.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5">
		<text>HK MP5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5_descr">
		<text>This submachine gun deservedly enjoys great popularity due to its reliability, easy handling and high firing accuracy. Adopted by army and police units in many countries, it also appeared on the black market and eventually reached the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ump45">
		<text>HK UMP45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ump45_unic">
		<text>HK UMP45 Unique Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ump45_descr">
		<text>Submachine gun, developed in the 1990s as an addition to the HK MP5 submachine gun family. The aim of its creators was a new generation of close combat weapon: large enough and fast enough, but accurate.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5sd">
		<text>HK MP5SD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_mp5sd_descr">
		<text>Silent version with integrated PBS and perforated barrel. Deservedly popular due to its reliability, easy handling and high accuracy. Adopted by army and police units in many countries, it also appeared on the black market and eventually made its way to the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_l85">
		<text>L85A2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_l85_tact">
		<text>L85A2 Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_l85_descr">
		<text>British bull-pup machine. Due to revealed shortcomings and low reliability German company Heckler and Koch received an order for modernization of the automatic rifle. As a result, British army received a significantly modified L85A2 assault rifle. The main advantages are high accuracy of single shot and high upgrade potential. When firing in bursts, the accuracy of the rifle drops dramatically, and the automatic rifle shows a tendency to delay.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_lr300">
		<text>LR-300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_lr300_descr">
		<text>A new step in the development of the famous line of weapons. In fact, the changes only touched the upper half of the receiver with the barrel, gas system and bolt group, which resulted in increased ergonomics and reliability, while the weight, on the contrary, decreased. This rifle features high accuracy in combat, although its high sensitivity to contamination makes it unsuitable for use in difficult conditions.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig550">
		<text>SIG 550</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig550_tact">
		<text>SIG 550 Tactical Option</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig550_descr">
		<text>Representative of a relatively new family of assault rifles. Thanks to its high reliability, precision and ease of use, it is one of the best weapons in its class. It's not common in the Zone and costs a lot of money; it's usually specially ordered by experienced stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552">
		<text>SIG SG-552 Commando</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552_descr">
		<text>A shortened version of the Swiss assault rifle SIG SG-550, designed for special police units. Unlike the SG-550, the return spring acts directly on the bolt carrier rather than on the gas piston rod. Like the base model, the SG-552 is very reliable and accurate, for which it enjoys well-deserved popularity in the security forces of many states, such as SWAT and the British SAS.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552_strelok">
		<text>SIG SG-552 Gunslinger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_sig552_strelok_descr">
		<text>While this copy of the assault rifle was not released yesterday, it is clearly visible that the previous owner treated the gun with care. The rifle was completely overhauled, and its parts were carefully matched to each other, which allowed for some increase in killing power. C" and 16 small crosses were carefully cut out on the buttstock.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_g36">
		<text>HK G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_g36_descr">
		<text>The embodiment of new trends in Western-made automatic weapons: The principle of automatic weapons is not based on a semi-automatic bolt, but on a short stroke of the gas piston. It must be said that the changes were clearly beneficial: this assault rifle is a first-class example of modern weapon - lightweight, reliable and ergonomic.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fn2000">
		<text>FN F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_fn2000_descr">
		<text>This futuristic weapon is a serial-produced automatic grenade launcher of modular design. It is equipped with a 40 mm grenade launcher and a computerized fire control module sights. Despite its external cumbersomeness, it is highly ergonomic, comfortable to fire in all modes and high reliability.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak_alfa">
    	<text>АК-Alpha</text>
  	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak_alfa_tact">
    	<text>АК-Alpha Tactical Option</text>
  	</string>
	
  	<string id="gunsl_wpn_ak_alfa_descr">
		<text>Developed in Israel by Command Arms & Accessories, the AK-Alpha was first shown to the public in 2016. The AK-Alpha assault rifle is an attempt to improve the ergonomics of the Kalashnikov assault rifle while maintaining its main advantages – high reliability and ease of maintenance</text>
  	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_m4">
    	<text>Colt M4A1</text>
  	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_m4_tact">
    	<text>Colt M4A1 Tactical Option</text>
  	</string>
	
  	<string id="gunsl_wpn_m4_descr">
		<text>The Colt M4A1 is an assault rifle created in the USA on the basis of the AR-15 platform for the 5.56x45 NATO cartridge. It was planned to arm the crews of combat vehicles and calculations of equipment, which needed to have weapons of smaller dimensions than regular weapons, but using standard ammunition</text>
  	</string>

<!-- Heavy -->
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pkm">
		<text>RP-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_pkm_descr">
		<text>Manual modification of a belt-fed army machine gun. Despite the high mass and unsatisfactory accuracy of combat, it has found a fairly wide application in the Zone. Mainly used to suppress an outnumbered enemy and when clearing mutant lairs.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rg6">
		<text>"Bulldog-6"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rg6_descr">
		<text>Grenade launcher of the revolver type, in which the drum chambers are formed by six threaded barrels. It is designed to fight against an enemy in hiding and fire in squares; it is also useful when attacking well-guarded objects or in combat with particularly survivable creatures. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_wpn_rpg7_descr">
		<text>Grenade launcher from the 1960s, in huge quantities left in army warehouses, where it got into the Zone. It is a smooth, single-barrel, recoilless type launcher. Its impressive size and heavy weight make it not too common among Stalkers, but due to its enormous destructive power and ease of use, it has found loyal followers in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
<!-- LASTOCHKA -->
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2">
		<text>Scope PSO-1M2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2_descr">
		<text>Optical sight of fixed multiplicity (4 diopters). Varinat PSO-1M2 is intended for long-range combat with SVD and IED sniper rifles. It is installed on the weapon as standard in the Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2_1">
		<text>Scope PSO-1M2-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pso1m2_1_descr">
		<text>Optical sight of constant magnification. The reticle is marked for shooting at medium distances. For ease of aiming in the dark, the sight is equipped with an illuminated reticle, which can be turned on if necessary. Commonly used in conjunction with assault rifles equipped with special attachments in Warsaw Pact nations with dovetail mounts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_4">
		<text>Scope 1PN93-4 Night vision</text> 
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_4_descr">
		<text>Fixed multiplex night sight (4 diopters). Variant 1PN93-4 is intended for combat in poor visibility conditions at long range from SVD sniper rifles, IEDs... Standard dovetail mount is used for installation on weapons in countries-participants of the Warsaw Pact.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_1">
		<text>Night sight 1PN93-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_1pn93_1_descr">
		<text>Fixed multiplex night sight (4 diopters). Variant 1ПН93-1 is designed for fighting in poor visibility conditions at medium range with Kalashnikov, АН-94, АС, VSS... The "swallow's tail" type fixture, which is standard in the Warsaw Pact countries, is used for installation on weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kashtan">
		<text>Scope 1P78-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kashtan_descr">
		<text>Telescopic sight 1П78-1 with 2.8 multiplicity is intended for aiming at medium range from weapons with side-firing position, such as Kalashnikov automatic rifles, AN-94, VSS, AS VAL...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_cobra">
		<text>Scope "Cobra" </text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_cobra_descr">
		<text>Cobra collimator sight (variant of ECP-1C-03) provides aiming in natural light conditions (bright sunny day, deep twilight and lunar night) due to 16 levels of manual brightness adjustment of the sight mark. The weapon is fitted with a standard dovetail mount in the Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pka">
		<text>Scope PC-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pka_descr">
		<text>The collimator sight PK-A is designed to point an automatic firearm at the target in all light conditions. It is mounted on automatic rifles with "Dovetail" type mounts.</text>
	</string>

<!-- PICCATINY -->

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_susat">
		<text>Scope SUSAT</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_susat_descr">
		<text> The SUSAT four-time telescope sight was developed in the UK at the Royal Centre for Arms Research and Development. It is produced by Avimo as well as by United Scientific Instruments. It is most often used to aim light small arms at medium and long ranges. It is mounted on a special mount for the L85 "Dovetail", and also comes with an adapter bracket for mounting the sight on the "Picatinia Plank" type mount. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_aimpoint">
		<text>Scope Aimpoint CompM4s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_aimpoint_descr">
		<text>Closed collimator sight from Swedish company Aimpoint AB. Designed for accurate shooting at short and medium range. Mounted on a "Picatinia Lath" type mount.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kemper">
		<text>Scope Firefield Kemper XL-M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_kemper_descr">
		<text>Kemper XL-M is a panoramic open collimator sight, ideal for high-tempo shooting, offhand shooting and shooting at moving targets. Mounted on a "Picatinia Lath" type mount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_eotech">
		<text>Scope EOTech XPS3-0</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_eotech_descr">
		<text>Holographic scope from American company EOTech. Model XPS3-0 is smaller than other holographic sights, but it is not inferior in speed and functionality. Mounted on a "Picatinia Lath" type mount.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_elcan">
		<text>Scope Elcan Specter DR 1x/4x</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_elcan_descr">
		<text>Optical sight from Canadian company ELCAN Optical Technologies with variable multiplicity (1 and 4 diopters). It is mounted on a "Picatinia Lath" type mount. Optical sight from ELCAN Optical Technologies.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pn23">
		<text>Scope night PN-23</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pn23_descr">
		<text>Small-sized night sight from Russian refinery company (Novosibirsk Instrument-Making Plant) with fixed multiplicity (3 dioptres). It is mounted on a mount of "Picatinia Plank" type.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_acog">
		<text>Scope Acog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_acog_descr">
		<text>ACOG stands for Advanced Combat Optical Gunsight and belongs to the family of optical sights manufactured by Trijicon. This instance with a USMC reticle and a multiplicity of 3.5 x is mounted on a picatini bar mount.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_leupold">
		<text>Scope Leupold Mark 8 CQBSS 1.1-8x24</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_leupold_descr">
		<text>The Leupold Mark 8 1.1-8x24 optical sight is a universal device with a wide range of multiplicities. The model is perfect for shooting at short distances, but you should not label the "corral" sight, since it is quite a well-off sight for accurate shots at medium distances.</text>
	</string>

<!-- Other scopes -->
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_rakurs">
		<text>Sight of PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_rakurs_descr">
		<text>Telescopic Wide-angle View-PM increases the effectiveness of direct fire (up to 400 m) on moving and stationary targets. The variant (PM) is intended for installation on Weaver bar.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pu">
		<text>Scope PU 3,5x22</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pu_descr">
		<text>Hunting sight with a multiplicity of 3.5 for hunting weapons with a bracket for mounting on the TOZ-34.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pgo7v">
		<text>Scope PGO-7B</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_pgo7v_descr">
		<text>Soviet telescopic sight developed at Tochpribor Central Design Bureau to increase accuracy of fire from RPG-7, RPG-7B, RPG-7D hand grenade launchers... </text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_po4x34">
		<text>Optical sight PO 4x34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_scope_po4x34_descr">
		<text>Soviet four-fold optical sight, designed for use at medium distances. It is distinguished by its simple design and unpretentiousness in operation, although due to the small number of adjustments it is not particularly popular among snipers. It is included in the standard delivery set of the OTs-14 Groza automatic grenade launcher and is most often used in tandem with it.</text>
	</string>

<!-- SILENCERS -->

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_pb">
		<text>PBS (NASADCA) for PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_pb_descr">
		<text>The front part of the integral silencer (nozzle) of the PB pistol is 9x18mm caliber. Incompatible with other weapons. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_m4_2000">
		<text>PBS for caliber 5,56x45mm AAC M4-2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_m4_2000_descr">
		<text>Silencer for automatic rifles and carbines of 5.56x45mm caliber. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_apb_silencer">
		<text>PBS for 9x18mm caliber for ADB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_apb_silencer_descr">
		<text>Silencer for 9x18mm LPG. Incompatible with other weapons. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_svd">
		<text>TGP-B for SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_svd_descr">
		<text>Muffler-plumber tactical for SVD sniper rifle. Incompatible with other weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_tgpa">
		<text>PBS for caliber 5,45x39mm TGP-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_tgpa_descr">
		<text>Muffler-type tactical silencer for 5.45-mm AK series machines.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_colt_p220_silencer">
		<text>BS under caliber .45ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_colt_p220_silencer_descr">
		<text>Advanced Armament Corp. BLACK BOX .45 - Silent firing device for .45ACP pistols.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon12">
		<text>Sound moderator Hexagon 12K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon12_descr">
		<text>Shooting Sound Moderator from Hexagon for Carbines and 12-gauge shotguns</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon">
		<text>Sound moderator Hexagon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_hexagon_descr">
		<text>Shooting Sound Moderator from Hexagon, designed for weapons of caliber 7,62x39 /7,62x51</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28">
		<text>PBS with 5.7x28mm caliber for P90</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28_descr">
		<text>Silent firing device for the FN P90 submachine gun. Incompatible with other weapons. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28_pistol">
		<text>PBS in 5.7x28mm caliber for Five-seveN</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_57x28_pistol_descr">
		<text>GEMTECH SFN57 - Silent firing device for FN Five-seveN pistol. Incompatible with other weapons. </text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18smg">
		<text>PBS 9mm "Bizon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18smg_descr">
		<text>This silencer is designed for installation on the Bizon family of 9mm submachine guns.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18">
		<text>PBS pistol 9x18 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x18_descr">
		<text>Universal silencer for 9x18 mm pistols. Suitable for most weapons, however, some designs may require special threading on the barrel.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x19">
		<text>PBS for 9x19mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x19_descr">
		<text>Silent firing device for 9x19mm pistols</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x21">
		<text>PBS for 9x21mm caliber for SR1MP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_9x21_descr">
		<text>Silent firing device for SR1MP pistol. Incompatible with other weapons.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_groza">
		<text>Silencer module 9x39 mm "Thunderstorm"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_silencer_groza_descr">
		<text>Silencer module from the delivery set of the OTs-14 Groza automatic grenade launcher. Thanks to the rubber casing, it is possible to use this silencer as a handguard when holding a weapon.</text>
	</string>

<!-- GRENADE LAUNCHERS -->

	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_gp25">
		<text>GP-25 "Fire"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_gp25_descr">
		<text>Single-charge, muzzle loaded grenade launcher for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries. Self-propelled grenade launcher, with manual safety and automatic latching in case of improper installation. The equipment is fitted with VOG-25 and VOG-25P ammunition...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_l123a2">
		<text>L123A2 UGL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_l123a2_descr">
		<text>Grenade launcher appeared in the process of update by HK of L85A1 rifle, after which it acquired the index A2.Heckler and Koch adapted the AG36 to the L85A2, and developed a new stock and slightly different grenade launcher.The grenade launcher uses 40x46mm caliber, which allows it to use a wide range of projectiles such as M433 HEDP, M397A1 and many others.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_m203_descr">
		<text>Modification of the M203 single shot grenade launcher with three inches shortened barrel and Picatinny bar mount. Thanks to the change of the mount, this model has found very wide application all over the world.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_groza">
		<text>ГП-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunsl_addon_gl_groza_descr">
		<text>A grenade launcher module designed to be used in conjunction with the OTs-14 Groza automatic grenade launcher system. Created on the basis of the GP-25 underbarrel grenade launcher, the design of which has undergone a number of changes and improvements. The most significant of these is the single trigger, used for both grenade firing and conventional ammunition firing. Due to the modified scheme of attaching the grenade launcher to the barrel, this module cannot be used with other types of weapons.</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="mil_m202_name">
	<text>M202 "FLASH"</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_m202_desc">
	<text>Le M202 "Flash" est un lance-roquette americain a quatre tubes tirant des roquettes incendiaires. Il a ete concu pour remplacer les lance-flammes de la guerre du Vietnam. La chaleur degagee est bien plus grande que celle du napalm a cause d'un melange a base d'aluminium. La lumiere et la chaleur sont tres intenses et peuvent causer de graves brulures a distance sans contact direct a cause de sa puissance.\n Munitions: \n Roquette "M74".</text>
</string>
</string_table>
