<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>


	<string id="psy_dog">
		<text>Chernobyl dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_psydog">
<text>At first glance one certainly considers this grey specimen to be one of the ordinary pseudodog kind. But it is definitely more than ten times deadlier, as it can generate hordes of it's own phantoms, which inflict unimaginary damage to the victim. The nature of the phenomena remains unknown, because never did any scientists manage to capture a chernobyl dog alive. These beasts have been encountered only within the Brain Scorcher area, but it is quite probable, that way more of the kind inhabit the northern parts of the Zone. Inaccessibility of those parts keep the scientists from researching the dog's mystery, as they can only theorize. It is pure conjecture, that Chernobyl dogs possess the unique psi-ability, which grants them some kind of intellect - that could be a converse effect of the Brain Scorher influence. This is the only possible explanation of the beasts' unique behavior: the dogs circle their victim, generate tens of phantoms and keep aside, watching the killing...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="electrochimera">
		<text>Electrochimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_electrochimera">
<text>Beasts, which mostly inhabit the areas with intense accumulation of electrical anomalies, where they draw additional energy. Are harder to kill and way more dangerous than ordinary chimeras. Have the ability to inflict additional damage by electrical discharges. Plenty rumours and legends cloak the mystery of the beasts' origin in the Zone. Some of those veteran stalkers, who have taken way more than a dozen of deep raids claim, that these mutants appeared after a strange surge a couple of years ago. The few survivors tell about a sudden underground bump in the Brain Scorcher area, followed by enormous electrical discharge from a secret lab. This discharge literally annihilated every living being within the 3 km radius. Only some chimeras survived, having obtained their anomalous attributes as a result of that cataclysm. Soon they got scattered throughout the Zone...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="psy-burer">
		<text>Psi-burer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_psyburer">
<text>Another horrible fiend of the Zone catacombs. This malicious mutant differs from its congeners by a strange psi-aura. Apparently the ability to telepathically scan the environment developed into the power to extort "psi-energy" from its victim. Experienced stalkers, who have encountered the dwarf and managed to escape, tell about severe headache, "old cinema" effect in their eyes and total desorientation. In addition to that, survivors mention sinister sounds they heard during the psi-impact. Some say those sounds are screams for help of the killed stalkers, others insist them to be groans of eternal pain of the pygmy itself, which he transfers to its victim prior to killing...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Zombie_rusty">
		<text>Zombie-kamikaze</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_rusty">
		<text>Nobody can tell for sure, if this phenomenal creature exists or not. The reason for such disarray is the complete absence of material evidence... and eyewitnesses... Since 2010 there exists a rumour, that when approaching the central part of the Zone, Strelok's team saw a group of quckly moving "undead". Those walking (more exactly - "running") corpses exploded upon touching any living obstacle, either a bloodsucker or a rat. After getting in such "contact" neither the prey nor the "hunter" survived. Trying to avoid the trounble, the legendary stalkers decided to take a round way to bypass the zombies, but they didn't succeed... A couple of remaining kamikazes was already approaching them. Luckily, the team managed to shoot them down at a safe distance. Rumours say that Fang have carried a trophy ever since - a hand of one of those mutants. It emitted heat and mysteriously protected the stalker from radiation...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="rusty_name">
		<text>Sakharov's Research Log</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rusty_zombie_research_text">
		<text>...Stalker called "Marked One" has brought a strange object, which does for another stalker's ("Ghost") unbelievable description of "zombie-kamikaze hand".\n Object ID: 75-AF - exploding zombie hand. Anomalous attributes of the specimen are directly associated with the "Burner" anomaly. Alike artifacts of this anomaly, the hand has the ability to protect against radiation. Additionally, it shows healing abilities: it withdraws toxic substances from human body and boosts tissues' regeneration process. Judging upon the research data it can be concluded, that zombie-kamikaze's metabolism is greatly increased. Theoretically, it may be the reason for the ability of the kind to self-explode. The mutants tissues are highly saturated with a variety of sulphuric gases in very unstable state. In combination with the effect of the "Burner" anomaly, the tissues become so extremely flammable, that any disturbance leads to explosive reaction. When is stable state, the substance shows amazing regeneration abilities. In contrast to other zombie species, representatives of this one are really ALIVE, in literal sense. Peculiar structure of the nerve cells testify to the effect that these creatures are able to control the rate of their metabolic processes. Also, they express some kind of collective intellect - one sacrifices its life for the others benefit. It is the only explanation to their suicidal tendencies. These creatures are amazing indeed! Enormous amount of scientific information could have been obtained, had a specimen of the kind been captured alive! But I assume it is impossible in respect of their "explosive temper". I issued the order to transfer the 75-AF sample to the central laboratory for further detailed research. Prof. A.P. Sakharov</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Zombie_plague">
		<text>Plague zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_plague">
		<text>Who said there are no insects in the Zone? It has been considered that way until recent testimony of Fedka Pump, the only survivor from his group. They managed to come very close to the Brain Scorher, where they encounered a strange creature, which they took after an ordinary zombie roving for food at first. Then suddenly they heard a strange hum from that direction, which was very similar to that of buzzing insects. The sound grew louder as the walking dead was approaching. Then within a blink of an eye the sky turned black and hordes of minute vermins swarmed the stalkers all over. They were able to penetrate through armour of any kind. Fedka himself survived only thanks to the totally enclosed suit he had obtained from the ecologists for his good service. The scientists were the first to hear his evidence and they came to conclusion, that the so-called "Plague zombie" became ideal "home" and "transport" for some mutated insects, attracted by decomposing radioactive flesh. Now the vermins keep attacking anything that may imperil their symbiont. They also spread fast among other zombies.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Zombie">
		<text>Civil zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_general">
		<text>The Brain Scorcher strips its victim of mind and reason, leaving only an empty, mindless shell. The brainless bodies then turn into zombies, following only the most basic instincts, wandering aimlessly around the Zone without weapons or clothing. Zombies are little more than sluggish walking corpses, caring only about food and sleep. They eat and drink just about anything they can get their claws on, hence they are virtually soaked in radiation and toxic waste. Usually they roam the Zone without any apparent purpose or just lie corpse-like in abandoned buildings. However, as soon as they sense the presence of a human being, they attack immediately. Experienced stalkers have learned to avoid them if they can.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Zombieg">
		<text>Ghost zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_zombieg_general">
		<text>Nobody can give an explanation to the "ghost zombie" phenomena. These strange creatures are different from common zombies because not only their personality has vanished, but also the corpse. They are more like energy entities, rather than undead. Maybe this also explains their higher vitality...</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Chimera">
		<text>Chimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_chimera_general">
<text>The result of horrible genetic experiments. Can reach up to 1.4 meters in length. Wise, strong and swift cheetah-like beast. Prefers to hide and backstab its victim. Doubled essential organs and systems lead to extreme vitality of this creature, additionally amplified by extraordinary regeneration abilities. The only worthy natural opponents in the Zone are Chernobyl dog and pseudogiant.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Fracture">
		<text>Fracture</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_fracture_general">
<text>Either a result of unknown mutations during some artificial experiments, or the outcome of the Zone's influence to human survivors. Strongly marked hypertrophy of the extremities. Expresses slight psi-abilities. Humanoid outward appearance and the manner to stoop and hide its pseudohand under a cloak give the mutant a look of a vagrant. The creature is artful at attracting stalkers by starting a conversation or asking a question. When the victim turns its back, the mutant stands up and attacks by means of its powerful extremity. Feeds on rats, blind dogs, fleshes. Rare cases show that it can sometimes chase lonely stalkers, attacking them at night.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Burer">
		<text>Burer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_burer_general">
<text>Ugly yellowish pygmies inhabit underground tunnels and catacombs, as their sensitive eyes get blind when exposed to daylight or glare. Often lay ambushes, attacking scientists and stalkers. Their usual tactic is to block all exits by large pieces of garbage, debris and concrete fractions. Killed victims are torn to pieces by the dwarves' strong hands. The burers are at war with the blind dogs. Their vile character and nervous spite lead them to sometimes perform unexpected and savage deeds. The creatures show great premonition and telekinetic abilities. Premonition helps burers to sense the enemy and determine his disposition without any visual contact, and the telekinesis allows them to distantly manipulate rather large objects, throwing them at the opponent, and inflict powerful telekinetic blows directly on the victim. Their abilities, character and intellect place burers in one line with the most dangerous mutants in the dark areas of the Zone.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Cat">
		<text>Cat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_cat_general">
		<text>Some of those cats, which got influenced by the Zone, have survived and gained very dangerous abilities. Are very aggressive.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Blind">
		<text>Blind dog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_blind_general">
		<text>Several generations of the dog species have lived and died since the catastrophe. Each was more affected by the Zone than the previous one. Rapid mutation lead to a vast improvement in previously peripheral abilities, frequently at the expense of primary ones. The most notable biological change was the loss of sight, paired with an uncanny development of smell. As it turned out, blind cubs survived in the Zone as well as normal ones, if not better. As a result, the common dog quickly became extinct in the Zone, giving way to a new breed - that of blind dogs. The animals instinctively identify and avoid anomalies, radiation, and other invisible dangers that plague the Zone. Like their wild ancestors - the wolves - blind dogs hunt in packs. An encounter with a large group of these animals can be dangerous even to an experienced and well-armed stalker.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Bloodsucker">
		<text>Bloodsucker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_bloodsucker_general">
		<text>Experienced stalkers describe this semi-legendary beast as a tall, hunched humanoid with a mess of tentacles where its mouth should be. According to those who saw it and lived to tell the tale, the creature uses its tentacles to cling to the victim's throat, paralyze it, and suck it dry of blood. A dry, mummified shell is all that's left of what used to be a living human being. The most astounding feature of the bloodsucker, however, is its ability to become invisible. Countless dead or missing stalkers are said to have perished in the merciless grip of a bloodsucker. The lucky few who have survived an encounter tell spine-chilling tales of marshes and subterranean areas haunted by the Zone's version of Count Dracula.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Boar">
		<text>Boar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_boar_general">
		<text>A massive, mutated animal, reaching 1.5 meters at the shoulder. The Zone boar's aggressiveness and ability to survive surpass by far those of its relatives outside the contaminated area. Radiation and anomalies left their mark on the physical appearance of the animal as well: its fur is entirely gone in some places, and long and bristly in others. The hooves have evolved into sturdy, sharp claws, the pupils became colorless, and the boar's bald head is marred by pigmentation disorders and deep wrinkles. Zone boars are quite resistant to radiation and can stay in heavily contaminated areas for longer periods of time. They usually charge at their victims, trying to knock them over and then rip them to shreds.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Crow">
		<text>Crow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_crow_general">
		<text>The only bird species to have survived in the Zone, enduring increased radiation levels and effectively avoiding anomalies. While the army pilots need to rely on complex detectors to avoid gravitational disturbances, the crow seems to rely on its own senses for that - a mystery that drives ornithologists and biologists mad. Various theories attempting to explain the phenomenon exist, all of them pointing to a highly specialized development of the bird's brain.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Flesh">
		<text>Flesh</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_flesh_general">
		<text>Like most other living creatures in the Zone, the domestic pig also underwent serious biological changes since the day of the catastrophe. It seems the genes responsible for metabolism were especially affected in this case. Mutant pigs, known simply as Flesh among the stalkers, are one of the most vivid examples of the Zone's disastrous perversion of nature. Mutant pigs developed a protective layer of scales and exoskeletal plates. Their regeneration potential increased several times, as did the complexity of their nervous system. Just like a normal pig, a Flesh is an omnivore and may attack a stalker if hungry.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Poltergeist">
		<text>Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_poltergeist_general">
		<text>Supernatural in the eyes of some, invisible creatures haunting the deeper reaches of the Zone, usually haunting old, abandoned buildings. Nothing is known about their origin, although rumors in circulation claim they are spirits of stalkers hit by a massive wave of radiation. Their mysterious appearances and disappearances seem to correspond to the poltergeist legend, hence the name. Known encounters with poltergeists are quite diverse in fact: from mischievous laughter and blood-chilling howling, to deadly fireballs appearing out of nowhere. Unfortunately, all information about the poltergeist phenomenon originates from unclear and contradictory stories of questionable validity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Pseudodog">
		<text>Pseudodog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudodog_general">
		<text>Despite the name, the pseudodogs evolved directly from wolves. The animals inhabiting the forests at the time of the catastrophe gave rise to one of the Zone's most dangerous mutant species. Pseudodogs are about as different from mutant dogs as wild wolves differ from poodles. The creatures mark and guard their territory carefully, attacking anyone stupid enough to venture into their line of sight. Lightning-fast reflexes, uncanny dexterity and razor-sharp teeth make the pseudodog a formidable enemy for large mutants and well-armed stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Pseudogiant">
		<text>Pseudogiant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_pseudogiant_general">
		<text>The pseudogiant resembles a massive, drop-shaped abdomen with a pair of disproportionately large limbs. The limbs are arms and legs at the same time. The creature uses them to move around and grab its victims. An adult pseudogiant can weigh up to two tons and stand 2 meters tall. Their clumsy appearance might be deceiving, since they can move very rapidly if needed. Their muscles are exceptionally powerful and their bones are as hard as steel. The creature's brain is protected by a sturdy (up to 10 centimeters thick) skull, while many complex functions are controlled by the spinal medulla. Another astonishing feature of the beast is its ability to create local shock waves, which damage all living things in the vicinity.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Snork">
		<text>Snork</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_snork_general">
		<text>It seems these creatures were human at some point, though it is difficult to imagine what conditions could turn a human being into such disgusting beast. Snorks are insane creatures leading a beast's life and differing little from other carnivorous monsters in the Zone. They move on all fours in long jumps, constantly sniffing the ground in hope of picking up the scent of prey. They hunt carefully, in a calculated manner, frequently setting up ambushes. Thanks to its uncanny reflexes and powerful muscles, the snork can approach the victim, pin it down in one long, accurate jump, and tear it to shreds in a matter of seconds. Strips of army uniforms and other clothing are occasionally found on their bodies. It stands to reason that they are all that's left of missing military stalkers.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Tushkano">
		<text>Rodent</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_tushkano">
		<text>In fact these animals are not related to jerboas, although there is a distinct resemblance. Attempts at determining the exact species from which this rodent evolved have so far been unsuccessful, although its ancestor must have been a gregarious rodent. Reaching up to 40cm at the shoulder, the animal is far more dexterous, aggressive and ravenous than its desert cousin. Mutant rodents live mainly in basements of destroyed buildings, feeding on everything they can get their teeth in, from plants to careless stalkers. Occasionally a pack of rodents will attack and kill large animals and mutants, tearing them apart before they can escape.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Controller">
		<text>Controller</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_controller_general">
		<text>A rare mutant seen near to the center of the Zone. Bears a superficial resemblance of a humanoid with a disproportionately big head. Possesses a good perception, and an ability to control the behavior of less developed creatures. Mature specimen are capable of taking control over human's head. This is a ferocious enemy, and even the most experienced stalkers are afraid of meeting it.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Rat_weak">
		<text>Rat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_rat_general">
		<text>After people abandoned the territories, rats have grown in number. Their main habitation places are sewage headers, tunnels and basements. The animals seldomly leave the underground. Mainly attack in hordes.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="Rat_plague">
		<text>Plague rat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_rat_plague">
		<text>"Plague rats" are those mutated creatures, which escaped the vivariums of multiple laboratories, abandoned after the Second Catastrophe. In no time they spreaded all over the Zone. Among them were the rats from the X-18 laboratory, which had been used in testing the samples acquired by KGB agents in Great Britain after certain events of late seventies. The experiments led to a number of changes of the rats' brain tissues, in which mutant flies were cultivated. Those flies carried the gene, which gave rise to the brain cells mutation. The process resulted in creation of a perfect environment for the maggots, but the destruction of the brain was very soon followed by pseudo- death of the host. Those experiments were simultaneously accompanied by researches in the field of the flies' influence on human beings. The flies can inflict multiple wounds, resulting in heavy bleeding and possible infection.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sceleton_weak">
		<text>Skeleton zombie</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_mutant_sceleton_weak">
		<text>The scientists can not even produce a theory about what keeps these creatures "alive". Among the stalkers the opinion is that they are just shells for ghosts.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="Mutants">
		<text>Animals and mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="General">
		<text>General information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg">
		<text>Boar's hoof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
		<text>Boar's hooves can be used to produce a number of drugs, including an antiradiation serum. \n"Whatsoever parteth the hoof, and is clovenfooted, and cheweth the cud, among the beasts, that shall ye eat" -Bible</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail">
		<text>Dog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to electricity and chemical agents has long been the subject of scientific attention. Since the animal's tail is almost completely free of fat tissue, it is especially suited for lab examination. \n "How many legs does a dog have, if you call his tail a leg? The answer is four, because calling a tail a leg doesn't make it a leg" -Abraham Lincoln</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
		<text>Flesh eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>The mutated, swollen eye of the Flesh acquired a number of strange characteristics, the most useful of which is the ability to regenerate the lens. The specifics of the process are hitherto unknown, although such discovery would most certainly revolutionize modern medicine. You can play your part in scientific development by selling Flesh eyes to scientists for their experiments. \n "She was flesh and blood. She ended up being killed" -Colin Anderson</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand">
		<text>Zombie hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombie_hand_description">
		<text>Attributes are unknown. You can contribute to science by selling it to some scientists for researches. \n "Sometimes, something will startle me, and I secretly hope it's a zombie" -Charleen Scott</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand">
		<text>Burer hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description">
		<text>Burer's tissues have gained a number of attributes, among which the most profitable is the resistance to radiation. The nature of this effect remains unknown. You can contribute to science by selling it to some scientists for researches. \n "Take a chance and try my fare! It will grow on you, soon it will taste good to you!" -Friedrich Wilhelm Nietzsche</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles contain a special gland producing a ferment capable of dissolving the skin and simultaneously preventing blood from clotting. Discovering the ferment's composition could be the cornerstone of a whole series of great medical advances. \n "Will it hurt your back....kissing your own ass like that?" -Will Grace</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
		<text>Pseudodog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
		<text>The resistance of mutant dogs' skin to electricity and chemical agents has long been the subject of scientific attention. Since the animal's tail is almost completely free of fat tissue, it is especially suited for lab examination. \n "A former Israeli intelligence officer will show us how to make the most of our loving relationship with dogs, ... And if you do not watch, he knows 17 different ways to kill you with a paper clip" -Al Roker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg">
		<text>Snork foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
		<text>Snork feet contain a huge number of highly elastic tendons. This explains the beast's ability to make those unbelievably long jumps. \n "Great wits jump (says the Poet) and hit his Head against the Post" -Benjamin Franklin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_face_tushkano">
		<text>Rodent head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_face_tushkano_description">
		<text>Rodents express high herd intellect. Numerous scientists do their best to understand how such small brain may accomodate huge amounts of various complex information and instincts. Researchers keep making extracts from their brain, but the entire amount of the product is exported from the Zone. The field of its application is also unknown. \n Very-a delicious! (Fu Chong)</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler">
		<text>Controller hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler_description">
		<text>As far as controllers possess unique psi-abilities, the scientists are very interested in conducting a thorough research of that phenomena. Some scientists reckon that the hand acts as a concentrator and directive radiator of psionic energy, greatly boosting the efficiency of the creature's attacks. Still, there is plenty more to research. \n "Cruelty and fear shake hands together" -Honore de Balzac.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas">
		<text>Poltergeist eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas_description">
		<text>Nobody knows what the scientists use it for, but... Who cares, as long as they pay a pretty penny? \n "One eye witness is better than ten hear sayers" -Titus Maccius Plautus</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand">
		<text>Pseudogiant paw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand_description">
		<text>In addition to enormous strength, the paw has got some other attributes, which scientists avoid to mention. But they do pay very well for it. \n "The Duchess! The Duchess! Oh my dear paws! Oh my fur and whiskers!" -Lewis Carroll</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_tail_cat">
		<text>Cat tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_tail_cat_description">
		<text>Unlike many other animals in the Zone, the cats didn't gain any remarkable abilities except increased size, extreme aggressivity and... remarkable wear-resistant fur! That makes tanners do their best to find out the secret so as to use it. \n "No cat out of its first fur can be decieved by appearances" -Peter Beagle</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot">
		<text>Chimera claw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot_description">
		<text>Chimera claw is harder than any known material on the Earth. That is why the military and the scientists are very much interested in it. \n "A young woman has young claws, well sharpened. If she has character, that is. And if she hasn't so much the worse for you" -Henri Matisse</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="izlom_hand">
		<text>Fracture hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="izlom_hand_description">
		<text>Anomalous hand and dexterity of fracture's extremity has been attracting the attention of the military and the scientists. Especially of the military. That is why it costs a lot. \n "How bad does it have to get before people stop arguing and backstabbing?" -John Thomas</text>
	</string>

	<string id="mutant_rat_corp">
		<text>Rat carcass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_rat_corp_description">
		<text>A rat carcass, which is not only less then useless, but can be infectious. But most stalkers in the Zone pay no attention to such crap.</text>
	</string>	
</string_table>
