<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="cheb_1_1_0">
    <text>Hello, Stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_1_1">
    <text>Am I seeing things?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_1_2">
    <text>Hi.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_2_0">
    <text>You're fine. Help me, please, mister... I'm not just a toy, I'm an assistant, I help one person. I have to find him. It's Kolya, he's somewhere in the Zone. Please...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_2_1">
    <text>I get it, it's a robot. Nice thing!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_2_2">
    <text>Who is he?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_3_0">
    <text>I knew that someone will find me, hurray! Look, are you a good guy or a bad guy? If you're bad, you throw me back, and if you're good, then help me. Can you help me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_3_1">
    <text>I'll help. What should I do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_4_0">
    <text>Please, do not throw me away! I'll die here, if no one will help me, and my friend who needs help will die too!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_4_1">
    <text>It's delirium.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_5_0">
    <text>Six months ago, Kolya hid me around here, he was afraid that he could get robbed, and went on his business. And disappeared. More recently, I got slung by an anomaly here during a blowout, and you found me. It's necessary to find Kolya, I have to know what happened to him. We'll have to go in his footsteps, and for that I can show you the way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_5_1">
    <text>How will you do that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_6_0">
    <text>I can recognize some places, I feel them. When we get close to such place, I'll give you a signal. So what? Can you help me, kind stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_6_1">
    <text>OK</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_7_0">
    <text>Thank you, you really are a good guy! Do you know what we should do? We have to go to a stalker named Tail and ask him about Kolya. And if you wonder why we should go see him first, it's because he's friend of Kolya. I enchanted your PDA so that it now shows where Tail is now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_7_1">
    <text>Well, that's a lead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_0">
    <text>Hi, master! What did you want?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_1">
    <text>What are you doing here? Who are you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_2">
    <text>Remind me, what I should do</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_3">
    <text>Do you know something interesting?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_4">
    <text>I have a problem with quest.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_5">
    <text>Can you shut up?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_2_0">
    <text>I don't know who or what I am. But since I'm aware of myself then I must be someone, not something. And I don't remember where I came from, but I do remember something else; the place I appeared, called "Hospital". For me to appear, someone must have made a strong wish. My friend made a very very strong wish, and then I appeared. Than my friend fell asleep. Someone big and grown-up came and took me with him. It was Nikolai - Kolya. He came to this Zone and hid me here.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_2_1">
    <text>You don't say.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_3_1_0">
    <text>We should go to the bar and talk to the stalker Tail. He'll tell us about Kolya and it will be easier to find him.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="cheb_2_3_1_0_1">
    <text>Tail said that Kolya went to a place called City-32. Let's look for this place!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_3_1_1">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4_0">
    <text>I can provide advice, I can tell a story, I can come up with something else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4_1">
    <text>From whence did you learn all that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_0">
    <text>I've laid in the Zone for a long time and read the thoughts of stalkers who were passing by. What do you want to hear?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_0_guid">
    <text>I've laid in the Zone for a long time and read the thoughts of stalkers who were passing by. Maybe you need advice?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_0_no_talk">
    <text>I've laid in the Zone for a long time and read the thoughts of stalkers who were passing by. Oh, I had something interesting to tell you, but... I forgot. I'll remember something in five minutes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_5_remember">
    <text>Well, ok.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_1">
    <text>Give me an advice.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_2">
    <text>Tell me a story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_3">
    <text>How much till the next blowout?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_4">
    <text>Where can I find a good artifact?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_5">
    <text>I don't need anything for now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_ok">
    <text>Thanks for the advice.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_1">
    <text>If you meet an enemy in the Zone, do not rush to shoot - first make sure that it is really your enemy. Some mercenaries, soldiers, or even bandits will sometimes make peace with loners if they need help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_2">
    <text>Sometimes in the Zone you'll find old safes, locked with combination locks. It is not always possible to break them open or hack them, but if you do you'll often find interesting stuff. If you encounter such a safe, remember the following.\n1) The code for each of them consists of no more than 4 or 6 digits.\n2) The numbers on the wheel - it's the regular series of numbers from 0 to 9.\n3)Use logical clues for the selection of the code.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_3">
    <text>Some artifacts do not have properties, either positive or negative. However, many of them are very interesting to the scientists, so do not rush to sell such "useless" looking artifacts: maybe someone will pay a lot for those.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_4">
    <text>Some artifacts are invisible to the naked eye. You have to extract them using those things - forgot how they're called. They're peculiar in the sense that they are born strictly in certain places and at varying intervals.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_5">
    <text>Sometimes, instead of valuable loot you might find some book or manuscript. I advise you to think twice before throwing it away or selling it. Even if it sounds ridiculous, you may find among stalkers someone who may find it useful for himself. In return, they won't mind sharing valuable stuff, such as interesting intel.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_empty">
    <text>I feel that something is very wrong...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_busy_0">
    <text>Oh, I had something interesting to tell you, but... I forgot. I'll  remember something in five minutes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_busy_1">
    <text>OK.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story_next">
    <text>[...next...]</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story_empty">
    <text>Something made me forget all the stories... Oh, you supposed not to see it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_1">
    <text>Once upon a time two Stalkers went togeher to raid for loot and stumbled upon a very valuable artifact. They immediately rushed to it, even bumping their foreheads in their haste! But there was only one artifact, and two of our friends: it was necessary to seek a solution. They argued again and again, but could not agree. The first wanted to sell the loot and split the money, the other wanted to keep such a precious artifact for himself, and repay the other with part of his own loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_2">
    <text>They argued all day, then someone came by and advised them to refer to the forester Zaharich, who lived alone in the DarkScape. The old man was known in stalker community for his wisdom and the fairness of the decisions he made. The friends went to him. They explained the reason for their dispute and he answered them: "The Zone made you quarrel, so it shall reconcile you. Take this thing that you found and put it on the rotten stump that sticks out just behind my hut."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_3">
    <text>"Cover it with the old bucket that is lying there and wait for three hours. Then take a look under the bucket. If the artifact turned blue, the first of you shall have it, and if it turned red - the other." The stalkers went to Zaharich's garden, found the stump, put on it their finding, covered it with the bucket, and sat. Waiting an hour..., two..., three... Our friends became nervous because of the half-a-million worth artifact! Then they started grumbling on each other, </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_4">
    <text>and very soon they started yelling on each other. Both grabbed their knives and paused, waiting to see who of them would attack first. Suddenly, both noticed that a strange smell was emanating from the bucket. One of the former friends cautiously raised its edge and both saw that on the stump, instead of their artifact there was nothing but the ordinary pile of cow dung, and, judging by the smell, pretty fresh. Stalkers became dumbfounded and when they recovered, they immediately rushed to Zaharich.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_5">
    <text>The old man looked at the stump and told them: "It might not be obvious, but that bucket of mine is anomalous. It revealed to you the secret of the artifact you had! And to think you were ready to get killed for it..." With these words, the forester spat juicily onto the stump and went into his hut. What happened to our heroes is unknown, but I do know that nobody found this artifact ever after.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_ok">
    <text>Interesting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_1">
    <text>Once upon a time an experienced stalker went for loot and didn't return. He was awaited for one day, two, and on the third he was awaited no more... Suddenly on the fourth day he arrives and tells everyone: "Guys, I found something - it's unbelievable. Come with me!" A group of six men, well equipped and armed, went with him. A day passes, two - no sign of them. The other stalkers started to wonder. Those that went weren't born yesterday, something was clearly not right here. A second group gathered, certainly about a dozen people; </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_2">
    <text>many were armed to the teeth, high-class rounds, detectors, one stalker even got an RPG. They went and... Yes, you guessed it - never returned! Their comrades grieved for a long time, even made near the entrance of the Bar some sort of a monument for them: a cross with a gasmask and a sign with the names. Suddenly, the head of the "Duty" became very interested in this matter. He wanted to know, what kind of power had emerged in the Zone, that almost twenty stalkers</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_3">
    <text>couldn't cope with it. He gathered his best scouts and ordered them to find the missing stalkers, and if they couldn't, then at least find the cause for their disappearance. These men were professionals - athletes, commandos, ninjas! Even prior to the Zone they had learned how to survive in the jungle with only a knife in hand. They weren't afraid of wild beasts nor anomalies, and they could deal bare-handed not only with bandits but also mercenaries. The scouts went on the search and the next day they went</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_4">
    <text>to the place, where the missings had last been seen - a small abandoned factory. As they approached they smelled a strange chemical smell... The commander of the scouts, an experienced man, immediately ordered his soldiers to put on their gas masks. As they crept in, they saw the following picture: in the middle of the main building was a hefty tank. Around it laid the bodies. The scouts counted  eighteen bodies, none of them moved.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_5">
    <text>Suddenly, from behind a corner a stalker jumped out... nah, probably tumbled out, with a RPG in his hands. Staggering, he blearily studied the entire company for a long time, then finally said with difficulty:\nAttention! Your papers! Comrade commander, reporting: as of eight o'clock in the evening the remaining liquid in the main tank is one hundred and seven liters, no leaks were found... Then he fell down and asleep. Dead drunk.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_ok">
    <text>Thank you for the story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_1">
    <text>There was once a stalker nicknamed "Beetle". He had this nick for, as you guessed, his cunningness and caution. Now then, one day our Beetle went ahead and screwed up. How did he do that? Very simple. He took an order for a rare artifact, got it and drank it away in "100Rad" bar. The client of the Beetle was powerful, beyond the perimeter. "If he'll offende, thought Beetle, - better for me not to come back from the Zone!" He thought and thought and decided to cheat his client.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_2">
    <text>And since he was cunning, he decided to do it smart. "I will fake my own death, - thought our Beetle, and then softly retreat from the Zone. Anyway, the client don't personally know me, so all will be well." But for the accident to seem plausible, witnesses were needed. Beetle decided to use for this purpose one of his friends who owed him some money. That friend was called Slavik, and his nickname was Bubble. Beetle called him along to the "Rostok" factory after careful preparations.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_3">
    <text>They came to a place stalkers were familiar with, when Beetle, shouting especially loudly and waving his arms, fell, or rather jumped into the prepared and camouflaged pit. At the bottom of the pit laid the fresh corpse of an unlucky stalker, which was found by Beetle on the outskirts of the Bar (a bloodsucker killed the poor soul). The dead man was wearing the exact same suit as our Beetle next to him, same backpack and assault rifle, and his face was severely disfigured  - everything was artfully taken care of by Beetle.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_4">
    <text>He did not foresee one thing though: the night before a hungry snork got in the pit, attracted by smell. One can only imagine the horror and surprise of poor hapless Bubble, when he saw at the bottom of the pit rather than one two of Beetle, and even an extra Snork. "Help me!" - yelled Beetle in the meantime, lashing out at the mutant, "just don't shoot or you can take me out! Give me your hand, I'll get out of here!" However, the Bubble does not hurry to help his comrad. Having assessed that Beetle's chances</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_5">
    <text> were rather slim, he turned and walked away, ignoring the cries from the pit. He owed too much to the Beetle. Meanwhile, the hungry, growling snork, crawled up to our schemer, who dug the pit for himself and was in the worst position now. Beetle rose his rifle, but it snapped - the shutter was filled with dirt. He barely made it out of the pit, he paid the price for salvation by letting the snork rip up his legs and back. Limping back to the camp, he learned that mercenaries kidnapped the Bubble right</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_6">
    <text>out of his tent. Apparently, the client learned that Beetle bailed out of his deal and began searching for him through his teammates. More about the Bubble have not been heard. And Beetle's stalker career was over.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_ok">
    <text>Well-well...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_1">
    <text>Once upon a time a stalker walked in the Garbage and saw: on the roadside a fracture was sitting with an artifact in its paws! First he held it between his claws, then slipped it into his jacket and ran. The stalker followed him. He ran behind the fracture, which turned out clever, going aroung "Springboards", jumping over "Fruit punches", slipping past "Vortexes"! The stalker ran exactly on his trail. They ran into some grove, the fracture jumped - and dropped into a burrow under an old stump. The man took his rifle and shot a whole magazine it that hole.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_2">
    <text>He wanted to throw a grenade, but changed his mind - it could brake the artifact. Then he sat, unable to catch his breath. But suddenly he hears -  a faint voice came from the hole: "Stalker" - it says, - "do not shoot at me, though I'm a mutant, i desire to live. Let's rather make a deal: I'll give you the artifact, and even show a place there are a lot of them, and you let me go." The stalker answered the mutant: - OK! - and thought: "I'll take the artifacts and shoot the monster." </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_3">
    <text>You know, fractures are very dangerous. The fracture got out of the hole, beckoned with its claws, and limped off into the bushes, so the stalker went after him. They walked a hundred meters and found a clearing with a large stone in the middle of it. The fracture crawled to it, dig the ground with its paw and pull out an old half-rotten backpack, and pours directly on the stalker's feet about twenty quite rare artifacts - more than he could collect in a week! He dumped his loot in front of him and quietly backed away to get back</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_4">
    <text> into the forest. But the man was not born yesterday, he realized what was happening here. He aims at it and says: - Show the remaining caches, if you don't want me to shorten your tail! The freak hissed, groaned. Obviously, it didn't want to part with its findings, but the fear was stronger. He led the stalker throughout the forest, they began emptiyng caches and transferring their contents into the stalker's backpack. They stuffed the backpack almost to the top, the staker had already</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_5">
    <text>thrown away his canned food to free some space. Suddenly the fracture said: - There's one cache left, the biggest... The stalker rejoiced and began to imagine what to buy with the money that he'll get for his loot. He estimated that it should be enough for his dream - brand new "Ford". He began to dream about coming to his native town, not in the stinking train, but in a brand new car, riding at his house, honking loudly, as if he was waiting for someone. The neighbours will lean out of the windows to watch, and he'll get out of the car,</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_6">
    <text>stand next to it, light a cigarette, put his hand on the hood... A new suit, shoes, sunglasses...The former classmate, Vitya-major, who laughed at him when he got a job as a welder at the factory with his two diplomas, at least once in his live will be humiliated. Well, his father has two stores, and the stalker never had something. So, they approached the last place. The stalker sees: an aircraft fuselage was lying amongst young pines. AN-2, according to its size. How it got there was unknown, however, there were rumors</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_7">
    <text>that some extreme athletes have tried to fly over the Zone in private planes to take pictures, but got lost. The fuselage was all mangled, peeled off the tail, the wings broken, the cockpit crushed. The fracture approached it, opened the door and climbed in while the stalker stood outside watching it. Suddenly, a loud hiss came from the wreckage, and a hefty Chimera poped out of it! The stalker immediately ran out. He ran in the woods, stumbling, going aroung "Springboards", jumping over "Fruit punches", slipping past "Vortexes"! Barely made it. He forgot about all his loot</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_8">
    <text>and only when he approached the Bar, he noticed that there's no backpack behind his back. That's the story... Yeah, that's not all! After a week the stalker went the same road where he spotted that fracture. He saw it again sitting at the same old place! The man quietly took on his rifle... The freak felt something, jumped up and ran away. The stalker shot once and missed. He approached the spot where the fracture was sitting at, and saw his lost backpack. He looked inside - there was all the canned food, which he threw in the woods. But he never saw that fracture again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_ok">
    <text>Yeah...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_1">
    <text>Once a stranger came to visit the Zone. What he had forgotten in it? It's just what his work was like - to go around the world, to visit the most dangerous places on the planet and then to describe them. He was a journalist and a traveller, and, quite a famous one. He has visited Iraq, Afghanistan, Libya, even the Chechen Republic. He travelled in the wild jungles of Amazon and the african deserts, contacted local hostile tribes, won confidence of these savages, lived among them;</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_2">
    <text>described it in books or wrote articles for magazines, such as "National Geographics" or "Science", he even went on TV. And one beautiful day he decided to visit our Zone and see, how stalkers living here; what they eat, what they drink, what they do in their spare time, etc. Our foreigner was especially interested in the local folklore. He was a big connoisseur of literature, knowing russian well, he read Pushkin, Dostoyevsky and Tolstoy in the original. He decided to collect when possible all histories,</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_3">
    <text>jokes, legends, and simple fairy tales connected to the Zone and its inhabitants. However, being an experienced man in such affairs, he made his excursion to the Chernobyl zone a secret. Well: militaries would not allow it - first, bandits would prey on him - second, mercenaries would scam him on the repayment - third. So he acted on it, simply, reasonably, but with one mistake - making the operation undercover. So the journalist (named James) arrived to our country under another name, having declared at home in England, </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_4">
    <text>that he'd go to investigate Sahara's bedouins culture. Here his friends helped him make a deal for a sortie in the Zone. They charged him a lot of money for this as they thought he's a tourist. But he wasn't satisfied with that, he wanted to dive into the atmosphere of danger and risk of a stalker's life. Our James soon regretted that he didn't go meet African bedouins however. First his group was properly handled by major Ovchinin at the Perimeter. I know this major personally - he has hardly not beaten me a kidney off on interrogation </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_5">
    <text>when I got on a violation of regime at the Cordon. He started his usual "shaking" on our gallant traveller and his escort. If he would just give all his money and stuff to major - all would go well. Skilled stalkers, who is not the first timers in the Zone, just take a certain amount (not too much, but not a penny either)and give it to the major without resistance, just to get to the Zone without problems. At the same time they'll earn much more in artifact later, if they're lucky.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_6">
    <text>But our brave englishman started to protest, he appealed to fairness, a military honor, then recalled the European Court of Human Rights... Well, when major's "sons" done with him, he hardly had enough power, to limp to the camp. Our journalist rested a bit in bed there to recover. There our veterans tried to heal him by thir own way, but they didn't success - foreigner felt worse, than from the beating... Cordon's sludge is such a thing: one digests it well, and others suffers, I know it by myself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_7">
    <text>And so, as our englishman came back up on his legs, he wanted to reach the Bar as he knew from stories, that there most stalkers lives. Locals decided to see him off. But near the camp they were "received" by bandits. Turns out someone was a "rat" amongst our guys, he got an eye on the pricey equipment of the foreigner and snitched the skinheads. Thank God, the bandits were in good mood and did not begin to play "moose" as they usually do with beginners, that repeated beatings would not have been endured by our journalist.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_8">
    <text>But still he reached the Bar empty-handed, and moreover half-naked - he's been removed the military suit, a gift from an american general and memory of such quiet days in Afghanistan. At the Bar the people did not recognize a celebrity. Stalkers are simple lads, not interested in science and nature, not reading smart magazines. They accepted our James as a tourist - such a thing is rare in the Zone, but it happens. He was lodged with the others, given a simple stuff. And our Englishman got accostumed among the local brotherhood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_9">
    <text>They advised him to get out of the Zone - but he disagreed. He was engaged in his favorite business: record local tales and the stories of skilled stalkers. Then a new trouble happened to him: mercenaries shot him. They're  practicing their accuracy on us sometimes, for not to lose that skill. A sniper sits someplace and shoots men, that go to the Bar from sorties. He wounds the first one, which fall behind. Wounded man starts yelling, blood everywhere, god. A friend tries to reach for him to help - the sniper shoots him in the forehead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_10">
    <text>When the unfortunate's comrades start to hesitate, not hasting to get under the bullets then that ugly beast begins to shoot the wounded man's fingers or ears... Assholes, in a word. And so, our journalist got to that situation. Mercenary shot him in the calves, first right, then left - so he couldn't esacpe. And nobody couldn't help him - the sniper not allowed that. The poor fellow already ceased to shout, resigned. Then someone from the "Duty" brought a smoke grenade and under the cover of a smoke screen dragged the poor man from under the firing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_11">
    <text>Our hero strongly changed after that - before he was all joking, laughing, and now he has become serious, tight-lipped. Some said that after the accident he's been heard a couple times as he cried softly at night. But that's nothing - the foreigner had grown accustomed to a stalker's life, drank it all up, recognized its grief and joy. There's one thing he really kept in his heart. There was a writer in the Zone: he wrote simple stories about local life. Some were funny, some were frightful, and some were sad. May be that was some student - they couldn't survive even thir first anomaly usually. </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_12">
    <text>But our James became exicted about that papers - it was what he needed! He made a lot of inquries about that unknown author, tried to find him. But that odd fellow apparently disappeared - nobody found more of his manuscripts on old yellow pages of Soviet papers. Then James began to ask all Stalkers to bring him these "books" for collection. So that's what he's doing now. That's the story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_ok">
    <text>Yeah, that's what happens...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_1">
    <text>Among all the other benefits available for stalkers, the one Vintar loved most was money. How much he collected in two years and a half of life in the Zone, no one knew exactly, but there were rumours that it was fantastic sum. As you could expect, our Vintar was greedy, like a vacuum cleaner. Even in dangerous places he always went up alone just not to share profit with assistants and he never brought "lockpicks" with him. Stalkers disliked him for this, but also respected him - Vintar knew </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_2">
    <text>how to work hard, he amassed all his stuff on his own and he didn't hesitate of dangers, or hard work. It's told, that once he dragged by himself to the Bar an old Soviet safe, which he found in some cellar. What was inside the safe and whether there was something at all - is unknown, but it is known only, that the burden weighed under a hundred kg. Although many, of course don't believe it... Those who don't know Vintar. Or rather, didn't know. Where he has kept his money? - you can ask. It was kept in the same safe, but not only there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_3">
    <text>He welded it to the metal floor in the basement of the Bar, put a lock with a code on the door, and every month gave the bartender some artifacts for the protection of his private "cell". A recurring joke at the Bar was, that when it's time for Vintar to leave the Zone, he'll have to give all his loot to militaries for permission to evacuate it, like Ostap Bender in "The Golden Calf". Our hero did not trust electronic money at all. Vintar never responded to jokes and in general conducted the closed way of life: he had no friends and didn't clash with anyone, </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_4">
    <text>trusting nobody. He was calm, but had a reputation of being gloomy and reticent, prefering to act, than to reason. Outside of the Perimeter he would be a successful businessman or a money-bag, though who knows...Somehow on the next spring our hero was going on a new raid God knows where - his plan, you guessed it, was kept in secret from anyone. One day passed, then another, then a week, but Vintar did not return. Normally a stalker raid for loot takes only three, maybe four days, because you can walk around the whole Zone (though it's large) in a week, of course, ignoring the anomalies and other things ... </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_5">
    <text>But two more days passed, and Vintar did not return. I must tell you that there was an unwritten law at the Bar, or rather, a custom that if a stalker perished in the Zone, his property was given to his relative or his friend, if there's no relatives. The barman had just began to think with stalkers, to whom he should give Vintar's property, when, out of nowhere, some stalker appeared. He declared the following: he was a best friend of Vintar since childhood and so now his property belonged to him. "He had no family, his parents died long ago" - </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_6">
    <text>our new friend sighed, - "and I was like a brother to him, I protected him, took care of him". As proof of his words he showed some old fuzzy photos, where they were captured together with Vintar during military service. The most experienced stalkers gathered for council (the case was not ordinary, it was about big money - Vintar spent years selling his loot) and began to settle. Some of the stalkers suggested to find out, whether there were relatives of the victim and send part of the money to them, and divide the rest amongst them, as a tax. But the </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_7">
    <text>others believed Vintar's freshly baked friend and entrusted the business to him. So the safe with goods passed to the new owner. Perhaps, you will think, that the given decision was too precipitated or even naive, however it is necessary to note, that the stalkers on this council were not fools and understood, that if outside the Perimeter huge money is success, here, in the Zone - it is more like a problem. Gangsters, thugish mercenaries, envious "friends" - the laws here are different. But shall we return to our sheeps, or rather, to the money. </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_8">
    <text>Having acquired the right to open the safe, Vintar's friend vigorously started to do it. However straight-off opening of the cache did not happen - only previous owner knew the code for the lock. Not really bothered, our new acquaintaance brought first a forty-pound sledgehammer, but when it didn't help - a propane torch. At last, after breaking thick metallic door, the stalker was stunned: it was empty inside... Someone, who knew the treasure numbers, hurried in advance and has withdrawn its property first! However taking a closer look, he saw some bundle at the bottom.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_9">
    <text>Reaching into the depth of the ruined safe, the stalker took a thick notebook wrapped in foil from it.He opened it and some incomprehensible inscriptions appeared before his eyes: squares, zigzags, squiggles, and figures - a whole sea of figures. Inscriptions and figures - that's all that Vintar left to them as his legacy... However, it looks like you already understood, that something was not rigth. The newfound "millionaire" also understood this, therefore he has shown the Barman and some stalkers the notebook for an interpretation. "It's a code" - realized the Barman, - </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_10">
    <text>"the deadman encyphered a map, showing where his savings can be found". However, a scientist who happened to be in the Bar has denied this hypothesis - Dr. Gorbovsky (he was involved in the study of a disease that strikes stalkers in the Zone). "This is a mathematical formula" - concluded the doctor, - "but I can't tell you what it means, because it is not in my field. I am, you see, a biologist". Stalkers understood, that Vintar's money could not have completely disappeared and the answer was hidden in the formulas from the notebook. However there are no </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_11">
    <text>mathematicians among Stalkers, therefore this question is still without answer... This story was long discussed among habitants of the Bar while drinking a beer. One theorized, that Vintar was not really lost, and all this time he simply quietly sent money out of the Perimeter, and the safe was used as a distraction; and when the time came, he has simply escaped from the Zone; others claimed, that he was actually a latent scientist or as we say here, a "nugget", that is to say a unique person. Having solved the mathematical riddle of the Zone's laws, he could deduce a method</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_12">
    <text>of determining the places where most of the artifacts will appear and used it for his needs... A wide variety of guesses were made by them, but no one ever saw Vintar, nor his money. And the notebook lies somewhere under a counter at the Bar. If you're in the area and give a glance at the "100Rads" Bar, you should ask to see it, it's free. And if you are versed into mathematics, can prove various theorems - then you have a chance to receive a key to the solution of this affair. For now it remains a mistery.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_ok">
    <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_0">
    <text>What are you working on?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_1">
    <text>"The Mystery of Old House"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_2">
    <text>"A Strange Anomaly"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_3">
    <text>"Safe of Digger"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_4">
    <text>"The Anomaly in the Tower"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_5">
    <text>"Flying Islands"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_6">
    <text>"The Struggle at the Sawmill"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_7">
    <text>"Flea's Hideout"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_8">
    <text>"The Trap at the Gas Station"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_9">
    <text>The Issue of Immortality - p. 1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_1_0">
    <text>A bad-bad person! Very bad! He has killed the good person, that's awful! Good person feels sick, he wishes to sleep... Help it to fall asleep, I can hear, how he is angry, he grumbles, he shouts! Find the four parts of the good person here, in the court yard. They're hidden very-very well: on a roof, on a tree, in a car and in some electric thing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_1_1">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_2_0">
    <text>Look around, do you see portals? You need to find the proper sequence of four portals.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_2_1">
    <text>Yeah, I'm on it...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_3_0">
    <text>The inscriptions on the safe, they mean something abbreviated. What is it? And could it be, next to the inscriptions stand numerals? They should be only four. By the way, remember: the divisions on the wheel of the safe account for figures from 0 up to 9, it's necessary to make a code or cipher of them. Got it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_3_1">
    <text>Yes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_4_0">
    <text>Oh, what a nasty sound! We should switch it off or the person in the tower will die! The sound comes from the box with the buttons. First press all the buttons from top to bottom, then bottom left. Then again from top to bottom.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_4_1">
    <text>Understood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_5_0">
    <text>Master, I know, what to do! Try to find a portal, which will lead you in this lodge.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_5_1">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_6_0">
    <text>Oh, once again thre are bad people! So there is a lot of them, more, than good people... The bad people want to trick the good people, they will suggest peace. But as soon as the good people will agree, they can die.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_6_1">
    <text>I will be aware.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_7_0">
    <text>The small person has lost his bag and is now punished for it, he is in a corner... What to do? We have to find the bag and all will be well. It is somewhere nearby, under a shrub near a fence... Don't forget to read, what you find in it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_7_1">
    <text>OK.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_8_0">
    <text>Oh, where we are? That is a terrible room, people have died here, they have died long ago... Here is uncomfortable. And it's impossible to leave - something won't let us. We need to open that old safe and to find one good thing which will help. The code of the safe? We shall give it some thoughts. Earlier, a long time ago, people brought fuel here for their cars. Fuel was designated by numbers... These numbers are written in columns! I hope, that you have remembered them, master? Try to enter these numbers. The code is four-digits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_8_1">
    <text>I see.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_muten">
    <text>Dead mister told me, that the Cobblestone should be looked for around great metallic structures. As those in the Garbage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_firefly">
    <text>For the Firefly it is necessary to wander on water during a rain. Brrr, I do not like to get wet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_chameleon">
    <text>The Chameleon can only be found during blowouts. Maybe we don't go for it, heh?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_common">
    <text>All the things that you have found, we need to bring to dead mister.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_1">
    <text>Thanks for tip</text>
  </string>
</string_table>