<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="af-zombie-hand">
		<text>Zombie-kamikaze palm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_zombie_hand">
		<text>Strange artifact. They say, the only specimen was owned by Fang, but he took it to the grave. The palm is warm and protects against gamma radiation. You can either use it to suit your own needs or give it to the scientists to help unmask the mystery of the legendary zombie.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-teleport-trap">
		<text>Unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-teleport-trap">
		<text>Unknown artifact with strange properties. Indicators doesn't react on it. Looks like strange ball with spikes. Should be brought to scientists, maybe they'll be interested in it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mopheus">
		<text>"Morpheus"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mopheus">
		<text>Unknown artifact. Maybe the note that was with it helps to understand, how it works.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-muten">
		<text>"Cobblestone"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-muten">
		<text>Artifact is a shapeless gray formation. Always appears near massive metallic constructions. Its most demasking signs are the psy-zone, formed by the artifact, and radiosignal distortion in 250 metres radius. Radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-firefly">
		<text>"Firefly"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-firefly">
		<text>Appears in Electra anomaly and only during rain. If you can't extract the artifact from the anomaly, it will disappear when the rain stops. artifact causes anomaly discharge while in it. The most visible sign of Firefly presence is its green glow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-chameleon">
		<text>"Chameleon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-chameleon">
		<text>Artifact appears only before Surge when anomaly energy level is maximum. It was never found by any stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_horror_time">
		<text>Horror Time</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_horror_time">
		<text>Quite often a Surge is followed by psi-surge, or the so-called "Horror Time". It's a sickening period of time, when people within the Zone experience incredible suffering. Phantoms and quickly moving anomalies appear during this time.
		Maybe the scientists at Yantar know more about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_horror_time_ecolog">
		<text>Professor Sakharov asserts that the "Horror Time" is a phenomena of psionic nature. At some uncertain frequency Surges are followed by a vigorous boom of psi-emission, which provoke hallucinations and delirium.
		This phenomena can spread over great distances without losing its properties and influence. Exact location of the source remains unknown.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="af-kaktus">
        <text>"Plasma Cactus"</text>
    </string>
	<string id="af-ameba-mica">
		<text>"Mica"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slime">
		<text>"Slime"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slug">
		<text>"Slug"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-blood">
		<text>"Stone Blood"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall">
		<text>"Crystal"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall-flower">
		<text>"Stone Flower"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-drops">
		<text>"Droplets"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-battery">
		<text>"Battery"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>"Shell"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>"Mama's Beads"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>"Pellicle"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-spring">
		<text>"Spring"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-flash">
		<text>"Flash"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>"Moonlight"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>"Sparkler"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fireball">
		<text>"Fireball"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>"Kolobok"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gold-fish">
		<text>"Goldfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gravi">
		<text>"Gravi"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-medusa">
		<text>"Jellyfish"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mincer-meat">
		<text>"Meat Chunk"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-night-star">
		<text>"Night Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>"Crystal Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>"Urchin"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>"Thorn"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-soul">
		<text>"Soul"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-vyvert">
		<text>"Wrenched"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-midas">
		<text>«Midas»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Agroprom">
		<text>Agroprom Research Institute</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Ameba">
		<text>"Fruit Punch"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Hvatalka">
		<text>"Grassper"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Liana">
		<text>"Liana"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Anomalies">
		<text>Anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Artifacts">
		<text>Artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Klondike_Artifacts">
		<text>Klondike artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bald">
		<text>"Springboard"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bar">
		<text>Bar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Darkdolina">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Deadcity">
		<text>Erased</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Electra">
		<text>"Electro"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_ameba">
		<text>An anomaly of unknown nature. On contact inflicts injuries similar to the effects of a strong acid. Forms three types of artifacts: "Slime", "Slug", and "Mica".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_bald">
		<text>One of the first anomalies ever recorded - an unstable gravitational field inflicting shock damage to anyone within its radius. Remains active for a week on average. The amount of damage inflicted changes during its lifetime, ranging from minor bruises, through serious wounds, to instant death. Easy to spot in daylight. Accompanied by air fluctuation above the anomaly, dancing leaves and distinctive crimson-colored stains on the ground. Picked up by all types of detectors, the Springboard can also be revealed by throwing objects into it. Forms three types of artifacts: "Jellyfish", "Stone Flower" and "Night Star".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_electra">
		<text>An anomalous formation, roughly 10 meters in diameter, accumulating large quantities of static electricity. When triggered, the anomaly bursts out in dozens of miniature lightnings, causing electric shock nearly always lethal to all living beings. Recognizable by the bluish fog hovering above it in daylight. At nighttime, the "Electro" can be revealed using any type of detector or by throwing metal objects into the anomaly. Forms three types of artifacts: "Sparkler", "Flash" and "Moonlight".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fuzz">
		<text>One of the Zone's examples of mutated vegetation. Reacts to rapidly approaching living beings by discharging a cloud of projectiles severely injuring uncovered or lightly protected skin upon contact. Does not react to slowly moving targets. Forms three types of artifacts (possibly its seeds): "Thorn", "Crystal Thorn" and "Urchin".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_gravi">
		<text>An anomaly of presumably gravitational nature. When triggered, the tremendous power of the Vortex drags everything within the radius of 10-15 meters towards center. Victims drawn into the core have no chance of survival: their bodies are quickly constricted into a tight lump, only to be blown up in a powerful discharge of energy a moment later. The anomaly remains stationary throughout its lifetime (a week on average). Easily recognizable in daylight by the air fluctuation above, dancing leaves, fragments of dismembered corpses lying around and a distinctive dark stain in the center. Highly dangerous at night since it can be revealed only by means of a detector or by throwing metal objects into it. Forms three types of artifacts: "Wrenched", "Gravi" and "Goldfish".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_lift">
		<text>A harmless anomaly, temporarily negating normal gravity. Manifests itself as an area - usually several meters in diameter - where Earth's gravitational pull is greatly reduced. Forms the "Pellicle" artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_meat">
		<text>The anomaly snatches its victims up in the air and spins them at a breakneck speed. The exact nature of the "Whirligig" remains unknown. The anomaly can be recognized by a light whirlwind of dust above and by body fragments scattered in the vicinity. Victims caught on its outer rim - far enough from the maximum effect zone at the center - can escape the "Whirligig" with relatively minor injuries. Forms three types of artifacts: "Stone Blood", "Meat Chunk" and "Soul".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_radioactive">
		<text>An area of increased radiation - over 50 mR/h. Staying in a radiation zone for longer periods of time is strongly discouraged.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_time">
		<text>A true miracle of an anomaly: an area several meters in diameter where the time flow is significantly slower than usual. Appears to have no negative effect on human health. However, the "Time Machine" can be very difficult to get out of. Interestingly, removing "Mama's Beads" - an artifact usually found in the center of the anomaly - causes the "Time Machine" to disappear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zharka">
		<text>While inactive, the anomaly manifests itself as a barely visible cloud of hot air. When triggered by an object or a living being it instantly heats up to lethal temperatures approaching 1500K. At nighttime, it can be revealed by powerful detectors or by throwing metal objects into the trigger area. Forms three types of artifacts: "Droplets", "Fireball" and "Crystal".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_hvatalka">
		<text>One of the first anomalies encountered in the Zone. Generally speaking, these half-floral, half-faunal mutants appeared long before the Second Catastrophe. Most probably they are the result of radioactive pollution of the area after the Chernobyl disaster. Still, the fact that the "Grasspers" are mostly encountered in the Agroprom Research Institute area indirectly indicates human influence on their birth. The anomaly itself resembles a huge predator plant like "Sundew" or "Venus flytrap". It can often be encountered by water ponds and other plants tangles, in which the "Grassper" camouflages easily due to its protective coloration. But the anomaly can be effortlessly detected by the great amount of flies near it, which feed on the remains of its victims. The "Grassper" is extremely dangerous - it is very difficult to break free out of its closed tentacles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_liana">
		<text>"Liana". Just another mutant of vegetable origin.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
		<text>Anomaly “Fruit punch” is able to create such an artifact at the rarest, most extreme collection of physical conditions. The result is a semi-transparent, hard object. A rare and expensive artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
		<text>It is certain that this artifact is created by the anomaly called "Fruit punch". When carried on the belt, the wounds bleed less, although the body of its owner becomes more vulnerable to various burns.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Formed by the "Fruit punch" anomaly. The negative qualities of this artifact are compensated by the fact that it heightens the coagulation quality of blood. It’s not often that one runs into such an artifact, and they pay well for it too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
		<text>You can find this artifact near the anomaly “Whirligig”. It is quite an ugly reddish object made out of pressed together and curiously bent polymerized remnants of plants, soil, and bones. Quite widespread and not very effective.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
		<text>Is created when heavy metals fall into the "Burner" anomaly. This artifact eliminates radiation wonderfully. It is highly valued by stalkers and hard to find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
		<text>Born in the "Springboard" anomaly. This artifact is found in only a few areas of the Zone. The bits of metallic compounds create a beautiful light play. It is very calming to study this artifact at night by the fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
		<text>Formed in the anomaly “Burner” at high temperatures. From the exterior looks like a tear-like shade compound with a glossy surface, covered in cracks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
		<text>The origin of this object is shrouded in scientific mystery. It’s clear that it’s made in part by di-electric elements, but science does not know the physical conditions in which it is formed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>When wearing this artifact the denaturalization of proteins happens slower. In other words, the flesh is able to endure higher temperatures and burns less. In itself it is an expensive and rare thing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>Wonderful artifact. Keep it safe - it's good because it only has positive qualities. Scientists can't figure out how to create such an artifact in laboratory conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>This artifact is so rare that many researchers can't even imagine that such a substance can exist in a natural setting. Emmits acidic chemical components.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
		<text>According to the opinion of some researchers-theorists, this artifact is a hybrid between "Battery" and "Shell".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
		<text>"Electro" sometimes births this artifact. Stalkers readily use it because of its good qualities. Not a bad price and a good external look make this artifact appealing to collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>Degenerate case of the activity of the "Electro" anomaly. It seems that such a wonderful round form is created when the anomaly is subjected to thermal influences. Expensive artifact.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-kaktus">
        <text>This artifact is born by the "Whirligig" anomaly and presents a composition of half-welded mutated plants, one of which is supposed to be the nettle. The artifact appearance resembles a cactus, and that obviously led to such a name. One can also observe a luminous membrane (possibly of plasma origin), covering the artifact's surface. "Plasma Cactus" is quite a rare and expensive artifact.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>Found near the "Electro" type of anomaly. Quite widespread and inexpensive artifact. But still it is valued among the researchers in the Zone for its qualities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
		<text>Crystallizes in the anomaly "Burner". Fights well with radioactivity, though the heightened rate of energy exchange wears out the muscles of the moving apparatus. Won't be able to run for long. Artifact emmits heat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>When you hold this mystery of the Zone in your hands, you feel how your skin becomes tougher and less sensitive. You can still pierce it with a bullet, but it's much more resistant to cuts and abrasion.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
		<text>An artifact formed in the "Vortex" anomaly. Is activated by the heat of the body. Decide what's worse: radiation or knife wounds, and chose the lesser of the two evils. In any case you can sell the artifact for good profit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
		<text>Can spot it near anomalies such as "Vortex" or in the hands of another stalker. While wearing it a certain amount of radiation is stored in the body while the rest of it is scattered in the radial direction away from the body. A good price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
		<text>Is formed in the "Springboard". Forms a weak protective field whose side effect is a slight radiation. The artifact is widespread and not very valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
		<text>Manufactured by the "Whirligig" anomaly. Causes increased cell growth. On the other hand, the newly formed cells are much more receptive to the effects of physical damage. The artifact doesn't show up very often, but it's hard to call it rare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
		<text>This wonderful artifact is formed by the anomaly "Springboard". The use of the artifact demands the neutralization of deadly radiation. Expensive and rare, this artifact is extremely interesting for scientific expeditions and other research activity in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Crystallizes in the anomaly "Burnt Fuzz". Naturally takes out the radiation from the organism. That is, through the ears along with some amount of blood. Blood loss is possible also through other openings. Widespread and quite effective, which is the cause for the stable price in the artifact market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>The anomaly "Burnt Fuzz" very rarely gives rise to this artifact. Blood pressure rises, the body gets rid of a large amount of red blood cells. But along with them the stored radiation leaves the body as well. In his fundamental work titled "Ionization and polarization of the components of rare artifacts", Sakharov noted that the content of this formation has a critical stability, and it's not realistic to create such an artifact in lab conditions in the next ten years.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>The result of the interaction between the anomaly "Burnt Fuzz" and the body of a careless stalker. The "Thorn" artifact pokes the body of its owner, no matter what. But it also helps clean the body of radionucliodes. Quite widespread and cheap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
		<text>Very rarely found artifact, located near the "Whirligig" anomaly. Only a very few manage to find this artifact, and few have even seen it. It has a nice shape and an equally nice price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
		<text>Located in the anomaly called "Vortex". When it touches the body it disseminates the directed of the radiation, protecting from scratches or wounds made by weapons. This artifact isn't hard to find, that's why they don't pay much for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-midas">
		<text>Mythical artifact that can turn everything to gold if properly activated. Dealers and traders of all kind offer great money for it. But no one ever wanted to sell this artifact... or maybe couldn't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_agroprom">
		<text>A strange, heavily contaminated area. Should you wander deeper into it, you will see a shallow lake, crammed shore-to-shore with abandoned equipment and other debris. You can also check out the abandoned Institute and the factory, though the military have been hanging around there quite a lot recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_bar">
		<text>The Duty faction have set up camp on the plain's edge and they always welcome stalkers in need of rest. A desert oasis of sorts - a place completely devoid of anomalies and mutants. Be sure to check out the "100 Rads" bar in the vaults - it's a meeting point for stalkers from all over the Zone. The bar is run by the local trader, so if you're interested in selling or buying wares apart from the local gossip - that's the place to go to. North of the bar is the military base, with the Garbage to the South.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_darkdolina">
		<text>Always gloomy, always misty and always rainy. Stalkers venturing into the Dark Valley are likely to find valuable artifacts, instant death, or both. A place frequented by some of the most experienced old-timers, though you may also stumble upon some common bandits. There's supposed to be an underground lab around there somewhere, so it might be worth to look for a hidden entrance along the way. No one has returned from there alive though and no one can tell for sure just what nasty surprises await you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_escape">
		<text>Think of it as the Zone's antechamber - it's a good place for rookies to get their head around. You'll find a trader in the vaults at the back of the village, next to the army outpost. Don't miss the chance to talk to him. You'd be advised to steer clear of the outpost itself, however. You don't want the soldiers to catch a sight of you - most of them shoot first and don't bother asking questions later. Yet, as always, there are some who can be bribed as long as the top brass is looking the other way. Attacking the soldiers is not recommended, unless they pose a direct threat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_garbage">
		<text>A vast machinery graveyard. Right after the first accident whole heaps of radioactive waste were dumped there. Mostly ruins of old buildings infested with mutants. Much like the outskirts of the Zone, the place swarms with rookie stalkers, with an occasional bandit loitering around, always on the lookout for freebies. Some artifacts to be found here, but most of them are just not worth the effort. You'll be better off elsewhere. Going North, you will get to the Wild Territory, West lays the entrance to the Dark Valley, with the road to the Agroprom Research Institute to the East.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_military-loc">
		<text>A deserted army base next to a dilapidated hamlet and a small marsh. The village is an eerie place literally swarming with mutants - the bloodsuckers alone are legion. Stalkers do their best to keep away from it, even if it means going extra kilometers around it. The anarchists from the Freedom faction have settled down in the army base. The road connecting the base to the Zone is guarded by the "Brain Scorcher", which blocks the way to Pripyat and the Chernobyl NPP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_pripiat">
		<text>This used to be a town built for engineers working at the Chernobyl NPP. Quite a big place once, it is a ghost town now with mutants and zombies as the only residents. There seems to be no way to get in there: the "Brain Scorcher" is blocking the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_radar">
		<text>A dreadful place. Easy to vanish without a trace there, no matter how lucky you have been in life so far. Whoever gets close to the Brain Scorcher immediately goes insane, turns into a zombie and starts stalking the Zone restlessly. A human shell is all that’s left. No-one has ever returned with a sound mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_rostok">
		<text>The Wild Territory used to be the site of a rather large manufacturing plant, currently in ruins. Many stalkers met their death there: the place is swarming with all sorts of monsters. The beasts are literally streaming over there from the entire Zone. It is said that something of great importance is hidden at this site, so there are always plenty of daredevils willing to try their luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_stancia">
		<text>The site of the world-famous nuclear power plant. This is the heart of the Zone. If you believe the legends, this is also the site of the "Monolith" - a mysterious thing capable of granting any wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_yantar">
		<text>The legendary lake in the sector of the same name dried up a long ago, leaving a shallow swamp in its place. The place is morbid and sodden with death. Great dangers await any adventurous soul foolish enough to get near it. Anyone who dares to go too far goes insane. Zombie drones are rambling around the whole sector, waiting for new victims. If you walk around the lake and past the zombies, you’ll end up at the scientists' camp, where the eggheads brought there by choppers are doing some research. You can have a chat with them; they buy artifacts and could even send you on a mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2006">
		<text>The contaminated zone was aglow with the brightest of lights, almost unbearable to the human eye. You could virtually see the clouds in the sky turning into vapor. After a moment of dead silence there came rattling thunder, and then the earth shook. People fell to the ground, screwing up their eyes and covering their ears. Those who could still stand ran for their lives. It looked as though all the nuclear fuel buried under the Sarcophagus had suddenly exploded. The next day the army cordoned off the new Zone. The satellites helped to establish that the epicenter of the explosion was not actually in the vicinity of the NPP reactors, but about half a kilometer away. It is believed that the personnel of the station died at once, though many people still remained within the cordoned area. The rescue operation soon proved a pointless endeavor, as all the people and machinery sent deep into the area would die or malfunction immediately. A little while after the disaster, the Zone diameter hopped out by a few more kilometers. Most of the government troops guarding the border line and the research teams stationed there perished instantly. Panic stricken, people took to flight. The residents of nearby towns and villages were hastily evacuated. An enormous danger is looming over the world and we can only guess what its full impact may be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2008">
		<text>Two years have passed since the disaster in the contaminated zone around Chernobyl NPP. Skyrocketing deathtoll, countless people missing, dead cattle, decaying buildings, maimed forests... Until this day scientists have no explanation as to what exactly happened in Chernobyl. Meanwhile, some inconceivable anomalies were discovered in the area, and the Zone keeps expanding. Rare expeditions encounter mutated species of animals exhibiting unbelievable abilities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2010">
		<text>Following in the tracks of those foolhardy loners who call themselves the stalkers, research expeditions are once again embarking on an in-depth study of the Zone. However, the perimeter guarded by the army has other, dangerous inhabitants now - from common poachers to the worst bandit scum. Most of the stalkers roam the Zone in search of anomalies and the so-called artifacts for which they gain quite a profit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-raid">
		<text>The army, including special forces headed by paramilitary stalker detachments, launched a massive raid deep into the Zone. Their objective was to break through to the Chernobyl NPP and wipe out the cause of anomalous fields or at least obtain first-hand information on the current state of affairs. This endeavor, involving over a thousand people and heavy machinery, was a complete failure. Isolated groups of survivors were forced to settle within the Zone with slender hopes of rescue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Escape">
		<text>Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fuzz">
		<text>"Burnt Fuzz"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Garbage">
		<text>Garbage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Gravi">
		<text>"Vortex"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Lift">
		<text>"Elevator"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Locations">
		<text>Locations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Meat">
		<text>"Whirligig"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Military-loc">
		<text>Army base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pripiat">
		<text>Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radar">
		<text>Brain Scorcher</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radioactive">
		<text>Source of radioactivity</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Rostok">
		<text>Wild Territory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stancia">
		<text>Chernobyl NPP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2006">
		<text>2006, April 12, 14:33</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2008">
		<text>Year 2008.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-2010">
		<text>Year 2010.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story-raid">
		<text>Army raid into the Zone, 2010.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Time_machine">
		<text>"Time Machine"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Yantar">
		<text>Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zharka">
		<text>"Burner"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone">
		<text>The Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone-story">
		<text>History of the Zone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psy">
		<text>"Psi-zone"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_phenomena_psy_general">
		<text>Area with high psi-emission activity. Causes powerful hallucinations and severe headache. Remaining in such area for a prolonged time must be avoided as far as it can lead to loss of mind. One can even become zombified.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Surge">
		<text>Surge</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_phenomena_surge_general">
		<text>In equal periods of time the entire Zone is rocked by surges of gravity nature combined with intense psychotropic activity. Staying in the Zone during this time is fatally dangerous. The earth starts shaking, the entire area is rolled over by invisible waves followed by a number of flashes. The entire world seems black-and-white, heavens emit dazzling light nobody's eyes can withstand... Phantom formations and haze above the gravitational anomalies can be seen during the surge. Everybody without special equipment gets killed within a blink of an eye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Surge-story">
		<text>Surge story</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_anomalies_activation-basic">
		<text>Activated artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_anomalies_activation-practice">
		<text>Activation of artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_basic">
		<text>In addition to other known properties, some artifacts have the ability to be activated. The activation process releases the concentrated energy of the artifact, which developes an anomalous area around the activated artifact, similar to that of the initial ("birthgiving") anomaly. The artifact itself collapses. It should be noted that though outwardly alike, these anomalies differ by nature: the "classic" anomalies seem to draw energy for their existance from the Zone itself, the "artificial" ones consume the energy of the artifact and thus their life isn't long. Initial cause of this phenomenon obviously lies in some of the physical processes of the activation being reversible. That allows some energies to be drawn from the artifact instead of being consumed by it, thus allowing a smaller analogue of the "mother"-anomaly to be formed. It should also be remembered that such artificial anomalies are not capable to "birth" artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_practice">
		<text>The activation of an afrtifact can only be performed under certain circumstances. It is required to manipulate the artifact in a specific manner so as to reach necessary activation conditions. Some artifacts are activated by warmth of the body and quite simple movements, while the others can not be activated even with the help of high-technology equipment of scientific labs. To activate an artifact place it into corresponding slot in your inventory and hold the "Fire" button.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_why">
		<text>Artifact activation process requires some specific condition. artifact must be manipulated with specific maner in favorable conditions for this process. Some artifacts can be activated with body heat and simple moving above ground, some can't be activated even in science lab. For artifact activation move it to first slot and hlod (Fire) button.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zone_hit_from_arts">
		<text>Artifact are harmful</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_hit_from_arts">
		<text>According to Professor A.A.Likhodeev's research, those artifacts, which contact or effect the human organism directly, must be treated with utmost care. It was found out that their positive influence, being excessively multiplied, leads to possible damage to health, or may even develop environmental conditions, under which a resonant anomalous energy release may occur. E.g. those artifacts increasing bulletproof characteristics do it by stiffening the skin and subcutaneous fat (making soft tissues more tenacious). After biological hazard treshold is reached, such effect becomes harmful due to loss of elasticity by lymphocapillar vessels, resulting in ruptures and, consequently, atrophy and dying off of effected tissues. And the artifacts, protecting their bearer from high temperatures, under certain conditions instantly start emitting heat themselves, causing severe burns. Besides there is a risk that the destabilized organism may change its properties and further summarized influence effects will surely lead to an extremely dangerous output. \n --- \nNote: Professor A.A.Likhodeev died in an accident while experimenting on anomalous artifacts.</text>	
	</string>

	<string id="anomaly_ochyag">
		<text>Anomaly hearth</text>
	</string>

	<string id="anomaly_ochyag_info">
		<text>Aggregation of anomalys of various kind in a small area. This phenomenon is very dangerous and very attractive because it is considered that there can born unique artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_mobkiller_name">
		<text>"Poacher's paw"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_mobkiller_desc">
		<text>A unique atefact that has a protective property against cuts and bumps.%c[100,50,250,50]When worn on a belt, mutant damage is applied to all mutants within a 20m radius.%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
